<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://joe8755.github.io/the-news-rss-reader/index.html</id>
    <title>the news rss reader</title>
    <updated>2024-06-27T12:34:29.868Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joe8755.github.io/the-news-rss-reader/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://joe8755.github.io/the-news-rss-reader/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD P-State Core Performance Boost To Be Merged For Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Core-Perf-Boost-Linux-6.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Core-Perf-Boost-Linux-6.11"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.11 is shaping up to be an exciting summertime kernel cycle for AMD Ryzen owners. The newest feature now being queued ahead of next month's merge window is Core Performance Boost support within the AMD P-State CPU frequency scaling driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Battlemage PCI IDs Being Added To Linux 6.11 For Xe Kernel Graphics Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/DRM-Xe-Next-BMG-PCI-IDs</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/DRM-Xe-Next-BMG-PCI-IDs"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T10:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sent out on Wednesday were the latest set of DRM-Xe-Next changes of the last round of feature updates for this Xe kernel graphics driver targeting the upcoming Linux 6.11 cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD's AOMP 19.0-2 Compiler Brings Zero-Copy For CPU-GPU Unified Shared Memory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-AOMP-19.0-2-Compiler</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-AOMP-19.0-2-Compiler"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T09:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD compiler engineers have released AOMP 19.0-2 as the newest version of their downstream LLVM/Clang compiler that carries all of their latest work around OpenMP/AOCC GPU device offloading to Radeon and Instinct hardware. With this updated AOMP compiler is now run-time support for zero-copy with CPU-GPU unified shared memory and various other new features for this GPU/accelerator-focused compiler...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multi-Grain Timestamps Revived For Linux File-Systems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Multi-Grain-Timestamps-Revived</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Multi-Grain-Timestamps-Revived"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T09:45:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year a new kernel feature merged in Linux 6.6 was multi-grain(ed) timestamps for file-systems as a means of better timestamp handling originally for NFS compared to the existing coarse-grained timestamps with the once per jiffy timestamps being used for invalidating NFS caches. But multi-grain timestamps was reverted just weeks after landing in the mainline kernel due to corner cases like a newer file with a coarse-grained timestamp appearing earlier than another file with a fine-grained timestamp. Due to subtle bugs like that, multi-grain timestamps were dropped before Linux 6.6 was even released while now there is a revised attempt...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Granite Rapids Brings New "SBAF" Core Testing Capability]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Granite-Rapids-SBAF-IFS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Granite-Rapids-SBAF-IFS"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T09:19:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming Intel Xeon 6 "Granite Rapids" processors will support a new Structural Based Functional Test at Field (SBAF) testing capability to help verify the health of the CPU cores...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Software Foundation Names Three New Board Members]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/FSF-3-New-Board-Members</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/FSF-3-New-Board-Members"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T00:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following a more than one year long process, the Free Software Foundation today named three additional board members...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-26]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-26.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-26.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 26, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Liquid Layers
(comments)


I found a 1-click exploit in South Korea's biggest mobile chat app
(comments)


Show HN: Triplit – Open-source syncing database that runs on server and client
(comments)


Show HN: From dotenv to dotenvx – better config management
(comments)


Waymo One is now open to everyone in San Francisco
(comments)


Show HN: Glasskube – Open Source Kubernetes Package Manager, alternative to Helm
(comments)


Fixing QuickLook (2023)
(comments)


Ball: A ball that lives in your dock
(comments)


HyperCard Simulator
(comments)


One Million Checkboxes
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Compute Runtime 24.22.29735.20 Brings Latest OpenCL & Level Zero Support On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-CR-24.22.29735.20</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-CR-24.22.29735.20"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T23:05:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel today issued the Compute Runtime 24.22.29735.20 release as their open-source driver providing OpenCL and oneAPI Level Zero capabilities on Windows and Linux systems. This update was joined by an updated Intel Graphics Compiler, IGC 1.0.16900.23...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arch Linux Installer "Archinstall" 2.8.1 Adds Experimental LVM Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Archinstall-2.8.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Archinstall-2.8.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T15:47:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Archinstall 2.8.1 is now available for the newest version of this easy-to-use, command-line driven installer for the Arch Linux operating system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[COSMIC Alpha Desktop Release Still Planned For Late July]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/COSMIC-Alpha-Next-Month</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/COSMIC-Alpha-Next-Month"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T15:16:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[System76 developers are still on track for releasing the alpha version of their Rust-written COSMIC desktop in late July...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical Offers Up 12 Year "Everything LTS" For Docker Images]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Canonical-12Year-Everything-LTS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Canonical-12Year-Everything-LTS"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T14:14:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu maker Canonical announced "Everything LTS" as a new initiative where for Ubuntu Pro customers they will offer up a twelve year LTS period for any open-source Docker image...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rust-Written OpenCL Driver Now Works On Raspberry Pi GPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Rusticl-V3D-OpenCL-Raspberry-Pi</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Rusticl-V3D-OpenCL-Raspberry-Pi"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T12:37:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa's Rusticl driver as a Rust-based OpenCL driver for GPUs backed by Gallium3D support now works with the Broadcom V3D driver. This V3D support is notable as it's most commonly associated with the Raspberry Pi single board computers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMDVLK 2024.Q2.3 Release Brings Few Changes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDVLK-2024.Q2.3</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDVLK-2024.Q2.3"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T12:12:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD has published AMDVLK 2024.Q2.3 as the newest version of their open-source Radeon Vulkan driver for Linux systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Vulkan Driver Enables Cooperative Matrix Support For Xe2 GPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Xe2-Coop-Matrix-Enable</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Xe2-Coop-Matrix-Enable"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T10:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's open-source Linux graphics driver developers continue to be quite busy in preparing for the Xe2 next-generation graphics to be found with forthcoming Lunar Lake processors and the Battlemage discrete graphics cards...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 15 Adds NVIDIA Grace CPU Support With "-mcpu=grace" Option]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-15-NVIDIA-Grace-CPU</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-15-NVIDIA-Grace-CPU"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T10:12:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA has upstreamed a patch to the GCC 15 compiler for adding the "-mcpu=grace" option to make it easier to target NVIDIA Grace AArch64 CPU cores from this open-source compiler...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[openSUSE Leap Micro 6.0 Now Available For Container & VM Needs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/openSUSE-Leap-Micro-6.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/openSUSE-Leap-Micro-6.0"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T10:01:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSUSE has released Leap Micro 6.0 as stable for this community rebranded build of SUSE Linux Enterprise Micro 6.0. Leap Micro continues to be focused on delivering a very reliable and robust experience for containers and virtual machines...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora 41 Will Make OpenSSL Distrust SHA1 Signatures By Default]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-41-OpenSSL-Distrust-SHA1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-41-OpenSSL-Distrust-SHA1"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T09:51:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A change proposal has been approved for Fedora 41 to make OpenSSL distrust SHA1 signatures by default...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-25]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-25.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-25.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 25, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


More Memory Safety for Let's Encrypt: Deploying ntpd-rs
(comments)


The case for not sanitising fairy tales
(comments)


Round Rects Are Everywhere
(comments)


Julian Assange has reached a plea deal with the U.S., allowing him to go free
(comments)


SIMD-accelerated computer vision on a $2 microcontroller
(comments)


Local First, Forever
(comments)


Microsoft breached antitrust rules by bundling Teams and Office, EU says
(comments)


Microsoft removes documentation for switching to a local account in Windows 11
(comments)


Show HN: I built a JavaScript-powered flipdisc display
(comments)


Polyfill supply chain attack hits 100K+ sites
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NUMA Emulation Yields "Significant Performance Uplift" To Raspberry Pi 5]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/ARM64-NUMA-Emulation-RPi5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/ARM64-NUMA-Emulation-RPi5"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T16:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Engineers at consulting firm Igalia are exploring NUMA emulation for ARM64 (AArch64) due to the potential of "significant" performance uplift as observed on the popular Raspberry Pi 5 single board computer...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 6.1 Performing Much Better On Older Intel Integrated Graphics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Intel-iGPU</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Intel-iGPU"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T15:01:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the recently released KDE Plasma 6.1 desktop environment, those still relying on old Intel integrated graphics should have a much more pleasant experience thanks to improvements made to the KWin compositor. For very old Intel integrated graphics, it can effectively be a night and day difference upgrading to the new Plasma 6.1 desktop...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Linux Software Optimizations Still Pay Off For Xeon 6700E "Sierra Forest" E-Core CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6e-clear-linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6e-clear-linux"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T13:48:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When testing Intel's aggressive software Linux optimizations shipped by way of their in-house Clear Linux distribution, I am most often testing it on their high core count Xeon processors with AVX-512... Over the years in dozens of Phoronix articles there have been countless metrics showing off the out-of-the-box performance benefits from leveraging software built for higher x86_64 micro-architecture feature levels, employing compiler-based function multi-versioning, and the other extensive performance tuning carried out by Intel software engineers. But now with the Intel Xeon 6700E "Sierra Forest" series now being available for these all-E-core server processors, I was curious about quantifying the Clear Linux benefits over the likes of Ubuntu Linux. Here are those benchmarks for those curious about the difference.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Connect Adds Remote Shell Access, Support For Older Raspberry Pi SBCs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-Connect-Shell</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-Connect-Shell"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T13:31:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in May the Raspberry Pi crew announced Raspberry Pi Access as an easy means of remote GUI access to Raspberry Pi single board computers all from a web browser. Today they've announced the latest improvements to Raspberry Pi Connect...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More AMD P-State Driver Improvements Queued For Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-P-State-Linux-6.11-Round-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-P-State-Linux-6.11-Round-2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T10:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this month AMD Fast CPPC support was queued into the Linux power management subsystem's "-next" codebase ahead of the Linux 6.11 cycle. Additional AMD P-State driver enhancements are now deemed ready and submitted for staging ahead of next month's Linux 6.11 cycle kicking off...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Vulkan Driver Sees Fixes To Improve OpenGL-On-Vulkan Zink Compatibility]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-ANV-Sparse-Zink-Fixes</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-ANV-Sparse-Zink-Fixes"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T10:33:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The open-source Intel ANV Vulkan driver has recently been seeing improvements around better handling the Zink OpenGL-on-Vulkan driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora 41 Installer Proceeding To Transition From X11 To Wayland App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-41-Anaconda-Wayland</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-41-Anaconda-Wayland"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T10:08:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Fedora's new web-based installer UI being delayed to 2025 with Fedora 42, part of Red Hat's justification for that setback was needing to invest resources first in Fedora 41 by transitioning the OS installer to being a native Wayland application. The Fedora Engineering and Steering Committee (FESCo) has now signed off on that work as expected to make the Anaconda OS installer a native Wayland application...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenShot 3.2 Released With Better Performance For This Open-Source Video Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/OpenShot-3.2-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/OpenShot-3.2-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T09:38:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenShot 3.2 has been released as the latest feature update to this open-source, non-linear video editor that is popular on Linux systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-24]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-24.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-24.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 24, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Timeliness without datagrams using QUIC
(comments)


Detecting hallucinations in large language models using semantic entropy
(comments)


LINQPad – The .NET Programmer's Playground
(comments)


Apple's secret silicon fab next to thousands of homes
(comments)


Cosmopolitan v3.5
(comments)


US prosecutors recommend Justice Department criminally charge Boeing
(comments)


Apple found in breach of EU competition rules
(comments)


Microfeatures I love in blogs and personal websites
(comments)


Car dealerships revert to pens and paper after cyberattacks on software provider
(comments)


Windows 11 is now enabling OneDrive folder backup without asking permission
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RadeonSI Enables Compute PBO Blits: "Massively Improves Perf In A Number Of Cases"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/RadeonSI-Compute-PBO-Blits</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/RadeonSI-Compute-PBO-Blits"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T17:59:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Related to the work by Mike Blumenkrantz for significantly improving the Mesa glReadPixels performance by more than 100%, the open-source driver developer at Valve has now enabled compute PBO blits within mainline Mesa for the AMD Radeon "RadeonSI" Gallium3D driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Llamafile 0.8.7 Brings Fixes, Better ARM Performance & Preps For New Server]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Llamafile-0.8.7-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Llamafile-0.8.7-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T15:11:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Llamafile has been one of the better new initiatives out of Mozilla in recent years. Llamafile makes it easy to conveniently distribute and run large language models as a single file while supporting both CPU and GPU execution and all-around making AI LLMs much more approachable for end-users. Out today is Llamafile 0.8.7 with more performance optimizations and new features...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel P-State Patches Further Tune Linux For Better Scheduling On Hybrid CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-P-State-Asymmetric-Cap</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-P-State-Asymmetric-Cap"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new set of patches are currently being tested for improving task scheduling and in turn performance for modern Intel Core hybrid processors. With the patch also mentioning systems that are hybrid but without SMT, this looks like it may be some early tuning as well for upcoming Intel Lunar Lake processors that lack Hyper Threading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 24.10 Now Defaults To NVIDIA On Wayland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.10-GDM-Wayland-NVIDIA</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.10-GDM-Wayland-NVIDIA"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T10:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Ubuntu 24.10 due for release in October one of the expressed planned changes has been NVIDIA defaulting to using Wayland rather than X11 for the default desktop session. As of this past week the change is now in place for Ubuntu 24.10 daily users that will find Wayland-by-default when using the official NVIDIA Linux graphics driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CentOS Linux 7 Is End-Of-Life Next Week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/CentOS-7-EOL-Next-Week</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/CentOS-7-EOL-Next-Week"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T10:37:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just a friendly reminder that if you've been procrastinating in migrating past the once-great CentOS Linux 7, there is less than one week to go now until it's officially end-of-life...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qualcomm Aiming For Snapdragon X Elite GPU Support In Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Qualcomm-Adreno-X1-85-GPU-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Qualcomm-Adreno-X1-85-GPU-Linux"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T10:22:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Qualcomm engineers on Sunday posted patches for enabling the Adreno X1-85 GPU within the MSM DRM driver. The Adreno X1-85 GPU is what's found within the Snapdragon X Elite SoC powering various new Windows ARM laptops although the Linux support continues maturing too for these platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ASUS ROG Raikiri Pro Controller Support Being Added To Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/ASUS-ROG-Raikiri-Pro-Linux-6.10</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/ASUS-ROG-Raikiri-Pro-Linux-6.10"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T09:55:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back during the Linux 6.9 kernel cycle support was added for the ASUS ROG Raikiri as a newer gaming controller. Now on its way for landing in Linux 6.10 is support for the ASUS ROG Raikiri Pro...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-23]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-23.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-23.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 23, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


I kind of like rebasing
(comments)


The biggest CRT ever made: Sony's PVM-4300
(comments)


Show HN: I made tool that let's you see everything about any website
(comments)


HH70, the first high-temperature superconducting Tokamak achieves first plasma
(comments)


Ruby: A great language for shell scripts
(comments)


I've stopped using box plots (2021)
(comments)


Llama.ttf: A font which is also an LLM
(comments)


I am using AI to drop hats outside my window onto New Yorkers
(comments)


The tiny chip that powers Montreal subway tickets
(comments)


Start all of your commands with a comma (2009)
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10-rc5 Released With This Kernel Cycle Looking Good So Far]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc5"/>
        <updated>2024-06-23T21:47:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds has just tagged Linux 6.10-rc5 as the newest weekly test release leading up to the Linux 6.10 stable release by mid-July...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Exploring MM-Local Memory Allocations To Help With Current/Future Speculation Attacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-MM-Local-Kernel-Allocs</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-MM-Local-Kernel-Allocs"/>
        <updated>2024-06-23T13:42:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in 2019 after various speculation-based CPU vulnerabilities began coming to light, Amazon engineers proposed process-local memory allocations for hiding KVM secrets. They were striving for an alternative mitigation for vulnerabilities like L1TF by essentially providing some memory regions for kernel allocations out of view/access from other kernel code. Amazon engineers this week laid out a new proposal after five years of ongoing Linux kernel improvements for MM-local memory allocations for dealing with current and future speculation-based cross-process attacks...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Longtime Linux Wireless Developer Passes Away]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Larry-Finger-Linux-Wireless</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Larry-Finger-Linux-Wireless"/>
        <updated>2024-06-23T10:41:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux kernel community has sadly lost one of its longtime, prolific contributors to the wireless (WiFi) drivers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rust Coreutils 0.0.27 Continues The Climb Of Better GNU Coreutils Interoperability]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Rust-Coreutils-uutils-0.0.27</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Rust-Coreutils-uutils-0.0.27"/>
        <updated>2024-06-23T10:31:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The uutils project has released Rust Coreutils 0.0.27 as the newest feature update to this Rust-written, drop-in replacement to the GNU Coreutils as the common set of utilities found on Linux systems and other platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Readies More Kernel Graphics Driver Code For Linux 6.11, Enables DCC For RDNA4]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-GFX12-DCC-Linux-6.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-GFX12-DCC-Linux-6.11"/>
        <updated>2024-06-23T10:19:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Friday more AMDGPU/AMDKFD kernel driver changes were submitted for the upcoming Linux 6.11 cycle by way of DRM-Next. We're nearing the end of feature work to DRM-Next before the Linux 6.11 merge window begins in mid-July while this latest AMD pull request continues preparing for upcoming RDNA4 graphics hardware among other changes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat Proposes Queue PerCPU Work "QPW" For Better Handling Per-CPU Work On RT Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Queue-Per-CPU-Work-QPW</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Queue-Per-CPU-Work-QPW"/>
        <updated>2024-06-23T10:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat engineer Leonardo Bras has laid out a proposal for QPWs, or "Queue PerCPU Work", as a better means of handling per-CPU operations within the Linux kernel especially for real-time (RT) workloads...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flathub Has Now Served More Than Two Billion Downloads For Flatpaks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Flathub-Two-Billion-Downloads</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Flathub-Two-Billion-Downloads"/>
        <updated>2024-06-23T01:45:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flathub as the centralized repository for serving Flatpak sandboxed Linux applications crossed the threshold this weekend of serving more than two billion downloads...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-22]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-22.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-22.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 22, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Show HN: Eidos – Offline alternative to Notion
(comments)


Spending 3 months investigating a 7-year old bug and fixing it in 1 line of code
(comments)


Innovation heroes are a sign of a dysfunctional organization
(comments)


Testing Generative AI for Circuit Board Design
(comments)


Self-driving Waymos secure final clearance for expansion beyond S.F
(comments)


Internet Archive forced to remove 500k books after publishers' court win
(comments)


My Windows Computer Just Doesn't Feel Like Mine Anymore
(comments)


Language is primarily a tool for communication rather than thought [pdf]
(comments)


After my dad died, I ran and sold his company (2018)
(comments)


Andrew S. Tanenbaum Receives ACM Software System Award
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bcachefs Making Tiny Steps Toward Full Self-Healing Capabilities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Bcachefs-Tiny-Step-Self-Healing</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Bcachefs-Tiny-Step-Self-Healing"/>
        <updated>2024-06-22T20:09:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another round of Bcachefs file-system fixes were merged today for the in-development Linux 6.10 kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD AI Compiler Engineer Lands A Generic MLIR To SPIR-V Pass In LLVM 19]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/LLVM-19-MLIR-To-SPIR-V</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/LLVM-19-MLIR-To-SPIR-V"/>
        <updated>2024-06-22T12:40:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged on Friday to LLVM 19 Git is a generic MLIR to SPIR-V pass for lowering the Multi-Level Intermediate Representation down into SPIR-V as the intermediate representation consumed by OpenGL / OpenCL / Vulkan drivers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME Seeing Much Work On Their "Setup" OEM Style Installer, Key Rack & oo7]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Setup-KeyRack-oo7</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Setup-KeyRack-oo7"/>
        <updated>2024-06-22T10:40:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME developers continue to be very busy with a variety of initiatives thanks to the Sovereign Tech Fund (STF) financing as well as other general development efforts as they work their way toward GNOME 47 in September...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE's Cube Effect Now Launches More Reliably & Other Post-6.1 Plasma Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Fixes-Week</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Fixes-Week"/>
        <updated>2024-06-22T10:05:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following this week's great KDE Plasma 6.1 desktop release, developers have been fixing some minor bugs and other issues that were raised by early users of this updated open-source Qt6-powered desktop...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-21]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-21.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-21.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 21, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


NASA releases Hubble image taken in new pointing mode
(comments)


Free software hijacked Philip Hazel's life
(comments)


Let's write a video game from scratch like it's 1987
(comments)


We no longer use LangChain for building our AI agents
(comments)


Notes on Tajikistan
(comments)


Donald Sutherland has died
(comments)


Fuzz Map
(comments)


MeshAnything – Converts 3D representations into efficient 3D meshes
(comments)


Ladybird browser spreads its wings
(comments)


Allan McDonald refused to approve Challenger launch, exposed cover-up (2021)
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blumenkrantz "Massively Improves" Mesa's glReadPixels Performance With 7 Lines Of Code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Blumenkrantz-glReadPixels-Perf</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Blumenkrantz-glReadPixels-Perf"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T19:44:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mike Blumenkrantz of Valve's open-source/Linux graphics driver team has submitted a merge request to "massively" improve the OpenGL glReadPixels performance within the common Mesa state tracker...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Darktable 4.8 Pulls AI Feature After Discovering It Doesn't Work Well]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Darktable-4.8-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Darktable-4.8-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T16:56:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While more software piles on AI features these days, today's release of the Darktable 4.8 RAW photography software has removed one of its AI features after realizing it only delivers mediocre quality...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VKD3D-Proton 2.13 Brings OpenVR/OpenXR Interop & Performance Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/VKD3D-Proton-2.13</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/VKD3D-Proton-2.13"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T15:08:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[VKD3D-Proton 2.13 is now available as the newest version of this Direct3D 12 over Vulkan API translation later that is used by Valve's Steam Play (Proton) for accelerating D3D12 Windows games on Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Can Have A "Black Screen Of Death" For Kernel Panics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Black-BSoD</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Black-BSoD"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:55:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With some Linux users not liking the recently showcased new Linux "Blue Screen of Death" for kernel panics, Red Hat engineer Javier Martinez Canillas who has been one of those involved in the new DRM Panic infrastructure showed that it can also be a "black screen of death" if so desired...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa Developers Aren't Convinced Over Dropping Old OpenGL Drivers Right Now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-Devs-On-Keeping-Drivers</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-Devs-On-Keeping-Drivers"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this week was a proposal for creating a new Mesa legacy driver branch for clearing out older OpenGL drivers like the ATI R300, AMD R600, Lima, Nouveau NV30, and other older GPU drivers. However, other upstream Mesa developers aren't convinced by the proposal...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud Hypervisor 40 Released With Better Boot Time Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Cloud-Hypervisor-40-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Cloud-Hypervisor-40-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud Hypervisor 40.0 is out today for this open-source Rust-written VMM that started off as an Intel software project and evolved into a multi-vendor initiative with backing from the likes of Microsoft, Arm, AMD, and others for a cloud-focused, security-critical virtualization hypervisor...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Lunar Lake Workload Hints & Power Floor Patches Posted For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-LunarLake-WLT-Power-Floor</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-LunarLake-WLT-Power-Floor"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T11:02:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel software engineers have been upstreaming the Lunar Lake support for Linux a number of months already and the basics appear in good shape, aside from the Xe2 graphics enablement being an ongoing matter. Much of the rest of the core functionality has appeared to be in good shape ahead of Lunar Lake laptops launching in Q3, but it seems there have been a few missing power management related bits...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building Mesa On POWER Now Presents A Default Set Of OpenGL & Vulkan Drivers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.2-Default-POWER-PPC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.2-Default-POWER-PPC"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T10:34:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Newly merged patches for Mesa 24.2 slightly enhance the default out-of-the-box build experience for the open-source OpenGL and Vulkan drivers on POWER/PowerPC platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Xe Driver Seeing PMT Support For Alchemist & Battlemage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Xe-PMT-DG2-BMG-Patches</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Xe-PMT-DG2-BMG-Patches"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T09:55:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Intel Xe driver is working on supporting PMT functionality with a new set of patches that may be mainlined for Linux v6.11~6.12...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-20]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-20.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-20.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 20, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Show HN: Radius – A Meetup.com alternative
(comments)


Agricultural drones are transforming rice farming in the Mekong River delta
(comments)


Please don't mention AI again
(comments)


EU Council has withdrawn the vote on Chat Control
(comments)


Tetris Font
(comments)


Claude 3.5 Sonnet
(comments)


Show HN: I made a puzzle game that gently introduces my favorite math mysteries
(comments)


Small claims court became Meta's customer service hotline
(comments)


More Disabled Americans Are Employed, Thanks to Remote Work
(comments)


Gilead shot prevents all HIV cases in trial
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qualcomm Cloud AI 100 "AIC100" Firmware Upstreamed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Qualcomm-AIC100-Firmware</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Qualcomm-AIC100-Firmware"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T19:57:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While not talked about as much as the likes of the Intel Gaudi accelerators with their upstream Habana Labs kernel driver or the AMD Instinct MI300 series with their open-source upstream support too, back in 2022 Qualcomm did post an open-source kernel driver for their Cloud AI accelerator. That was followed by an open-source compiler and user-space stack and in turn the QAIC driver was upstreamed into the accelerator (accel) subsystem last year with Linux 6.4...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Linux NPU Driver v1.5 Released - Now Validated On Arrow Lake & Lunar Lake]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Linux-NPU-Driver-1.5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Linux-NPU-Driver-1.5"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T17:15:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel on Wednesday released version 1.5 of their Linux NPU driver, their user-space driver component for Linux systems in enabling the neural processing unit found with Core Ultra "Meteor Lake" processors and newer. This goes along with their upstream IVPU kernel accelerator driver for allowing a full open-source solution for AI workloads with the likes of OpenVINO...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi 5 Kernel Graphics Driver Support Will Hopefully Be Upstreamed Soon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-5-Kernel-DRM-Soon</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-5-Kernel-DRM-Soon"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T16:36:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the Raspberry Pi 5 debuted last September, the mainline Linux kernel support for this popular single board  computer continues to lag behind the state of Raspberry Pi's downstream kernel. SUSE has been working to upstream various Raspberry Pi 5 driver support while now Raspberry Pi engineers have also begun the trek toward upstreaming their kernel graphics driver support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME Shell Accent Color Support Merged For GNOME 47]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Shell-Accent-Color-Merged</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Shell-Accent-Color-Merged"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T14:38:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to Mutter seeing Wayland DRM lease protocol support merged, another long-in-development patch series hit GNOME Shell this morning: accent color support!..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME Merges Wayland DRM Lease Protocol For Better VR Handling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Wayland-DRM-Lease</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Wayland-DRM-Lease"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T14:11:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged today into GNOME's Mutter compositor is support for the Wayland DRM lease protocol to allow for nice virtual reality (VR) headset support for GNOME on Wayland...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Introduces New Gaudi "2D" Product Support To Their Linux Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Gaudi2D-Linux-Driver</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Gaudi2D-Linux-Driver"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was just a few months back that Intel introduced a Gaudi "2C" variant of Gaudi2 to their open-source Linux driver. This variant might be for some export model or otherwise a hyperscaler/customer-specific revision or something along those lines. Now appearing within new Habana Labs driver patches for the upcoming Linux 6.11 kernel are patches for a new Gaudi 2D variant...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 12.4 Compiler Released With 84+ Bugs Fixed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-12.4-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-12.4-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:18:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those continuing to rely on the GCC 12 series open-source compiler that was introduced as stable in 2022, GCC 12.4 is out today as the newest bug fix release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monochrome TV Mode Coming To Linux 6.11, Added By Raspberry Pi Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-DRM-Monochrome-TV</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-DRM-Monochrome-TV"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T09:58:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another weeks worth of random DRM-Misc-Next changes have been queued ahead of next month's Linux 6.11 merge window...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theseus Ship 6.1 Released For This KWinFT Evolution Now Based On KDE Plasma 6.1]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Theseus-Ship-6.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Theseus-Ship-6.1"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T09:45:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Theseus Ship is the X11/Wayland compositor previously known as KWinFT developed by Roman Gilg as a fork of KDE Plasma's KWin. Pulling in patches from KWin in this week's KDE Plasma 6.1 release, Theseus Ship 6.1 is now available...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zhaoxin "Shijidadao" x86_64 CPU Support Merged Into The GCC 15 Compiler]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Zhaxoin-Shijidadao-GCC-15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Zhaxoin-Shijidadao-GCC-15"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T00:25:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zhaoxin Shijidadao CPU support was upstreamed today into the GCC 15 compiler codebase. Zhaoxin as a reminder is the joint venture between VIA and the Shanghai Municipal Government for creating x86/x86_64-compatible processors for the Chinese market...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-19]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-19.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-19.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 19, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Show HN: Billard – Generate music from ball collisions in 2D space
(comments)


Nature retracts paper that claimed adult stem cell could become any type of cell
(comments)


KidPix
(comments)


Ask HN: Why do message queue-based architectures seem less popular now?
(comments)


Fern Hollow Bridge should have been closed years before it collapsed
(comments)


EU Council to Vote on Chat Scanning Proposal on Thursday
(comments)


Neofetch developer archives all his repositories: \"Have taken up farming\"
(comments)


Fast Crimes at Lambda School
(comments)


1/25-scale Cray C90 wristwatch
(comments)


Safe Superintelligence Inc.
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radeon Software For Linux 24.10.3 With ROCm 6.1.3]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Radeon-Software-ROCm-24.10.3</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Radeon-Software-ROCm-24.10.3"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T20:23:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As written about this morning, AMD announced ROCm 6.1.3 with multi-GPU support, beta support for Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL2), Radeon PRO W7900 Dual Slot compatibility, and TensorFlow framework qualification support. The upstream ROCm code on GitHub as of writing continues pointing only to the prior ROCm 6.1.2 software but there is now a Radeon Software for Linux packaged driver offering up ROCm 6.1.3...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.11 To Enable Intel Battlemage GPU Display Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Battlemage-Linux-6.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Battlemage-Linux-6.11"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T18:09:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building off the Xe2 foundation in place for the Lunar Lake integrated graphics, more recently Intel's open-source Linux graphics driver engineers have begun pushing out code focused on enabling the Xe2-based Battlemage discrete GPUs as the successor to the DG2/Alchemist hardware. That enablement work remains ongoing and with the upcoming Linux 6.11 kernel cycle the important fundamental milestone is being crossed of actually being able to drive a connected display/monitor by a Battlemage GPU...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proposal For Creating A New Mesa Legacy Driver Branch: R300, R600, Lima, NV30 & More]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-Amber2-Legacy-Branch-Call</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-Amber2-Legacy-Branch-Call"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T16:40:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mike Blumenkrantz of Valve's open-source Linux GPU driver team and known for his work on the Zink OpenGL-on-Vulkan driver has issued a proposal for creating a new legacy branch for older/less-maintained Gallium3D drivers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Patches Posted For Intel Lunar Lake DLVR Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Lunar-Lake-DLVR-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Lunar-Lake-DLVR-Linux"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T16:13:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While it looked like all of the Intel Lunar Lake support was wrapped up with the first of these next-gen Core Ultra laptops set to debut next quarter and the Panther Lake bring-up for Linux has begun, it looks like there may be some stragglers still around Lunar Lake. Sent out today was the patch series enabling DLVR (Digital Linear Voltage Regulator) support for these upcoming mobile SoCs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zlib-ng 2.2 Speeds Up Compression By ~12% On x86_64 CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/zlib-2.2-RC1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/zlib-2.2-RC1"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T14:18:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first release candidate of Zlib-ng 2.2 for this drop-in replacement to the Zlib data compression library is now available for testing. Zlib-ng continues to ship new performance optimizations and other tuning for providing faster Zlib performance on modern processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Announces ROCm 6.1.3 With Better Multi-GPU Support, Beta-Level WSL2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-ROCm-6.1.3-Announced</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-ROCm-6.1.3-Announced"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T13:48:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD today announced the ROCm 6.1.3 open-source GPU compute stack. While a point release, this new ROCm revision comes with several notable refinements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated DRM Rust Abstractions For Linux As Part Of Bringing Up The Nova Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/DRM-Rust-Abstractions-v2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/DRM-Rust-Abstractions-v2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T12:48:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sent out last month were the very preliminary Rust-written Nova GPU kernel driver patches for this in-development Direct Rendering Manager driver for open-source NVIDIA GPU support for RTX 20 / Turing GPUs and newer by leveraging the NVIDIA GPU System Processor (GSP). Sent out this week is the second iteration of the stubbed Nova kernel driver and the associated Rust language DRM subsystem abstractions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Systemd 256.1 Fixes "systemd-tmpfiles" Unexpectedly Deleting Your /home Directory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/systemd-tmpfiles-purge-drama</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/systemd-tmpfiles-purge-drama"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T10:03:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those running the command "systemd-tmpfiles --purge" and think that this command just deletes your temporary files, think again and watch out. In reality it will delete all files and directories created by a tmpfiles.d entry... Including the /home that is created by systemd-tmpfiles' home.conf. With users being bitten in recent days by this behavior when they were just expecting tmp files to be removed, systemd 256.1 is now available and does have a change to avoid inadvertently deleting your all-important home directory...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds Demotes "FORCE_NR_CPUS" Embedded Linux Option To Avoid Confusion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Demote-FORCE_NR_CPUS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Demote-FORCE_NR_CPUS"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T00:26:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux kernel "FORCE_NR_CPUS" Kconfig option has been around a few years to force the number of CPU cores the kernel expects in order to allow for better compiler optimizations. When building a kernel targeted for a specific device/platform with a given number of CPU cores, the compiler can optimize CPU mask routines and shrink the size of the resulting kernel image rather than having to accommodate up to a dynamic upper-limit for the number of CPU cores to be found at boot time. Linus Torvalds himself has turned to demoting this CONFIG_FORCE_NR_CPUS option further to avoid confusion...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-18]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-18.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-18.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 18, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Lindroid
(comments)


Understanding SPF, DKIM, and DMARC: A Simple Guide
(comments)


Show HN: Token price calculator for 400+ LLMs
(comments)


Sam Altman is not on YC's board. So why claim to be its chair?
(comments)


“Attention assault” on Fandom
(comments)


Getting 50% (SoTA) on Arc-AGI with GPT-4o
(comments)


Cyber Scarecrow
(comments)


Chat Control Must Be Stopped – Now
(comments)


Chat Control: Incompatible with Fundamental Rights (2022)
(comments)


A new RISC-V Mainboard from DeepComputing
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Panther Lake Audio Support Coming With Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Panther-Lake-Audio-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Panther-Lake-Audio-Linux"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Intel Panther Lake processors aren't expected until at least mid-2025, with Intel open-source Linux engineers already having much of the Arrow Lake and Lunar Lake support in order (the main Lunar Lake area still being ironed out is the Xe2 graphics), work is slowly beginning on upstreaming Panther Lake support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora 41 To Replace Power-Profiles-Daemon With "Tuned"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-41-Goes-Tuned-PPD</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-41-Goes-Tuned-PPD"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T16:36:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Fedora Engineering and Steering Committee has approved of Fedora 41 switching from power-profiles-daemon to "Tuned" as the default power profile management daemon on Fedora Workstation as well as the KDE Plasma and Budgie desktop spins...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Framework Laptop 13 To See A RISC-V Motherboard Option]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Framework-Laptop-RISC-V-Board</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Framework-Laptop-RISC-V-Board"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T15:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Framework Computer Inc announced today that they have been working with DeepComputing on a partner-developed RISC-V motherboard for the Framework Laptop 13...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 6.1 Released With Easier Remote Desktop Support, Wayland Explicit Sync]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T14:43:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Right on schedule today KDE released Plasma 6.1 as the first feature update to the Plasma 6 desktop stack that debuted back in February...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Companies Now Backing Valkey As Leading Redis Fork]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Valkey-Redis-Fork-More-Backers</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Valkey-Redis-Fork-More-Backers"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T14:35:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Announced back in March by the Linux Foundation was Valkey as a Redis fork following upstream licensing changes. In the few months since the Valkey in-memory NoSQL data store has put out its first release and has continued attracting more interest from Linux/open-source communities. Today the Linux Foundation announced another handful of organizations now throwing their weight behind Valkey...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PoCL 6.0 OpenCL Implementation Brings OpenMP For CPU Driver, More Remote Driver Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/PoCL-6.0-Released-OpenCL</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/PoCL-6.0-Released-OpenCL"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T12:48:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Portable Computing Language "PoCL" that started off as a CPU-based OpenCL implementation has grown to support multiple hardware targets from NVIDIA PTX to Intel Level Zero to AMD ROCm and other innovations like a recent remote driver for transparent OpenCL across networked systems. PoCL 6.0 was released today for delivering the latest enhancements to this independent OpenCL compute implementation and continuing to enhance support for its different hardware targets...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marek Olšák Lands Support In Mesa 24.2 To Vectorize IO In The GLSL Linker]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.2-Vectorize-IO-Linker</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.2-Vectorize-IO-Linker"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T12:23:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well known AMD Mesa developer Marek Olšák has shown no signs of hitting the end of the road for optimizing OpenGL support within the Mesa/Gallium3D driver stack. More than one decade since joining AMD and more than a decade and a half of being involved with Mesa since beginning as a student developer, Marek still isn't slowing down with his performance optimizations and new features to benefit the open-source Radeon Linux graphics drivers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Linux Patches To Help Ensure Intel Xeon Servers Can Achieve Highest Frequencies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Xeon-Top-Frequencies</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Xeon-Top-Frequencies"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T11:04:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A set of patches for the Linux kernel's Intel P-State driver aim to ensure Intel Xeon servers can hit their highest clock frequencies following changes in the server's performance profile. It turns out some special handling is needed to update the highest frequencies of a CPU after boot to ensure the performance profile is properly reflected...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora 41 Hopes The GIMP 3.0 Photoshop Alternative Will Be Ready To Shine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-41-GIMP-3.0-Plans</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-41-GIMP-3.0-Plans"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:44:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora developers are hoping that the long-awaited GIMP 3.0 will ship before October and be all ready for serving as the default GIMP package with the in-development Fedora 41...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patches For AMD GPUs On Loongson Point To "Massive Platform Bug" For These Chinese CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-Patches-Loongson-Bug</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-Patches-Loongson-Bug"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:30:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A set of patches were posted on Monday in aiming to get aging AMD Radeon GFX7/GFX8 era graphics processors working on Loongson LoongArch platforms. These patches for handling old Radeon Hawaii~Polaris GPUs on Loongson point to a "massive platform bug" with these domestic Chinese systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Testing Ground Toolkit v0.0.2 Adds NetBSD & FreeBSD Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/X.Org-Testing-Ground-0.0.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/X.Org-Testing-Ground-0.0.2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T09:56:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week marked the inaugural release of the X.Org Testing Ground Toolkit to make it easier to compile the X.Org Server. That v0.0.1 release was limited to supporting Debian/Apt-based Linux distributions while now this helper toolkit has been extended to support FreeBSD and NetBSD too...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-17]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-17.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-17.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 17, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Building SimCity: How to put the world in a machine
(comments)


Why \"Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs\" matters (2011)
(comments)


NumPy 2.0
(comments)


How to get stuff repaired when the manufacturer don't wanna: take 'em to court
(comments)


Being laid off and unplanned entrepreneurship
(comments)


DJI ban passes the House and moves on to the Senate
(comments)


Trading cards with e-ink displays (2023)
(comments)


FTC sues Adobe for hiding fees and inhibiting cancellations
(comments)


Htmx 2.0.0 has been released
(comments)


EU to greenlight Chat Control tomorrow
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora 41 Aims To Ship AMD SEV-SNP Confidential Virtualization Host Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-SEV-SNP-Fedora-41-Plan</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-SEV-SNP-Fedora-41-Plan"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T20:49:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the release of Fedora 41 in October, this Red Hat sponsored Linux distribution is hoping to have all the software bits aligned that its AMD SEV-SNP virtualization stack will be all squared away for this latest iteration of Secure Encrypted Virtualization...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Releases OpenVINO 2024.2 With Llama 3 Optimizations, More AVX2 & AVX-512 Optimizations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/OpenVINO-2024.2-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/OpenVINO-2024.2-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T18:28:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel today released OpenVINO 2024.2, the newest version of its open-source AI toolkit for optimizing and deploying deep learning (A) inference models across a range of AI frameworks and broad hardware types...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME Software To Better Support NVIDIA's Proprietary Linux Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Software-Better-NVIDIA</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Software-Better-NVIDIA"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a planned change for Fedora 41, Red Hat engineers are working on upstream GNOME Software better supporting the NVIDIA proprietary driver installation by allowing the installation to work gracefully with UEFI Secure Boot enabled systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD 14.1 vs. DragonFlyBSD 6.4 vs. NetBSD 10 vs. Linux Benchmarks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/bsd-linux-threadripper-7980x</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/bsd-linux-threadripper-7980x"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T15:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After last week looking at how FreeBSD 14.1 has improved performance over FreeBSD 14.0, here is an expanded cross-OS comparison now looking at how the new FreeBSD 14.1 stable release compares to the recently released NetBSD 10.0, the current DragonFlyBSD 6.4 release, and then CentOS Stream 9 and Ubuntu 24.04 LTS for some Linux comparison data points.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sovereign Tech Fund Opens Up To Smaller Investments & Updated Criteria]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Sovereign-Tech-Fund-Lower-Limit</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Sovereign-Tech-Fund-Lower-Limit"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T13:32:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Germany's Sovereign Tech Fund has been making sizable investments into various Linux desktop projects, the Rust-based Coreutils implementation, libmicrohttpd, PHP, a systemd bug bounty, and other prominent open-source software that could benefit from greater financial resources. Today they have announced they have opened up for a new round of applications for those open-source projects seeking funding from this German government initiative...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Image Denoise 2.3 Prepares For Arrow Lake, Lunar Lake & Battlemage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Open-Image-Denoise-2.3</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Open-Image-Denoise-2.3"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T13:15:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Open Image Denoise open-source software that is a denoising library used by Blender and other applications is out with a new feature release as it prepares for the integrated graphics of upcoming Arrow Lake and Lunar Lake processors as well as nearing the launch of Xe2 / Battlemage discrete graphics...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux To Incorporate Intel CPU Hybrid Topology For Determining Vulnerabilities/Mitigations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Hybrid-Topology-Mitigate</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Hybrid-Topology-Mitigate"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T10:55:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Within the every increasingly complex world of CPU security mitigations, Intel engineers have submitted Linux kernel patches to begin taking into account the CPU core "hybrid" topology when determining relevant CPU security vulnerabilities and in turn the mitigations to apply...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora 41 Looks To Offer A KDE Plasma Mobile Spin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-41-KDE-Mobile-Proposal</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-41-KDE-Mobile-Proposal"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T10:18:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two new change proposals have been filed for enhancing the KDE offerings with this autumn's Fedora 41 release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NumPy 2.0 Brings Faster Performance Thanks To Intel's x86-simd-sort & Google's Highway]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/NumPy-2.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/NumPy-2.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T10:09:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NumPy 2.0 was released on Sunday that's been in the making for the past year and their first major release since 2006. While it comes with API/ABI breakage, NumPy 2.0 delivers new features and performance improvements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The JFS File-System Remains In Sad Shape With The Upstream Linux Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/JFS-Not-Yet-Orphaned-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/JFS-Not-Yet-Orphaned-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T09:31:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While at the start of 2023 was talk among kernel developers for orphaning the JFS file-system at a time that developers began the processes toward removing the ReiserFS file-system driver, the Journaled File-System so far remains within the mainline kernel and not yet officially orphaned...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-16.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-16.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 16, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Just Enough Software Architecture (2010)
(comments)


Google, Cloudflare and Cisco will poison DNS to stop piracy block circumvention
(comments)


SimCity in the web browser using WebAssembly and OpenGL
(comments)


Show HN: We Made The World's Smallest and Cheapest Network Switch
(comments)


What You Get After Running an SSH Honeypot for 30 Days
(comments)


Simple sabotage for software (2023)
(comments)


Do not try to be the smartest in the room; try to be the kindest
(comments)


NLRB judge declares non-compete clause is an unfair labor practice
(comments)


The Raspberry Pi 5 Is No Match for a Tini-Mini-Micro PC
(comments)


MicroMac, a Macintosh for under £5
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10-rc4 Released With Another Week Worth Of Driver Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc4-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc4-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-16T20:56:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds as the father of the Linux kernel set aside some time this Father's Day to release Linux 6.10-rc4...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IceWM 3.6 Released With A Few New Features & Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/IceWM-3.6-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/IceWM-3.6-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-16T13:15:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IceWM 3.6 is out today as the newest version of this lightweight X11 window manager...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux's New DRM Panic "Blue Screen of Death" In Action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-DRM-Panic-BSoD-Picture</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-DRM-Panic-BSoD-Picture"/>
        <updated>2024-06-16T10:48:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After being talked about for years of DRM panic handling and coming with a "Blue Screen of Death" solution for DRM/KMS drivers, Linux 6.10 is introducing a new DRM panic handler infrastructure for being able to display a message when a panic occurs.  This is especially important for those building a kernel without VT/FBCON support where otherwise viewing the kernel panic message isn't otherwise easily available...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VMware Hypercall API To Likely Land In Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/VMware-Hypercall-API-Linux-6.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/VMware-Hypercall-API-Linux-6.11"/>
        <updated>2024-06-16T10:36:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For months Broadcom has been working on the VMware Hypercall API for the Linux kernel. This "vmware_hyperscall" is a new family of functions for use by the VMware guest code and virtual device drivers in an architecture-independent manner...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora Making Strides On Enabling Greater AI Use, Easier AMD ROCm PyTorch Acceleration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-Seeing-More-AI-Work</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-Seeing-More-AI-Work"/>
        <updated>2024-06-16T10:23:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Christian Schaller of Red Hat shared an update on Friday around the ongoing enhancements to Fedora Workstation. Given the current industry trends, ongoing Fedora Workstation development is seeing a lot of attention around... AI, AI, AI...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RKVDEC2 Driver Posted For Accelerated Video Decoding On Newer Rockchip SoCs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/RKVDEC2-Rockchip-Video-Decode</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/RKVDEC2-Rockchip-Video-Decode"/>
        <updated>2024-06-16T10:11:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For years there has been the RKVDEC Linux media driver to provide accelerated video decoding on Rockchip SoCs. Being worked on now is RKVDEC2 for providing video decoding on the newer Rockchip SoCs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-15.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-15.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 15, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Eden Abhez: The strangest hit songwriter
(comments)


Chaos in the medium: Watercolour plotting
(comments)


Microsoft to delay release of Recall AI feature on security concerns
(comments)


H.264 Is Magic (2016)
(comments)


The sun's magnetic field is about to flip
(comments)


AI Search: The Bitter-Er Lesson
(comments)


Exponentially Better Rotations (2022)
(comments)


Voyager 1 is back online! NASA spacecraft returns data from all 4 instruments
(comments)


Perplexity AI is lying about their user agent
(comments)


ESASky
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine Staging 9.11 Released With A Patch For A 17 Year Old Bug Report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-Staging-9.11-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-Staging-9.11-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-15T23:09:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building off Friday's release of Wine 9.11 as that newest bi-weekly development release, Wine Staging 9.11 has been released with some 428 patches re-based atop this latest upstream Wine code...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Linux Change Helps Ensure AMD Ryzen With NVMe Works After Resuming From Suspend]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc4-PM-Ryzen-NVMe</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc4-PM-Ryzen-NVMe"/>
        <updated>2024-06-15T13:50:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Linux power management change merged on Friday aims to help ensure AMD Ryzen systems with NVMe solid-state drive storage will work properly when resuming from suspend...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME Papers Document Viewer Making Progress As GTK4-Based Evince Fork]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Papers-GTK4-Evince-Fork</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Papers-GTK4-Evince-Fork"/>
        <updated>2024-06-15T10:37:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME's longtime document viewer, Evince, was recently forked as GNOME Papers and saw its first release a few weeks back. This new GNOME document viewer has been ported from GTK3 to GTK4 and also brings an improved user interface and other refinements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple M4 Support Added To The LLVM Compiler, Confirming Its ISA Capabilities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Apple-M4-Added-To-LLVM-Clang</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Apple-M4-Added-To-LLVM-Clang"/>
        <updated>2024-06-15T10:06:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple compiler engineers have contributed Apple M4 CPU support to the upstream LLVM/Clang compiler via the new -mcpu=apple-m4 target. Interestingly the Apple M4 is exposed as an ARMv8.7 derived design...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 6.1 Prepares For Release Next Week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Next-Week</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Next-Week"/>
        <updated>2024-06-15T09:47:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 6.1 is preparing for release next week on 18 June. KDE developers this week have thus been very busy with last minute finishing touches to this updated desktop while also already beginning feature work on Plasma 6.2...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 9.11 Released With More Monitor DPI Awareness Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-9.11-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-9.11-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-15T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 9.11 is now available as the newest bi-weekly development release of this open-source software for enjoying Windows games and applications under Linux and other platforms. With Wine 9.11 we are now roughly at the half-way point before Wine's typical feature freeze and release candidate start that typically begins around early December and this cycle will lead up to the Wine 10.0 stable release in early 2025...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-14]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-14.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-14.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 14, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


My thoughts on Python in Excel
(comments)


Show HN: Shpool, a Lightweight Tmux Alternative
(comments)


AMD CEO Lisa Su reminisces about designing the PS3's infamous Cell processor
(comments)


Mouth-based touchpad enables people living with paralysis to use computers
(comments)


Fungus breaks down ocean plastic
(comments)


Land value tax in online games and virtual worlds (2022)
(comments)


I found a 55 year old bug in the first Lunar Lander game
(comments)


Start presentations on the second slide
(comments)


Nvidia Warp: A Python framework for high performance GPU simulation and graphics
(comments)


Microsoft's Recall AI feature is now indefinitely delayed
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Receives New Human Interface Guidelines For 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-New-HIG-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-New-HIG-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T21:16:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prominent KDE developer Nate Graham has been working with various KDE designers and developers to establish a new set of Human Interface Guidelines (HIG)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LibreOffice 24.8 Beta Now Available For Testing This Free Software Office Suite]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/LibreOffice-24.8-Beta-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/LibreOffice-24.8-Beta-1"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T21:12:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LibreOffice 24.8 is now available in beta form for those wanting to test this open-source, cross-platform office suite alternative to the likes of Microsoft Office...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.11 Bringing "Hardware Replay" Feature For Intel Graphics Debugging]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-Intel-HW-Hang-Replay</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-Intel-HW-Hang-Replay"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The main set of drm-intel-gt-next patches aiming for the Linux 6.11 kernel were submitted this week to DRM-Next. Most notable with this feature update for the next kernel version is enabling a new hardware replay feature for better reproducing GPU hangs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 24.10 Seeing More Desktop Installer Improvements, Improving The Steam Snap]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.10-Desktop-June</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.10-Desktop-June"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T13:04:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month some of the Ubuntu 24.10 desktop plans were laid out such as NVIDIA Wayland by default, a new welcome wizard, and more. Canonical's Oliver Smith has posted an update today around some of the ongoing Ubuntu 24.10 desktop enhancements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Vulkan Driver Halves The Time Required For Startup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Vulkan-Faster-vkCreateDev</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Vulkan-Faster-vkCreateDev"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T12:31:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's open-source Vulkan Linux driver "ANV" has reduced the driver start-up time by about half...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Two Year Journey Funded By Arm/Qualcomm For Improving ARM Linux Laptop Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Two-Years-Improving-ARM-Laptops</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Two-Years-Improving-ARM-Laptops"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T11:06:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kernel developer and consultant Johan Hovold spent the last two years working on improving ARM Linux laptop support with a particular focus on the Lenovo ThinkPad X13s powered Qualcomm SoC. Arm funded this Linaro effort and as a result the ThinkPad X13s enjoys pleasant upstream kernel support now. This Arm Linux laptop project has now concluded but sets a nice base for further ARM Linux laptop improvements moving forward...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel To Upstream Habana Labs Network Drivers Into The Linux Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/HabanaLabs-Network-Driver-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/HabanaLabs-Network-Driver-Linux"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:44:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While for years there has been the Habana Labs AI accelerator driver within the mainline Linux kernel, this "accel" driver has been focused on just supporting training/inference across their products. Now being worked on for the mainline Linux kernel are upstreaming the Habana Labs network drivers that can be used for scaling out the AI workloads across multiple systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 24.2 Adds Support For Fixed-Rate Compression Extensions For OpenGL & EGL]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.2-Fixed-Rate-Compress</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.2-Fixed-Rate-Compress"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:26:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Being merged to Mesa 24.2 this week is a set of 12 patches that have been four months in the making for supporting the OpenGL/EGL fixed-rate compression extensions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qt 6.8 Beta Released With Multi-View Rendering, Better GNOME Wayland Experience]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Qt-6.8-Beta-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Qt-6.8-Beta-1"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:08:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first beta release of the Qt 6.8 toolkit is now available for testing with many new features...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10-rc4 To Fix Display For The Ayaneo Kun Gaming Handheld]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Display-Ayaneo-Kun</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Display-Ayaneo-Kun"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T09:38:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those interested in running Linux on the Ayaneo Kun handheld gaming console alternative to Valve's Steam Deck and the ASUS ROG Ally, among others, a display quirk has been submitted ahead of the Linux 6.10-rc4 release this weekend to fix the display handling...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-13]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-13.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-13.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 13, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Banana giant Chiquita held liable by US court for funding paramilitaries
(comments)


Twenty, a modern CRM alternative to Salesforce
(comments)


Serious Sam handled massive amounts of enemies on 56k modem connections
(comments)


The GJK Algorithm: A weird and beautiful way to do a simple thing
(comments)


Japan enacts law to promote competition in smartphone app stores
(comments)


How Meta trains large language models at scale
(comments)


Uncensor any LLM with abliteration
(comments)


Microsoft Chose Profit over Security, Whistleblower Says
(comments)


Indian startup 3D prints rocket engine in 72 hours
(comments)


MLow: Meta's low bitrate audio codec
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA Exploring Ways To Better Support An Upstream Kernel Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/NVIDIA-Exploring-Upstream-KMD</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/NVIDIA-Exploring-Upstream-KMD"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T17:44:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's how an exciting message from a NVIDIA engineer that just hit the mailing list begins: "NVIDIA has been exploring ways to better support the effort for an upstream kernel mode driver for GPUs that are capable of running GSP-RM firmware, since the introduction to Nova."..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fwupd 1.9.21 Released With Synaptics Carrera & Wacom Movink Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fwupd-1.9.21-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fwupd-1.9.21-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T16:51:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fwupd 1.9.21 is now available for this open-source software for facilitating system firmware and device/peripheral firmware updates under Linux and other platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Rocket" Accelerator Open-Source Linux Kernel Driver Posted For Rockchip NPU]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Rocket-Rockchip-NPU-Driver</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Rocket-Rockchip-NPU-Driver"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T14:35:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The past few months open-source developer Tomeu Vizoso has been developing an open-source accelerator driver for Rockchip's NPU. The experimental driver has shown the open-source code can compete with Rockchip's proprietary driver and Vizoso has been working to develop an upstream-minded driver for a kernel driver living within the "accel" subsystem and then leveraging Mesa's Teflon for the user-space component. Yesterday the "Rocket" accel kernel driver was posted for the Rockchip NPU...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Testing Ground Toolkit: Making It Less Difficult To Compile The X Server In 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Xorg-Testing-Ground-Toolkit</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Xorg-Testing-Ground-Toolkit"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T13:51:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the upstream X.Org Server development remains slow with most of the large vendors treating it in maintenance mode and not investing in new features, open-source developer Enrico Weigelt has been one of the few still working to improve the X.Org Server. As part of his work besides pushing new patches and testing of the latest X.Org Server Git state, today he announced the release of the X.Org Testing Ground Toolkit v0.0.1 as a means to help in facilitate testing of the latest X.Org Server Git by making it easier to build it...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu Talks Up A RISC-V Octa-Core Laptop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/DC-ROMA-RISC-V-Laptop-II</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/DC-ROMA-RISC-V-Laptop-II"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T11:02:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu maker Canonical put out a news release today around the DC-ROMA RISC-V Laptop II that is an octa-core RISC-V laptop shipping soon with Ubuntu Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coreboot To Be Shown Today With An Intel Meteor Lake Laptop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Coreboot-Dasharo-Meteor-Lake</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Coreboot-Dasharo-Meteor-Lake"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:46:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Going back to 2022 we've seen work by Intel engineers on adding Meteor Lake SoC support to Coreboot while to date there hasn't been much in the way of actual Intel Core Ultra "Meteor Lake" laptops with Coreboot as a replacement to the proprietary BIOS/firmware. But to be shown later today is one of the first laptop designs using these latest Intel mobile processors and running the Dasharo downstream of Coreboot...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Framework Laptop 16 CAD Design Files Open-Sourced]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Framework-16-CAD-Files</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Framework-16-CAD-Files"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:27:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In making the Framework 16 laptop even more appearing to open-source hardware enthusiasts and makers, Framework Computer has published the CAD design files as open-source...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft's Azure Linux 2.0 Update Ships Dozens Of Security Patches, Adds Azl-Compliance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Azure-Linux-2.0.20240609</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Azure-Linux-2.0.20240609"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:02:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft's in-house Linux distribution, Azure Linux (nee CBL-Mariner), is out with a new update. In the first new stable release for Azure Linux 2.0 since late April, the Azure Linux 2.0.20240609 update ships with dozens of security fixes to address a wide range of CVEs as well as bringing various bug fixes and other updates...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FEX 2406 Brings JIT Optimizations For Running x86_64 Binaries On AArch64]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/FEX-2406-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/FEX-2406-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T09:44:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FEX is one of the open-source projects working on user-mode x86/x86_64 binary emulation atop ARM64/AArch64 Linux. FEX 2406 is out today as the project's newest monthly feature release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-12]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-12.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-12.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 12, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Home-Cooked Software and Barefoot Developers
(comments)


When Water Flows Uphill [video]
(comments)


Show HN: Unforget, the note-taking app I always wanted: offline first, encrypted
(comments)


Self-Serve Dashboards
(comments)


Show HN: Revideo – Create Videos with Code
(comments)


ARC Prize – a $1M+ competition towards open AGI progress
(comments)


Flameshot – Open-source screenshot software
(comments)


Swift Static Linux SDK
(comments)


Silicon Valley's best kept secret: Founder liquidity
(comments)


Elixir 1.17 released: set-theoretic types in patterns, durations, OTP 27
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD Community Survey Confirms ZFS Is Their Most Valued Server Feature]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeBSD-Community-Survey-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeBSD-Community-Survey-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T21:11:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The FreeBSD Foundation has published the results of the FreeBSD Community Survey that reveal interesting insights about FreeBSD usage and its users...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve Rolls Out Proton 9.0-2 With Many Fixes For Running More Games On Steam Play]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Valve-Proton-9.0-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Valve-Proton-9.0-2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T19:24:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proton 9.0-2 is out this afternoon as the Valve/CodeWeavers downstream of Wine that powers Steam Play for running Windows games under Linux within the Steam client...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safety-Critical Rust Consortium Announced]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Safety-Critical-Rust-Consortium</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Safety-Critical-Rust-Consortium"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T16:34:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In aiming to make the Rust programming language more suitable for safety-critical software like within automobiles, aviation, and other industries, the Safety-Critical Rust Consortium was announced today...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD 14.1 vs. FreeBSD 14.0 Benchmarks On AMD Ryzen Threadripper]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/freebsd-141-benchmarks</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/freebsd-141-benchmarks"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T14:36:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Debuting last week was FreeBSD 14.1 with performance improvements and more. Given there being some performance optimizations and other upgrades like a more recent LLVM Clang compiler by default, I've begun running some benchmarks of this newest FreeBSD stable release. In today's article is a quick comparison of FreeBSD 14.1 vs. FreeBSD 14.0 performance using an AMD Ryzen Threadripper 7980X 64-core processor within the System76 Thelio Major workstation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Fast CPPC To Be Merged For Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Fast-CPPC-For-Linux-6.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Fast-CPPC-For-Linux-6.11"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T13:50:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The AMD Fast CPPC feature enablement for the "amd_pstate" driver has been submitted to the power management subsystem ahead of next month's Linux 6.11 merge window...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[openSUSE Leap 15.6 Release - Adds Cockpit, Linux 6.4 & Other Updates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/openSUSE-Leap-15.6-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/openSUSE-Leap-15.6-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T13:21:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSUSE Leap 15.6 is now officially available for this community Linux distribution release aligned with SUSE Linux Enterprise 15 Service Pack 6. With Leap 15.6 comes the inclusion of the Cockpit web administration software and many software updates...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Low Power Mode Daemon v0.0.4 Released To Optimize Hybrid CPUs On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-LPMD-Low-Power-0.0.4</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-LPMD-Low-Power-0.0.4"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:54:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Low Power Mode Daemon v0.0.4 has been released with "LPMD" being the open-source daemon for optimize active idle power for modern Core hybrid CPUs under Linux that sport a combination of the E and P cores...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LLVM Clang 19 Lands Support For C23's #embed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/LLVM-Clang-19-C23-Embed</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/LLVM-Clang-19-C23-Embed"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:27:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged today to LLVM Clang 19 Git is support for the #embed resource inclusion mechanism that is an approved C23 feature. This also makes Clang the first for supporting this pre-processor embed feature...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marek Lands 40 Patch Series To Further Enhance The Open-Source AMD Graphics Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Marek-Universal-Optimized-Comp</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Marek-Universal-Optimized-Comp"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:14:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well known open-source AMD OpenGL/Gallium3D driver developer Marek Olšák has landed a big patch series into Mesa 24.2 for a universal optimized compute image clear/blit shader and MSAA-resolving pixel shader...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's oneDNN 3.5 Begins Optimizing For Xe2, More Xeon 6 Tuning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-oneDNN-3.5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-oneDNN-3.5"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's oneDNN 3.5 has been released as this Deep Neural Network Library for the oneAPI specification and now part of the UXL Foundation. With oneDNN 3.5 comes more performance optimizations for existing and upcoming Intel hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds Throws Down The Hammer: Extensible Scheduler "sched_ext" In Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-Extensible-Scheduler</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-Extensible-Scheduler"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T00:40:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The extensible scheduler "sched_ext" code has proven quite versatile for opening up better Linux gaming performance, more quickly prototyping new scheduler changes, Ubuntu/Canonical has been evaluating it for pursuing a more micro-kernel like design, and many other interesting approaches with it. Yet it's remained out of tree but that is now changing with the upcoming Linux 6.11 cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-11.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-11.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 11, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


I built an ROV to solve missing person cases
(comments)


Apple unveils 'Passwords' manager app at WWDC 2024
(comments)


macOS Sequoia Preview
(comments)


Deterioration of local community a major driver of loss of play-based childhood
(comments)


Apple's On-Device and Server Foundation Models
(comments)


Private Cloud Compute: A new frontier for AI privacy in the cloud
(comments)


Noam Chomsky 'no longer able to talk' after 'medical event'
(comments)


POV-Ray – The Persistence of Vision Raytracer (2021)
(comments)


I like the RP2040
(comments)


Lynn Conway has died
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[systemd 256 Released With run0, systemd-vpick, importctl & Other New Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/systemd-256</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/systemd-256"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T23:20:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Systemd 256 is out today as the latest major feature update to this integral component to modern Linux distributions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SUSE Working To Upstream RP1 Southbridge Linux Driver For The Raspberry Pi 5]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-5-RP1-Linux-RFC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-5-RP1-Linux-RFC"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T20:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Raspberry Pi 5 features the "RP1" as the in-house silicon design for the southbridge to this single board computer. The RP1 driver maintained by Raspberry Pi is just found in their downstream kernel while a SUSE engineer is working to rework that driver so that it can be eventually mainlined in the upstream Linux kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Glibc Non-Temporal Stores Memset Optimization Extended To AMD CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Glibc-Non-Temp-Stores-AMD</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Glibc-Non-Temp-Stores-AMD"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T14:57:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged last month to the GNU C Library (glibc) Git code was a new tunable for non-temporal stores for memset. This optimization for glibc's memset performance was limited to Intel processors given at the time it was only tested/benchmarked on Intel CPUs but now it's proven to be useful too for AMD processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AlmaLinux Now Available For The Raspberry Pi 5]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AlmaLinux-Raspberry-Pi-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AlmaLinux-Raspberry-Pi-5"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T14:12:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coincidentally coming out on the day of Raspberry Pi's IPO is AlmaLinux providing official support for the Raspberry Pi 5...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat Developing "eu-stacktrace" For Profiling Without Frame Pointers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Red-Hat-eu-stacktrace</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Red-Hat-eu-stacktrace"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T13:45:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While last year we saw Fedora to no longer omit the frame pointer to help in debugging/profiling Fedora packages and Ubuntu 24.04 LTS also enabled frame pointers for better debugging/profiling, among other distributions, there is the known performance implications of no longer omitting the frame pointer. But now in aiming to make the best of both worlds, it turns out Red Hat has been developing eu-stracktrace as a new means of profiling without relying on frame pointers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD P-State Linux Patches Updated For Heterogeneous CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-P-State-Hetero-v3</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-P-State-Hetero-v3"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T10:44:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month AMD Linux engineers posted ap atch series for better handling heterogeneous core type CPUs. This is for enhancing the P-State CPU frequency scaling on CPUs featuring a mix of conventional cores and efficiency cores, e.g. Zen 4 and Zen 4C. A third iteration of these patches were posted today...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Open-Sources GWPSan As A New Sanitizer Framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Google-GWPSan</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Google-GWPSan"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T10:25:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google is known for their many contributions to open-source compilers and particular many different sanitizer efforts over the years. Their newest project they have made open-source in this area is GWPSan as a sampling-based sanitizer framework...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Serves Up A Tasty IPO On The London Stock Exchange]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-IPO</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-IPO"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T10:04:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi carried out a successful IPO today on the London Stock Exchange...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[oneAPI-Focused UXL Foundation Now Collaborating With The Khronos Group]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/UXL-Foundation-Khronos-Collab</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/UXL-Foundation-Khronos-Collab"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T00:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year it was announced that Intel's oneAPI software initiative evolved into the UXL Foundation for making compute accelerators more open as well as opening things up to more cross-vendor collaboration and adoption. Intel started the Unified Acceleration Foundation with the Linux Foundation, Google, Arm, Qualcomm, Samsung, and others. Announced today is that the UXL Foundation has begun collaborating with The Khronos Group...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-10.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-10.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 10, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


An Introduction to ARM64 Assembly on Apple Silicon Macs
(comments)


Ultrasonic investigations in shopping centres
(comments)


A Revolution in Biology?
(comments)


Designing a Lego orrery
(comments)


Libtree: Ldd as a tree saying why a library is found or not
(comments)


A ChatGPT mistake cost us $10k
(comments)


Show HN: Markdown HN profiles at {user}.at.hn
(comments)


Apple blocks PC emulator in iOS App Store and third-party app stores
(comments)


Apple Intelligence for iPhone, iPad, and Mac
(comments)


OpenAI and Apple Announce Partnership
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One-Line Patch For Intel Meteor Lake Yields Up To 72% Better Performance, +7% Geo Mean]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-meteorlake-epp-perf</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-meteorlake-epp-perf"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covered last week on Phoronix was a new patch from Intel that with tuning to the P-State CPU frequency scaling driver was showing big wins for Intel Core Ultra "Meteor Lake" performance and power efficiency. I was curious with the Intel claims posted for a couple benchmarks and thus over the weekend set out to run many Intel Meteor Lake benchmarks on this one-line kernel patch... The results are great for boosting the Linux performance of Intel Core ultra laptops with as much as 72% better performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TUXEDO Developing A Snapdragon X Elite Linux Laptop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/TUXEDO-Snapdragon-X-Elite</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/TUXEDO-Snapdragon-X-Elite"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T14:23:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bavarian Linux PC vendor TUXEDO Computers is working on bringing a Snapdragon X Elite powered laptop to market...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 127 With 32-bit x86 Linux Pretending To Be "x86_64" To Reduce Fingerprinting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mozilla-Firefox-127</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mozilla-Firefox-127"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T14:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla Firefox 127.0 binaries are available for download today ahead of tomorrow's official announcement. Firefox 127 brings a few nice changes for this month's feature update...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Posts New Linux Patches For Per-Core CPU Energy Counters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Linux-PMU-Power-Per-Core</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Linux-PMU-Power-Per-Core"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T10:48:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After an attempt in early 2023 didn't pan out, today an AMD Linux engineer posted a new kernel patch series for enabling per-core RAPL energy counter support for AMD processors. With this patch series when using Linux's venerable perf utility it's now possible for reading the power use on a per CPU core basis using a new "power_per_core" PMU...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Quest For Faster getrandom() Performance Continues Two Years Later]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Random-vDSO-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Random-vDSO-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T10:15:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Going back just under two years was the propsal for adding getrandom() to the vDSO in the quest to achieve faster performance for obtaining random numbers in user-space. That effort while seemingly simple remains an ongoing and contentious matter...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Lot More AMD RDNA4/GFX12 Graphics Driver Code Has Landed In Mesa 24.2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Busy-RDNA4-Mesa-24.2-Week</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Busy-RDNA4-Mesa-24.2-Week"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T09:57:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of AMD GFX12 IP enablement landed in Mesa 24.2-devel over the past week for bringing up the RadeonSI Gallium3D driver and RADV Vulkan driver for the upcoming RDNA4 graphics...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-09]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-09.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-09.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 09, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


LSP-AI: open-source language server serving as back end for AI code assistance
(comments)


Detecting a PS2 Emulator: When 1*X does not equal X
(comments)


My favorite 1980's Canadian TV show: Bits and Bytes
(comments)


Gene therapy restores hearing to children with inherited deafness
(comments)


Draw an iceberg and see how it will float
(comments)


Viagra improves brain blood flow and could help to prevent dementia
(comments)


Piku: Allows git push deployments to your own servers
(comments)


Economic Termites: Monopolies not noticeable enough for most of us
(comments)


The Weird Nerd comes with trade-offs
(comments)


Keylogger discovered in image generator extension
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10-rc3 Released For A Boring But Good Week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc3-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc3-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-09T21:37:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds just announced the release of Linux 6.10-rc3 as a rather pleasant week for this stage of the kernel cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arch Linux Powered CachyOS Now Defaults To Btrfs Rather Than XFS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/CachyOS-Btrfs-Default</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/CachyOS-Btrfs-Default"/>
        <updated>2024-06-09T16:25:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arch Linux derivative CachyOS that is optimized for a nice desktop experience and shipping a nice set of performance optimizations/tuning by default is out with its June 2024 refresh...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD's Linux Kernel Compute Driver For ROCm Begins Preparing For RDNA4 GPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDKFD-GFX12-Support</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDKFD-GFX12-Support"/>
        <updated>2024-06-09T10:52:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to debuting their "Peano" LLVM compiler back-end for Ryzen AI NPUs on Friday, AMD also submitted a new batch of feature code for their AMDGPU kernel graphics driver and AMDKFD kernel compute driver of new feature code aiming for the upcoming Linux 6.11 merge window...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel In-Tree Linux Network Drivers Being Adapted To Support Firmware Updates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-IGB-IXGBE-Firmware-Update</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-IGB-IXGBE-Firmware-Update"/>
        <updated>2024-06-09T10:36:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's IGB and IXGBE network drivers within the mainline Linux kernel are being adapted to support firmware updates for the underlying driver. To date such functionality was limited to Intel's out-of-tree versions of these drivers for their higher-end network hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mold 2.32 Released With Increased LLVM LLD Compatibility, Faster Identical Code Folding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mold-2.32-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mold-2.32-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-09T10:07:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mold 2.32 is out as the newest feature release for this high speed code linker that rivals LLVM LLD and GNU Gold...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-08]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-08.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-08.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 08, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Own a weather station? We want your data
(comments)


Tom 7: Badness 0 (Three ways)
(comments)


σ-GPTs: A new approach to autoregressive models
(comments)


Ask HN: Machine learning engineers, what do you do at work?
(comments)


Feynman’s Razor
(comments)


Xv6, a simple Unix-like teaching operating system
(comments)


What Is PID 0?
(comments)


Apollo 8 astronaut William Anders ID'd in WA plane crash
(comments)


South Pole Water Infrastructure
(comments)


The Backrooms of the Internet Archive
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD's Newest Open-Source Surprise: "Peano" - An LLVM Compiler For Ryzen AI NPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Peano-LLVM-Ryzen-AI</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Peano-LLVM-Ryzen-AI"/>
        <updated>2024-06-08T11:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There was a very exciting Friday evening code drop out of AMD... They announced a new project called Peano that serves as an open-source LLVM compiler back-end for AMD/Xilinx AI engine processors with a particular focus on the Ryzen AI SOCs with existing Phoenix and Hawk Point hardware as well as the upcoming XDNA2 found with the forthcoming Ryzen AI 300 series...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME OS Continues Seeing New Features, New GNOME App for Viewing 3D Models]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-CAD-Exhibit-OS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-CAD-Exhibit-OS"/>
        <updated>2024-06-08T10:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME developers continue to be quite busy this summer from enhancing their desktop with more security and accessibility features to further crafting GNOME OS...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redox OS With COSMIC Apps Is Looking Quite Nice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Redox-OS-COSMIC-Look</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Redox-OS-COSMIC-Look"/>
        <updated>2024-06-08T10:26:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jeremy Soller who is an engineer at System76 and manages a side hustle of leading development on the open-source, Rust-written Redox OS has shared the latest look at this open-source operating system with the System76 COSMIC desktop applications...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OBS Studio 30.2 Beta Brings Native NVENC Encoder Support On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/OBS-Studio-30.2-Beta-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/OBS-Studio-30.2-Beta-1"/>
        <updated>2024-06-08T10:17:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Out for testing this weekend is the OBS Studio 30.2 beta software for those into live-streaming their desktop and other screen recording purposes. With the OBS Studio 30.2 release there are video encode improvements for Linux, support for multi-track video streaming, hybrid MP4 output, and other new features...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 6.1 Is Looking To Be A "Good One"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Good-One</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Good-One"/>
        <updated>2024-06-08T10:07:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The KDE Plasma 6.1 desktop is due for release in a little more than one week. Prominent KDE developer Nate Graham thinks this is going to be a "good one" with a lot of new features, better performance, and more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-07]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-07.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-07.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 07, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Show HN: 2d web paddle game
(comments)


The right not to be subjected to AI profiling based on publicly available data
(comments)


lsix: Like \"ls\", but for images
(comments)


Extracting concepts from GPT-4
(comments)


Ice – open source menu bar manager for macOS
(comments)


Cancel Adobe if you are a creative under NDA with your clients
(comments)


How Does GPT-4o Encode Images?
(comments)


Microsoft will switch off Recall by default after security backlash
(comments)


OpenSSH introduces options to penalize undesirable behavior
(comments)


ASCII Silhouettify
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Begins Upstreaming Fuchsia OS Support Into Mesa 3D]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fuchsia-OS-Simple-Mesa-Support</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fuchsia-OS-Simple-Mesa-Support"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T20:45:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With not hearing much about Fuchsia OS in a while and the Fuchsia OS team being hit hard by layoffs last year, coming as a surprise today is seeing Google beginning to upstream Fuchsia OS support into the Mesa 3D graphics driver stack...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.11 To Merge Support For Running AMD SEV-SNP KVM Guests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-611-AMD-SEV-SNP-KVM-Guest</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-611-AMD-SEV-SNP-KVM-Guest"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T17:35:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The patches have been years in the making around AMD SEV-SNP encrypted virtualization and various elements have been upstreamed in prior kernel versions while for the upcoming Linux 6.11 cycle are finally the Kernel-based Virtual Machine (KVM) bits for launching SEV-SNP protected guest virtual machines...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big Speed Boost For AES-GCM Performance On Intel & AMD CPUs Queued Ahead Of Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AES-GCM-Intel-AMD-Linux-6.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AES-GCM-Intel-AMD-Linux-6.11"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T16:39:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The patches recently covered on Phoronix for up to 162% faster AES-GCM encryption/decryption with modern Intel and AMD processors is now queued for introduction in the upcoming Linux 6.11 cycle!..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Lands Support For Vendor Flavored SPIR-V Within LLVM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/LLVM-AMDGCN-Flavored-SPIR-V</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/LLVM-AMDGCN-Flavored-SPIR-V"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T14:12:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SPIR-V used by the likes of OpenGL, OpenCL, and Vulkan is a common intermediate representation (IR) / intermediate language for consumption by device drivers. With code now merged into LLVM, AMD has introduced the notion of vendor "flavored" SPIR-V for containing extra information pertinent to the GPU device/driver being targeted...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Xe Driver Preps For SR-IOV Support & More Lunar Lake With Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-DRM-Intel-Xe-Next</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-DRM-Intel-Xe-Next"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T10:56:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Thursday the first set of Intel Xe driver feature updates were submitted to DRM-Next of material intended for merging with the Linux 6.11 kernel in July...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python 3.13 Beta 2 Released For Testing The Experimental JIT & Other New Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Python-3.13-Beta-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Python-3.13-Beta-2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T10:49:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The second beta is now available for testing of the upcoming Python 3.13 release that is bringing an experimental JIT, a new interactive interpreter, and other big features for this annual Python feature release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved Linux Driver Support Coming For LG Gram 2024 Laptop Models]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/LG-Gram-2024-Laptops-LInux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/LG-Gram-2024-Laptops-LInux"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T10:37:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged to the Linux kernel back in 2018 was an LG Gram laptop driver for supporting various hotkeys and extra functionality of these LG laptops. That driver is now being extended to support the latest LG Gram laptop models...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Most Popular Linux Hardware Reviews & Featured Articles Over 20 Years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Hardware-Reviews-20</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Hardware-Reviews-20"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T10:21:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With this week marking the 20th birthday of Phoronix, as part of the commemorative articles this week has been looking at the most popular Linux/open-source news over 20 years. In the piece today is looking back at the most popular Linux hardware reviews and other featured articles on Phoronix since 2004...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-06]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-06.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-06.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 06, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Mathematical Optimization for Cargo Ships
(comments)


Show HN: Foosbar – My autonomous foosball-playing robot
(comments)


Researchers to retract landmark Alzheimer's paper containing doctored images
(comments)


Most life on Earth is dormant, after pulling an 'emergency brake'
(comments)


Microsoft AI spying scandal: time to rethink privacy standards
(comments)


Saint Michael Sword: Are the cathedrals really on a straight line?
(comments)


I learned Vulkan and wrote a small game engine with it
(comments)


AeroSpace is an i3-like tiling window manager for macOS
(comments)


Super Heavy has splashed down in The Gulf of Mexico
(comments)


Roman Roads (2017)
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated Intel Meteor Lake Tuning For Linux Shows Huge Performance/Power Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-MTL-EPP-Tuning-64</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-MTL-EPP-Tuning-64"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T20:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's like magic with one line of code changed in the Linux kernel that Intel is reporting up to 19% performance improvement for Intel Core Ultra "Meteor Lake" and up to an 11% improvement in performance per Watt. Or in another EPP mode, the power consumption during video playback can be reduced by 52%!..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New AMD RDNA 3.5 GPU Target "GFX1152" Appears In Open-Source Linux Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-GFX1152-Appears</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-GFX1152-Appears"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T17:02:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When it comes to the RDNA 3.5 / RDNA 3+ integrated graphics found with upcoming AMD products, the graphics driver IP has been referred to as "GFX1150" and "GFX1151" of the AMD GFX 11.5 graphics IP. But now appearing today within the AMDGPU LLVM shader compiler is a new GFX1152 variant...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD EPYC 4364P & 4564P @ DDR5-4800 / DDR5-5200 vs. Intel Xeon E-2488]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/amd-epyc-4004-ddr5-xeon</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/amd-epyc-4004-ddr5-xeon"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T16:15:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the AMD EPYC 4004 series that was announced in May and we have delivered benchmarks of the entire EPYC 4004 stack from the 4-core SKU up through the 16-core model with 3D V-Cache, there are many advantages over Intel's Xeon E-2400 series competition. In addition to going up to 16 cores versus 8 with the Xeon E-2400 series, the more competitive pricing, the 3D V-Cache SKUs, and 28 PCIe lanes rather than 20, the AMD EPYC 4004 models also support DDR5-5200 memory where as the Intel Raptor Lake E-2400 models are bound to DDR5-4800. In this follow-up testing is a look at the AMD EPYC 4004 performance both at DDR5-4800 and DDR5-5200 speeds for showing the performance difference.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shopping For A Launch-Day AMD Ryzen AI 300 Series Laptop For Linux Testing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ryzen-AI-300-Laptop-Shopping</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ryzen-AI-300-Laptop-Shopping"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T14:40:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With this week's Computex announcement by AMD of the Ryzen AI 300 series laptop processors built atop Zen 5, one of the pleasant aspects has been several laptop models being announced already to be powered by either the Ryzen AI 9 365 or Ryzen AI 9 HX 370 flagship models. Some models are also already available for pre-order ahead of launch day. This is quite nice compared to in the past there was often at times quite a delay between the initial AMD Ryzen mobile announcements and being able to (pre)order any hardware. And thus I've already been looking around to coordinate near launch day Linux testing of the new AMD Zen 5 powered Ryzen AI 300 series hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Releases Azure Linux 3.0 Preview]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Microsoft-Azure-Linux-3.0-Pre</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Microsoft-Azure-Linux-3.0-Pre"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft has published its first tagged preview of the upcoming Azure Linux 3.0 operating system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated AMD GPU Firmware Makes Valve's Steam Deck More Robust Against Buggy Apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-More-Robust-Steam-Deck</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-More-Robust-Steam-Deck"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD has published a new set of AMDGPU firmware binaries for Linux users. In particular, this should benefit AMD APUs the most and these firmware improvements were focused on Valve's Steam Deck to make the device more robust against buggy applications...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Fixes AMD Zen 5 CPU Frequency Reporting With cpupower]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-cpupower-Zen-5-Freq</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-cpupower-Zen-5-Freq"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:39:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week's pull request of power management fixes for the Linux 6.10 kernel has an important change for the in-tree cpupower utility to fix P-State frequency reporting on upcoming Zen 5 (Family 1Ah) processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Most Popular Linux News Over The Past 20 Years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/20-Year-Popular-News</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/20-Year-Popular-News"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:20:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With yesterday marking the 20th birthday of Phoronix, I was curious what the most popular news articles were over these past two decades. There's a lot of compiler fodder, news from the early days of AMD Ryzen, Linus Torvalds commentary, and more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sovereign Tech Fund Providing €300k For GNU libmicrohttpd]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/STF-GNU-libmicrohttpd</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/STF-GNU-libmicrohttpd"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:13:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest funding for open-source from Germany's Sovereign Tech Fund is providing €300,000 over the course of the next year for improving GNU libmicrohttpd for building high performance HTTP web servers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Libinput 1.26 Rolls Out New Features, gsetwacom Introduced To Replace xsetwacom]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/libinput-1.26-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/libinput-1.26-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:01:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat's Peter Hutterer is out with two important updates to the Linux input stack: libinput 1.26 has released for this input handling library used both by X.Org and Wayland systems and then secondly he has announced the "gsetwacom" CLI program as a replacement to the "xsetwacom" program...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 24.1.1 Released With Many Graphics Driver Bug Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.1.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.1.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T00:22:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those typically waiting until the first point release of a new Mesa3D driver series before upgrading, today it's your chance to upgrade! Mesa 24.1.1 is now available with the first round of Mesa 24.1 fixes to the prominent OpenGL and Vulkan drivers. Coincidentally the bi-weekly release times nicely for the Phoronix 20th birthday today as a nice present with our love for the open-source Linux graphics stack...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-05]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-05.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-05.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 05, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Sphere Rendering: Flat Planets
(comments)


Some notes on influenceering
(comments)


An animated introduction to Fourier series
(comments)


You'll regret using natural keys
(comments)


Israel reportedly used fake social accounts to garner support from US lawmakers
(comments)


Simple tasks showing reasoning breakdown in state-of-the-art LLMs
(comments)


Boeing Starliner launches first crewed mission
(comments)


Vulkan1.3 on the M1 in one month
(comments)


Managing my motivation as a solo dev
(comments)


Employees who stay in companies longer than two years get paid 50% less (2014)
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blender 4.2 LTS Beta Brings Open Image Denoise On AMD GPUs, GPU Compositing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Blender-4.2-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Blender-4.2-Beta"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T18:24:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The beta process has begun for the Blender 4.2 open-source 3D modeling software. Making Blender 4.2 all the more significant is that it's a Long Term Support (LTS) release for this widely-used program by 3D artists across platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Honeykrisp" Is A New Vulkan Driver For Apple M1 On Linux - Derived From The NVK Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Honeykrisp-Apple-Vulkan-Driver</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Honeykrisp-Apple-Vulkan-Driver"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T16:09:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the Asahi AGX Gallium3D driver for OpenGL support with Apple Silicon on Linux has been maturing nicely and is quite capable these days, the Vulkan support hasn't been coming together as quick or for as long. But a new Apple Silicon Vulkan driver was recently started by Asahi Linux / Mesa developers and is looking positive for being able to become a compliant Vulkan 1.3 driver for the Apple M1 on Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Xeon 6766E/6780E Sierra Forest vs. Ampere Altra Performance & Power Efficiency]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6700e-ampere-altra</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6700e-ampere-altra"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T15:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the launch day review of the Intel Xeon 6766E and Xeon 6780E "Sierra Forest" processors the focus was on looking at the performance and power efficiency compared to prior Intel Xeon generations as well as the AMD EPYC competition. For those wondering how Intel's new Xeon 6 Sierra Forest processors compete against Amere Computing's "cloud native" Altra Max processors, here are those benchmarks looking at the performance and power efficiency.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA 555.52.04 Beta Linux Driver Brings Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/NVIDIA-555.52.04-Linux-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/NVIDIA-555.52.04-Linux-Beta"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T13:51:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few weeks ago NVIDIA introduced their much anticipated R555 beta driver with NVIDIA 555.42.02 for Linux bringing Wayland explicit sync support, the GPU System Processor (GSP) firmware being used by default, and a variety of Wayland improvements. Today the NVIDIA 555.52.04 beta driver is out that offers additional fixes for the R555 series...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Is Soliciting Ideas For Their Goals To Pursue Over The Next 2~3 Years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Goals-2024-Request</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Goals-2024-Request"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T13:25:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in 2022 the KDE project laid out new goals to improve accessibility, develop more environmentally sustainable software, and automate more processes for easing the development of KDE. These overarching KDE Goals are refined every 2~3 years and they are now soliciting ideas from the community for what they should focus on ahead...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.11 Device Mapper Will Optimize Flushing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-DM-Optimize-Flushing</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-DM-Optimize-Flushing"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T10:32:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest performance optimization work for the Linux kernel's Device Mapper (DM) comes thanks to Red Hat's Mikulas Patocka...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel NPU Library v1.2 Adds Int4 Support & Performance Optimizations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-NPU-Library-v1.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-NPU-Library-v1.2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T10:20:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel released a new version of its NPU Acceleration Library, the user-space Python library for leveraging the Neural Processing Unit (NPU) found within their Core Ultra "Meteor Lake" laptops and upcoming Lunar Lake and Arrow Lake hardware as well...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMDVLK 2024.Q2.2 Driver Brings Bug Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDVLK-2024.Q2.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDVLK-2024.Q2.2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T10:02:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building off last month's AMDVLK 2024.Q2.1 driver adding Phoenix 2 support, AMD today released AMDVLK 2024.Q2.2 as the newest update to their official open-source Vulkan Linux driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Today Marks 20 Years Since Starting Phoronix For Linux Hardware Reviews & News]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Phoronix-20th-Birthday</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Phoronix-20th-Birthday"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well, it's been a wild ride to say the least... Today marks twenty years since I started Phoronix.com devoted to reviewing Linux hardware and ultimately enriching the Linux hardware experience with more benchmarks, open-source/Linux hardware news, and more over the years...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD ROCm 6.1.2 Released With Fixes & Optimizations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-ROCm-6.1.2-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-ROCm-6.1.2-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T00:17:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ROCm 6.1.2 is out today as the newest update to AMD's open-source GPU compute stack for Linux systems and with growing support for Windows Subsystem for Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-04]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-04.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-04.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 04, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Hacking millions of modems and investigating who hacked my modem
(comments)


Show HN: 10 Years to Build a Free SQL Editor
(comments)


Show HN: I made a tiny camera with super long battery life
(comments)


If English was written like Chinese (1999)
(comments)


Diffusion on syntax trees for program synthesis
(comments)


Hacking millions of modems and investigating who hacked my modem
(comments)


I am sick of LeetCode-style interviews
(comments)


A breakthrough towards the Riemann hypothesis
(comments)


Why do electronic components have such odd values? (2021)
(comments)


Things the guys who stole my phone have texted me to try to get me to unlock it
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dell "PC Extras" Driver Slated For Linux 6.11 - Initially To Control Fan Modes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Dell-PC-Driver-For-Linux-6.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Dell-PC-Driver-For-Linux-6.11"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Queued into the x86 platform drivers' "for-next" branch ahead of the Linux 6.11 kernel cycle is the "Dell PC Extras" driver. Initially this new dell-pc driver is used for controlling fan modes via the Platform Profile setting on capable systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Open-Source Vulkan Driver Wires Up Mesh Shader Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-ANV-Mesh-Shader-Queries</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-ANV-Mesh-Shader-Queries"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T18:22:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building atop the Intel "ANV" Vulkan driver's mesh shader support that's been enabled by default since last year, the newest Mesa 24.2-devel code as of today now adds support for mesh shader queries...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora Moves Ahead In Replacing Redis With Valkey]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-Replacing-Redis-Valkey</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-Replacing-Redis-Valkey"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in April I noted that Fedora was considering replacing Redis with Valkey given the upstream Redis software licensing changes. At yesterday's Fedora Engineering and Steering Committee (FESCo) they have now signed off on replacing Redis with Valkey...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IBM Ready With POWER11 Support "-mcpu=power11" For GCC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/IBM-GCC-mcpu-power11-Ready</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/IBM-GCC-mcpu-power11-Ready"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T14:45:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IBM compiler engineers are ready to flip-on their POWER11 support within the GNU Compiler Collection (GCC) in wiring up the "-mcpu=power11" option...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated Printk Rework Patches - Necessary Step For Mainlining Linux Real-Time "RT"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Printk-Rework-v2-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Printk-Rework-v2-Linux"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T10:43:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[John Ogness of Linutronix today sent out the second iteration of his patches working on threaded printing support for printk() and related rework of that code that is a necessary step before the real-time (RT) kernel patches can be finally mainlined...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi AI Kit Launches For $70 For 13 TOPS AI Inference]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-AI-Kit</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-AI-Kit"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T10:04:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi teamed up with Hailo to develop the Raspberry Pi AI Kit as a $70 add-on for the Raspberry Pi 5 that offers a 13 TOPS AI accelerator module...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD 14.1 Released With Performance Improvements, OpenZFS Upgrade & Better Sound]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeBSD-14.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeBSD-14.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T09:52:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD 14.1-RELEASE is now available as the newest stable release to this leading BSD operating system. There are a number of package updates, new features, and expanded hardware support to find with FreeBSD 14.1...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Xeon 6780E / Xeon 6766E 144-Core Performance Benchmarks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6780e-6766e</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6780e-6766e"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T03:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Intel's launch today of the Xeon 6700E series processors formerly codenamed Sierra Forest I am now able to share benchmarks of these new E-core server processors. Here is an initial look at the Intel Sierra Forest Linux performance using the Xeon 6766E and Xeon 6780E 144-core server processors in both single and dual socket configurations compared to prior Intel Xeon processors and the AMD EPYC competition.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Launches Xeon 6700E Sierra Forest CPUs - Initially Up To 144 Cores]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6700e-sierra-forest</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6700e-sierra-forest"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T03:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel is using Computex 2024 for announcing the first Xeon 6 processors, which are the E-Core Sierra Forest models that initially are available in up to 144 cores per socket. Intel is also using Computex to shed more light on the Gaudi 3 AI accelerator and the upcoming P core Xeon 6 Granite Rapids processors and the later launch of the Xeon 6900E models with up to 288 cores per socket.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Reveals New Lunar Lake Details At Computex]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Lunar-Lake-Xe2-Details</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Lunar-Lake-Xe2-Details"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[24 hours ago AMD was in the limelight in announcing the Ryzen 9000 series, the Ryzen AI 300 series, teasing AMD 5th Gen EPYC, etc. Now the tables have turned to Intel with the embargo lifting concerning new details on the Gaudi 3 AI accelerator and upcoming Lunar Lake mobile processors and the launch of the Intel Xeon 6700E (Sierra Forest) E-core server processors. In this article is a look at some of the new disclosures around Lunar Lake...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-03]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-03.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-03.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 03, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


L(O*62).ONG: Make your URL longer
(comments)


Everything I know about the fast inverse square root algorithm
(comments)


Ask HN: What was your most humbling learning moment?
(comments)


An intuitive guide to Maxwell's equations (2020)
(comments)


Learn CSS Grid with a virtual garden game
(comments)


AMD Unveils Ryzen 9000 CPUs for Desktop, Zen 5
(comments)


Making USB devices – end to end guide to your first gadget
(comments)


I'm forking Ladybird and stepping down as SerenityOS BDFL
(comments)


How many photons are received per bit transmitted from Voyager 1?
(comments)


Ask HN: Who is hiring? (June 2024)
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Hiring To Improve Their Linux Driver/ROCm Installation Process Across Distributions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Unified-Linux-Jobs</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Unified-Linux-Jobs"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T21:05:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD is hiring engineers to work on build and packaging of their "AMD Unified Linux Driver" to enhance the experience of deploying their packaged graphics driver stack -- including ROCm -- across different Linux distributions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rust-Written Redox OS Continues Gravitating Toward The COSMIC Desktop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Redox-OS-May-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Redox-OS-May-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T16:53:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Rust-written Redox OS operating system issued their May monthly status report to highlight the various improvements made to this original open-source OS...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debian Seeing Work To Support systemd-boot]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Debian-Expert-systemd-boot</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Debian-Expert-systemd-boot"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T15:10:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Debian developer Luca Boccassi has begun working on systemd-boot support for using it as an alternative to the GRUB bootloader...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Mint Disabling Unverified Flatpaks By Default]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Mint-Unverified-Flatpaks</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Mint-Unverified-Flatpaks"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T12:43:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux Mint project is out with its monthly newsletter that highlights recent progress made on this Ubuntu (and Debian) derived, desktop-focused Linux distribution. In May they worked out enhancements to Linux Mint's software manager and also continued working on optimizing their package archive hosting...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Up To 162% Faster AES-GCM Encryption/Decryption For Intel & AMD CPUs On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AES-GCM-Faster-AVX-VAES</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AES-GCM-Faster-AVX-VAES"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T10:38:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the in-development Linux 6.10 kernel Eric Biggers of Google landed new AES-XTS implementations for much faster performance for Intel/AMD processors via new AES-NI + AVX, VAES + AVX2, VAES + AVX10/256, and VAES + AVX10/512 code paths. Biggers has since begun tackling even better AES-GCM encryption/decryption performance by leveraging a new code path to utilize AVX-512/AVX10 and/or VAES...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 15 Merges Support For Intel APX NF]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-15-APX-NF</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-15-APX-NF"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T10:22:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest feature work around Intel's Advanced Performance Extensions (APX) that is merged for the in-development GCC 15 compiler is supporting APX NF functionality for suppressing the update of status flags on arithmetic operations...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCV 4.10 Released With Many DNN Improvements, Wayland Backend For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/OpenCV-4.10-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/OpenCV-4.10-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T09:54:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCV 4.10 is out today as the newest version of the Open Computer Vision Library for this widely-used library with machine learning support, object detection, segmentation and recognition, motion video tracking, gesture recognition, and a variety of other features important for today's diverse workloads...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phoronix Turns 20 Years Old This Week - Celebrate With A Premium Special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Phoronix-20th-Birthday-Special</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Phoronix-20th-Birthday-Special"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Wednesday, 5 June, marks 20 years since I started Phoronix.com for covering the Linux hardware ecosystem! It's sure been a long and tough journey with more remarks I'll reserve for Wednesday, but given the two decade mark, there's a Phoronix Premium special for those wishing to mark the special occasion and help ensure the site's healthy continuance into the next decade...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Ryzen 9000 Series Announced - Zen 5 Showing Big Generational Uplift]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Ryzen-9000-Series-Zen-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Ryzen-9000-Series-Zen-5"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T03:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arguably most exciting out of AMD's slew of Computex 2024 announcements is finally making official the Ryzen 9000 "Granite Ridge" processors built atop the new Zen 5 cores...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Previews 5th Gen EPYC With Up To 192 Cores Per Socket]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-5th-Gen-EPYC-Turin-192-Core</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-5th-Gen-EPYC-Turin-192-Core"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T03:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to all of the AMD client-side news during Lisa Su's keynote at Computex 2024 (see AMD Ryzen 9000 Series and AMD's Ryzen AI 300 Series Mobile APUs), the AMD CEO also teased the upcoming 5th Gen EPYC processors. AMD 5th Gen EPYC "Turin" processors are still on the way for releasing in H2'2024...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD's Ryzen AI 300 Series Mobile APUs Should Be Interesting For Next-Gen Laptops]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Ryzen-AI-300-Series-Zen-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Ryzen-AI-300-Series-Zen-5"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T03:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to announcing the AMD Ryzen 9000 series desktop processors powered by Zen 5, Lisa Su at Computex 2024 also announced the AMD Ryzen AI 300 series as the next-generation mobile processors powered by Zen 5 CPU cores while sporting RDNA 3.5 (also referred to as RDNA 3+ and RDNA3 refresh) integrated graphics and an XDNA 2 NPU...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Roadmaps Instinct MI325X Accelerator For Q4, Instinct MI350 In 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Instinct-MI325X-MI350-MI400</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Instinct-MI325X-MI350-MI400"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Computex 2024, AMD confirmed the Instinct MI325X will be released in Q4'2024 as the successor to the MI300X accelerator. Next year will be the AMD Instinct MI350 series based on the new CFNA 4 architecture. AMD is committing to an annual Instinct accelerator roadmap moving forward as they further up their AI game...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Announces Radeon PRO W7900 Dual Slot For Workstations & Gen AI]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Radeon-PRO-W7900-Dual-Slot</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Radeon-PRO-W7900-Dual-Slot"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the AMD Ryzen 9000 series (Zen 5) details are arguably the most exciting aspect of Lisa Su's keynote at Computex 2024, over on the Radeon side is the announcement of the AMD Radeon PRO W7900 Dual Slot graphics card intended for compact workstations and Gen AI...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-02]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-02.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-02.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 02, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Repairing my mug with Kintsugi
(comments)


What we've learned from a year of building with LLMs
(comments)


In Colorado, an ambitious new highway policy is not building them
(comments)


What I think about Lua after shipping a project with 60k lines of code
(comments)


Einstein went to his office just so he could walk home with Gödel
(comments)


Lisp: Icing or Cake?
(comments)


Python notebooks for fundamentals of music processing
(comments)


How do our brains adapt to control an extra body part?
(comments)


Signal: Will leave the EU market rather than undermine our privacy guarantees
(comments)


Parable of the Sofa
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10-rc2 Released With An Initial Batch Of Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc2-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc2-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds just released Linux 6.0-rc2 with a busy week's worth of fixes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autodafe 1.0 Released For Freeing Projects Of Autotools]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Autodafe-1.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Autodafe-1.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Controversial free software developer Eric S Raymond has been spending a lot of time recently on the new Autodafe project as a means of free software projects from relying on Autotools. This "De-Autoconfiscation" has now led to the release of Autodafe 1.0 with the tool now being considered production-ready...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.11 To Bring Nouveau NVreg_RegistryDwords Support, Intel NPU Enhancements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/DRM-Misc-6.11-Nouveau-Intel-NPU</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/DRM-Misc-6.11-Nouveau-Intel-NPU"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now past the Linux 6.10 merge window, this week brought an initial batch of drm-misc-next changes submitted to the Direct Rendering Manager subsystem's DRM-Next for queuing until the Linux 6.11 merge window opens up in July. The changes this week include a notable addition for the open-source NVIDIA (Nouveau) driver and some improvements for the Intel iVPU driver for their Neural Processing Unit (NPU)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10-rc2 Will Fix Booting Intel Quark CPUs & Problems With Old AMD CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc2-x86-urgent</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc2-x86-urgent"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of today's Linux 6.10-rc2 kerne weekly test release a few "x86/urgent" patches were submitted for addressing some fallout on Intel and AMD processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ASUS Announces The ROG Ally X Upgraded Handheld]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/ASUS-ROG-Ally-X</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/ASUS-ROG-Ally-X"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T10:14:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ASUS used Computex 2024 for announcing the ROG Ally X, the latest version of their handheld gaming console. The ASUS ROG Ally X continues to be powered by the AMD Ryzen Z1 Extreme SoC but now having more storage, faster RAM, a larger battery, updated controls, and other refinements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Shoots Past The 2% Threshold For The Steam Survey, AMD CPU Use Breaks 75%]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Steam-2024-Above-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Steam-2024-Above-2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T00:37:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Steam on Linux debuted a decade ago it maintained around a 2% marketshare before receding and then beginning its long climb back up following the debut of Steam Play for running Windows games on Linux and then with the much anticipated Steam Deck handheld game console and the modern Arch-based SteamOS. Valve just published their May 2024 numbers for the Steam Survey and they indicate the Linux marketshare is finally back above 2%...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-01]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-01.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-01.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 01, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Debian KDE: Right Linux distribution for professional digital painting in 2024
(comments)


Carpenter's AirTags help uncover 'massive' case of stolen tools in Maryland
(comments)


This Message Does Not Exist
(comments)


How to copy a file from a 30-year-old laptop
(comments)


Recall: Stealing everything you've ever typed or viewed on your own Windows PC
(comments)


UI elements with a hand-drawn, sketchy look
(comments)


Tiny number of 'supersharers' spread the majority of fake news
(comments)


ROOT: analyzing petabytes of data scientifically
(comments)


Arthur Whitney releases an open-source subset of K with MIT license
(comments)


Napster sparked a file-sharing revolution 25 years ago
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VCN5 AV1 Encode & More AMD RDNA4 RADV Support Land In Mesa 24.2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-More-GFX12-RDNA4-Mesa-24.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-More-GFX12-RDNA4-Mesa-24.2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T14:48:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been another busy week with the open-source AMD Linux graphics driver stack with continued preparations around enabling support for next-generation RDNA4 graphics (as well as continued RDNA3+ / RDNA 3.5 tuning)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Xe2 Brings Native 64-bit Integer Arithmetic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Xe2-Native-64-bit-Int</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Xe2-Native-64-bit-Int"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T10:50:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As some more exciting news for upcoming Xe2 graphics with Lunar Lake integrated graphics and Battlemage discrete GPUs, the latest open-source driver activity for Linux has confirmed Xe2 supporting native 64-bit integer arithmetic...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debian Has Yet To Establish Firm Stance On The Use Of AI]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Debian-AI-Undecided</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Debian-AI-Undecided"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T10:45:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the Gentoo Linux project recently established an AI policy to forbid contributions to the project made using any AI tools/assistance and NetBSD also came out with a similar policy against AI-generated code, the Debian project for now has no project-wide policy regarding AI...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA Open Kernel Driver News, AMD EPYC 4004 & Linux 6.10 Made For A Fun May]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/May-2024-Highlights</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/May-2024-Highlights"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T10:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[May 2024 is now in the books with 285 original news articles written by your's truly last month along with another 14 Linux hardware reviews / multi-page featured benchmark articles. It was an interesting month with some fun new hardware launches, the Linux 6.10 merge window taking place, and other open-source software progress...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Releases Updated Celeron & Pentium Silver CPU Microcode]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Celeron-Silver-Microcode</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Celeron-Silver-Microcode"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T10:13:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's not too common for Intel to publish new CPU microcode updates outside of their "Patch Tuesday" regiment but that happened yesterday with a Friday night release of new CPU microcode although this time is limited to the Celeron and Pentium Silver families...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME Shares Update On Sovereign Tech Fund & Other Development Funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-STF-Update</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-STF-Update"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T01:55:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Expressed last week was a "major issue" from the GNOME Foundation side with regard to the Sovereign Tech Fund partnership for funding a number of useful improvements to the GNOME software stack just as Germany's STF has been doing to a number of other prominent open-source projects. While there still aren't many clear public details on this "major issue", a Friday night update from the GNOME side seems to indicate all is well and they are also embarking on additional development funding initiatives...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkan 1.3.286 Released With One New Extension]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Vulkan-1.3.286-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Vulkan-1.3.286-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T00:38:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkan 1.3.286 was released today with a handful of corrections/clarifications as well as one new extension...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-31]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-31.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-31.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 31, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


The Pumpkin Eclipse
(comments)


Unexpected anti-patterns for engineering leaders
(comments)


Show HN: Every mountain, building and tree shadow mapped for any date and time
(comments)


Japan's push to make all research open access
(comments)


Engineering for Slow Internet
(comments)


Every mountain, building and tree shadow in the world simulated for any time
(comments)


A man ordered to hide his boat painted the boat on his fence
(comments)


Snowflake breach: Hacker confirms access through infostealer infection
(comments)


Standard Ebooks' 1,000th title: Ulysses
(comments)


IRS Direct File to open to all 50 states and D.C. for 2025 tax season
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 9.10 Released With Upgrade To VKD3D 1.12, Brings DPI Awareness Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-9.10-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-9.10-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T23:14:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 9.10 is out today as the newest bi-weekly development release for this open-source software to enjoy Windows games/applications on Linux and other operating systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Godot 4.3 Beta 1 Released With Native Wayland Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Godot-4.3-Beta-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Godot-4.3-Beta-1"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T14:06:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The open-source Godot game engine has worked its way up to the Godot 4.3 Beta 1 milestone with some exciting achievements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dav1d 1.4.2 Provides More AVX2 & AVX-512 Performance Optimizations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/dav1d-1.4.2-AV1-Decoder</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/dav1d-1.4.2-AV1-Decoder"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T13:57:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jean-Baptiste Kempf released Dav1d 1.4.2 as the newest version of this speedy CPU-based AV1 video decoder. With this new dav1d 1.4.2 update are yet more performance optimizations for modern systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Lands A Nice Memset Performance Optimization In Glibc]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Glibc-Memset-Perf</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Glibc-Memset-Perf"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T12:56:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel engineer Noah Goldstein has landed another nice performance optimization in the GNU C Library "glibc" for benefiting newer Intel processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Is Making It Much Easier To Deal With Quirky Touchscreens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Easier-Quirky-Touch</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Easier-Quirky-Touch"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T11:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Right now when dealing with quirky/buggy touchscreens a C file needs to be manually manipulated and the Linux kernel recompiled. With a new "i2c_touchscreen_props" kernel command line option on its way to the mainline kernel, the process of overriding touchscreen properties is dramatically easier for those dealing with Linux on touchscreen-enabled devices...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bcachefs Preparing For New Features In Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Bcachefs-Look-Toward-Linux-6.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Bcachefs-Look-Toward-Linux-6.11"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T10:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bcachefs lead developer Kent Overstreet sent in a batch of file-system fixes on Thursday for the in-development Linux 6.10 kernel. In that pull request he teased features that are set to arrive with the Linux 6.11 kernel later in the summer...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More AMDGPU Linux Firmware Published For RDNA 3+]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-Firmware-More-RDNA-3.5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-Firmware-More-RDNA-3.5"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T10:28:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month we began seeing AMDGPU driver firmware files published for the rumored "RDNA3+" hardware as an RDNA3 refresh (also as "RDNA 3.5") for upcoming APUs. More firmware files have now landed public in linux-firmware.git for these forthcoming RDNA3 refresh products...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kdenlive 24.05 Brings Multi-Format Rendering, Automatic Subtitle Translations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Kdenlive-24.05-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Kdenlive-24.05-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T10:19:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If the recent release of Flowblade 2.16 video editor wasn't of interest to you due to being GTK-based software, the Qt/KDE-aligned Kdenlive video editor is out this week with its Kdenlive 24.05 feature release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-30]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-30.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-30.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 30, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Donating forks to the dining hall
(comments)


DuckDB Doesn't Need Data to Be a Database
(comments)


Gov. Polis Signs Bill Mandating That Consumers Have Options to Fix Electronics
(comments)


FrankenPHP: Modern PHP App Server
(comments)


How actors remember their lines
(comments)


After 6 years, I'm over GraphQL
(comments)


I got tired of hearing that YC fired Sam, so here's what actually happened
(comments)


I love my wife. My wife is dead (1946)
(comments)


Show HN: ChatGPT UI for rabbit holes
(comments)


Don't DRY Your Code Prematurely
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wayland 1.23 Released With OpenBSD Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wayland-1.23-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wayland-1.23-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T19:46:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Simon Ser today released Wayland 1.23 for this core Wayland code that brings some minor enhancements, bug fixes, and Wayland protocol clarifications...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Rolling Out New Windows Subsystem For Linux "WSL" Features For 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Microsoft-WSL2-2024-Features</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Microsoft-WSL2-2024-Features"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T18:43:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Given Microsoft's recent BUILD conference, Microsoft has announced a number of sizable updates to Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD EPYC 4124P Benchmarks: A Quad-Core $149 Server CPU]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/amd-epyc-4124p</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/amd-epyc-4124p"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T16:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week with the AMD EPYC 4004 review and benchmarks I tested nearly the entire product stack for these new AM5-based server processors with the EPYC 4244P (6 cores), EPYC 4344P (8 cores), EPYC 4364P (8 cores), EPYC 4464P (12 cores), EPYC 4484X (12 cores + 3D V-Cache), EPYC 4564P (16 cores), and EPYC 4584PX (16 cores + 3D V-Cache). The only EPYC 4004 class processor I wasn't able to finish testing in time was the entry-level EPYC 4124P as a 4-core processor with $149 retail price. I've now had the time to finish benchmarking that budget-focused Zen 4 server processor as well as seeing how it compares to the 4-core Skylake Xeons that were prolific for years.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora's New Web-Based Installer UI Delayed Yet Again... Now In 2025 With Fedora 42]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Anaconda-Web-UI-Fedora-42</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Anaconda-Web-UI-Fedora-42"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T15:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been more than two years now talking about the Anaconda installer for Fedora/RHEL shifting to a web-based UI. Going back to Fedora 37 have been previews and plans for getting this modern user interface up to parity but it's been a long road. With repeated delays, there's at least one more delay: the Anaconda web UI was just shifted from Fedora 41 to Fedora 42...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real-Time Kernel Now Available On Ubuntu 24.04 LTS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.04-LTS-Real-Time</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.04-LTS-Real-Time"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T14:37:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Similar to the real-time kernel for Ubuntu 22.04 LTS, Canonical announced today the availability of their new real-time "RT" kernel for Ubuntu 24.04 LTS. But like with the existing Ubuntu RT kernels, this real-time support is limited to Ubuntu Pro subscriptions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Servo Web Engine Continues Advancing But Seeing Just $1.6k In Monthly Donations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Servo-Engine-May-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Servo-Engine-May-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T14:26:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Rust-written Servo web engine as a reminder was started as a Mozilla project but then abandoned and now developed by multiple organizations as part of Linux Foundation Europe. The Servo project has put out a new status update that highlights the work accomplished in recent weeks...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yocto 5.0 LTS Released - Now Powered By Linux 6.6 LTS, Boeing Joins The Project]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Yocto-5.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Yocto-5.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T14:09:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yocto 5.0 LTS has been released as the newest version from the Yocto Project that is popular for organizations assembling their own embedded/IoT-minded custom Linux distributions. The Linux Foundation also announced today that Boeing has become a Platinum Member with Yocto...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD & Intel Team Up For UALink As Open Alternative To NVIDIA's NVLink]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ultra-Accelerator-Link-UALink</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ultra-Accelerator-Link-UALink"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's rare for an advanced media briefing to involve representatives from both AMD and Intel, but that happened yesterday. AMD and Intel along with Broadcom have formed the Ultra Accelerator Link "UALink" as a new open standard they are hoping to use to take on NVIDIA's proprietary NVLink interface...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Battlemage Platform Support Begins Landing In Mesa 24.2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Battlemage-Goes-Mesa-24.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Battlemage-Goes-Mesa-24.2"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T10:33:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Intel Battlemage discrete graphics support is beginning to come together for the open-source Linux graphics driver stack as the successor to DG2/Alchemist. In addition to all the Xe2 work for what's found with Lunar Lake, more Battlemage Linux kernel and user-space driver work has been appearing recently. The milestone crossed today is the initial Battlemage "BMG" platform support being merged for the Mesa 24.2 OpenGL/Vulkan drivers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Improving NMI Source Reporting On Linux With FRED]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Linux-NMI-Source-Report</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Linux-NMI-Source-Report"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T10:24:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of Intel's Flexible Return Event Delivery (FRED), Intel open-source software engineers are now working on improving Non-Maskable Interrupt (NMI) source reporting for the Linux kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Enabling PowerVR Rogue GX6250 Open-Source Support With The MediaTek MT8173]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/PowerVR-GX6250-MT8173</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/PowerVR-GX6250-MT8173"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T10:14:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building off the PowerVR kernel driver merged in Linux 6.8 and PowerVR Vulkan driver in Mesa 24.0 that are both focused on Imagination's newer PowerVR Rogue architecture, Google engineers are working on enabling open-source driver support for the PowerVR Rogue GX6250 as found within the MediaTek MT8173 SoC...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDGpu v0.5 Vulkan Wrapper Released, KDXr Begins Wrapping OpenXR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDGpu-0.5-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDGpu-0.5-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T09:57:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year the KDAB consulting firm typically associated with Qt work published KDGpu as a thin Vulkan wrapper to make it easier leveraging this graphics API. Out today is KDGpu v0.5 with many improvements to this Vulkan wrapper...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VKD3D 1.12 Released With Support For Directly Outputting SPIR-V & D3D Shader Assembly]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/VKD3D-1.12-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/VKD3D-1.12-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T00:23:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While VKD3D-Proton that is bundled with Valve's Steam Play (Proton) is the most common source for mapping Direct3D 12 over the Vulkan API for Windows games on Linux, Wine's VKD3D upstream continues to be developed. Out today is VKD3D 1.12 as the newest feature release for this open-source D3D12-on-Vulkan implementation...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-29]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-29.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-29.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 29, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Mobifree – An open-source mobile ecosystem
(comments)


Show HN: Openkoda – Open–source, private, Salesforce alternative
(comments)


Llama 3-V: Matching GPT4-V with a 100x smaller model and 500 dollars
(comments)


Ex-OpenAI board member reveals what led to Sam Altman's brief ousting
(comments)


AI headphones let wearer listen to a single person in a crowd by looking at them
(comments)


Codestral: Mistral's Code Model
(comments)


I sold TinyPilot, my first successful business
(comments)


Ottawa wants the power to create secret backdoors in networks for surveillance
(comments)


Vector indexing all of Wikipedia on a laptop
(comments)


Kino: Pro Video Camera
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[XZ 5.6.2 Released With The Frightening Backdoor Removed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/XZ-5.6.2-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/XZ-5.6.2-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T20:14:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was two months ago today that an urgent security alert was issued over XZ being hit by malicious code that turned out to be a backdoor within liblzma added by a bad actor that worked his way into XZ co-maintainership. Longtime XZ developer Lasse Collin is back at the helm and has been auditing the prior XZ commits and today released XZ 5.6.2 with the backdoor completely removed...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Cloud Traffic Is Suffocating Fedora's Mirrors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AWS-Cloud-Breaks-Fedora-Mirrors</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AWS-Cloud-Breaks-Fedora-Mirrors"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T19:49:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A massive uptick in traffic to Fedora's package mirrors is causing problems for the Linux distribution. Some five million additional systems have started putting additional strain on Fedora's mirror resources since March and appear to be coming from Amazon's cloud...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Framework Announces Intel Core Ultra Powered Laptop With 2.8k Display]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Framework-Core-Ultra-Laptop</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Framework-Core-Ultra-Laptop"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T17:54:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Framework is out today with some exciting announcements from lowering the price of the existing Framework 13 with AMD Ryzen 7040 series SoC to announcing a new Framework Laptop 13 powered by Intel Core Ultra (Meteor Lake) and having a new 2.8K display option for this modular/upgradeable laptop shipping this summer...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Features Include TPM Bus Encryption, More AMD Zen 5 & A Prison Letter Merge Request]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/linux-610-features</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/linux-610-features"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now that the Linux 6.10 merge window has wrapped up, here's a look at all of the exciting features/changes coming to this summer 2024 kernel. Linux 6.10 brings a lot as usual for the latest/upcoming Intel and AMD platforms, never-ending work on file-systems, a new memory sealing "mseal" system call, TPM bus encryption, and dozens of other exciting changes and new hardware support.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arm Announces The Cortex-X925 & Cortex-A725]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Arm-Cortex-X925-Cortex-A725</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Arm-Cortex-X925-Cortex-A725"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T16:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arm today announced the latest products in the Armv9 CPU portfolio: the Cortex-X925 as their "ultimate performance" processor and the Cortex-A725 as their processor option for sustained performance...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[QuestDB 8.0 Brings Up To 50% Performance Improvement, ZFS Data Compression]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/QuestDB-8.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/QuestDB-8.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T14:39:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[QuestDB 8.0 is out today as the newest feature update to this open-source time-series database. QuestDB continues to cater to high throughput ingestion and fast SQL queries so it can handle use-cases from financial data to IoT sensors. With today's QuestDB 8.0 release, it's even faster...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Launches "Opt Green" Initiative For Sustainable Software & Hardware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Opt-Green</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Opt-Green"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T12:58:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[KDE's Eco group announced today "Opt Green" as a new initiative for sustainable software...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical Developing "Flamenco" For Enhancing .NET Developer Experience On Ubuntu]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Flamenco-dot-NET-Ubuntu</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Flamenco-dot-NET-Ubuntu"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T11:06:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the newest open-source projects in-development by Ubuntu maker Canonical is a new C# written program called Flamenco...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve's AMD Shader Compiler "ACO" Makes More Preparations For Radeon RDNA4]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-ACO-Changes-GFX12</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-ACO-Changes-GFX12"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:41:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The AMD shader compiler "ACO" alternative to the AMDGPU LLVM back-end has seen another batch of changes merged in preparations for next-generation Radeon RDNA4 GPUs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Makes One Line Tweak To GCC To Fix A "Random Performance Penalty"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-GCC-Loop-Alignment</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-GCC-Loop-Alignment"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coming up on my radar today is a commit made to the GNU Compiler Collection (GCC) for adjusting the loop alignment with Intel's generic tuning path. In turn this should address "some random performance penalty in benchmarks" with coping better around cache lines...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Sub-NUMA Clustering Support Linux Patches Spun A 19th Time]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-SNC-With-RDT-Linux-v19</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-SNC-With-RDT-Linux-v19"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:22:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The past year there's been a big Linux kernel patch series in the work by Intel to improve Sub-NUMA Clustering "SNC" support so it behaves well with Intel Resource Director Technology (RDT) on modern Intel hardware. Hopefully that work will soon be ready for mainlining in the Linux kernel while this week brought the 19th revision to those patches...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flowblade 2.16 Open-Source Video Editor Released]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Flowblade-2.16-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Flowblade-2.16-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:15:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flowblade 2.16 is out today as the newest version of this open-source non-linear video editor...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>