<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://joe8755.github.io/the-news-rss-reader/index.html</id>
    <title>the news rss reader</title>
    <updated>2024-06-15T12:32:12.006Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joe8755.github.io/the-news-rss-reader/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://joe8755.github.io/the-news-rss-reader/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME Papers Document Viewer Making Progress As GTK4-Based Evince Fork]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Papers-GTK4-Evince-Fork</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Papers-GTK4-Evince-Fork"/>
        <updated>2024-06-15T10:37:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME's longtime document viewer, Evince, was recently forked as GNOME Papers and saw its first release a few weeks back. This new GNOME document viewer has been ported from GTK3 to GTK4 and also brings an improved user interface and other refinements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple M4 Support Added To The LLVM Compiler, Confirming Its ISA Capabilities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Apple-M4-Added-To-LLVM-Clang</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Apple-M4-Added-To-LLVM-Clang"/>
        <updated>2024-06-15T10:06:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple compiler engineers have contributed Apple M4 CPU support to the upstream LLVM/Clang compiler via the new -mcpu=apple-m4 target. Interestingly the Apple M4 is exposed as an ARMv8.7 derived design...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 6.1 Prepares For Release Next Week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Next-Week</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Next-Week"/>
        <updated>2024-06-15T09:47:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 6.1 is preparing for release next week on 18 June. KDE developers this week have thus been very busy with last minute finishing touches to this updated desktop while also already beginning feature work on Plasma 6.2...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 9.11 Released With More Monitor DPI Awareness Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-9.11-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-9.11-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-15T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 9.11 is now available as the newest bi-weekly development release of this open-source software for enjoying Windows games and applications under Linux and other platforms. With Wine 9.11 we are now roughly at the half-way point before Wine's typical feature freeze and release candidate start that typically begins around early December and this cycle will lead up to the Wine 10.0 stable release in early 2025...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-14]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-14.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-14.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 14, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


My thoughts on Python in Excel
(comments)


Show HN: Shpool, a Lightweight Tmux Alternative
(comments)


AMD CEO Lisa Su reminisces about designing the PS3's infamous Cell processor
(comments)


Mouth-based touchpad enables people living with paralysis to use computers
(comments)


Fungus breaks down ocean plastic
(comments)


Land value tax in online games and virtual worlds (2022)
(comments)


I found a 55 year old bug in the first Lunar Lander game
(comments)


Start presentations on the second slide
(comments)


Nvidia Warp: A Python framework for high performance GPU simulation and graphics
(comments)


Microsoft's Recall AI feature is now indefinitely delayed
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Receives New Human Interface Guidelines For 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-New-HIG-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-New-HIG-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T21:16:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prominent KDE developer Nate Graham has been working with various KDE designers and developers to establish a new set of Human Interface Guidelines (HIG)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LibreOffice 24.8 Beta Now Available For Testing This Free Software Office Suite]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/LibreOffice-24.8-Beta-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/LibreOffice-24.8-Beta-1"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T21:12:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LibreOffice 24.8 is now available in beta form for those wanting to test this open-source, cross-platform office suite alternative to the likes of Microsoft Office...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.11 Bringing "Hardware Replay" Feature For Intel Graphics Debugging]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-Intel-HW-Hang-Replay</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-Intel-HW-Hang-Replay"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The main set of drm-intel-gt-next patches aiming for the Linux 6.11 kernel were submitted this week to DRM-Next. Most notable with this feature update for the next kernel version is enabling a new hardware replay feature for better reproducing GPU hangs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 24.10 Seeing More Desktop Installer Improvements, Improving The Steam Snap]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.10-Desktop-June</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.10-Desktop-June"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T13:04:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month some of the Ubuntu 24.10 desktop plans were laid out such as NVIDIA Wayland by default, a new welcome wizard, and more. Canonical's Oliver Smith has posted an update today around some of the ongoing Ubuntu 24.10 desktop enhancements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Vulkan Driver Halves The Time Required For Startup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Vulkan-Faster-vkCreateDev</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Vulkan-Faster-vkCreateDev"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T12:31:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's open-source Vulkan Linux driver "ANV" has reduced the driver start-up time by about half...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Two Year Journey Funded By Arm/Qualcomm For Improving ARM Linux Laptop Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Two-Years-Improving-ARM-Laptops</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Two-Years-Improving-ARM-Laptops"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T11:06:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kernel developer and consultant Johan Hovold spent the last two years working on improving ARM Linux laptop support with a particular focus on the Lenovo ThinkPad X13s powered Qualcomm SoC. Arm funded this Linaro effort and as a result the ThinkPad X13s enjoys pleasant upstream kernel support now. This Arm Linux laptop project has now concluded but sets a nice base for further ARM Linux laptop improvements moving forward...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel To Upstream Habana Labs Network Drivers Into The Linux Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/HabanaLabs-Network-Driver-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/HabanaLabs-Network-Driver-Linux"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:44:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While for years there has been the Habana Labs AI accelerator driver within the mainline Linux kernel, this "accel" driver has been focused on just supporting training/inference across their products. Now being worked on for the mainline Linux kernel are upstreaming the Habana Labs network drivers that can be used for scaling out the AI workloads across multiple systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 24.2 Adds Support For Fixed-Rate Compression Extensions For OpenGL & EGL]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.2-Fixed-Rate-Compress</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.2-Fixed-Rate-Compress"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:26:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Being merged to Mesa 24.2 this week is a set of 12 patches that have been four months in the making for supporting the OpenGL/EGL fixed-rate compression extensions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qt 6.8 Beta Released With Multi-View Rendering, Better GNOME Wayland Experience]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Qt-6.8-Beta-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Qt-6.8-Beta-1"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:08:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first beta release of the Qt 6.8 toolkit is now available for testing with many new features...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10-rc4 To Fix Display For The Ayaneo Kun Gaming Handheld]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Display-Ayaneo-Kun</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Display-Ayaneo-Kun"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T09:38:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those interested in running Linux on the Ayaneo Kun handheld gaming console alternative to Valve's Steam Deck and the ASUS ROG Ally, among others, a display quirk has been submitted ahead of the Linux 6.10-rc4 release this weekend to fix the display handling...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-13]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-13.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-13.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 13, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Banana giant Chiquita held liable by US court for funding paramilitaries
(comments)


Twenty, a modern CRM alternative to Salesforce
(comments)


Serious Sam handled massive amounts of enemies on 56k modem connections
(comments)


The GJK Algorithm: A weird and beautiful way to do a simple thing
(comments)


Japan enacts law to promote competition in smartphone app stores
(comments)


How Meta trains large language models at scale
(comments)


Uncensor any LLM with abliteration
(comments)


Microsoft Chose Profit over Security, Whistleblower Says
(comments)


Indian startup 3D prints rocket engine in 72 hours
(comments)


MLow: Meta's low bitrate audio codec
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA Exploring Ways To Better Support An Upstream Kernel Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/NVIDIA-Exploring-Upstream-KMD</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/NVIDIA-Exploring-Upstream-KMD"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T17:44:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's how an exciting message from a NVIDIA engineer that just hit the mailing list begins: "NVIDIA has been exploring ways to better support the effort for an upstream kernel mode driver for GPUs that are capable of running GSP-RM firmware, since the introduction to Nova."..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fwupd 1.9.21 Released With Synaptics Carrera & Wacom Movink Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fwupd-1.9.21-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fwupd-1.9.21-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T16:51:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fwupd 1.9.21 is now available for this open-source software for facilitating system firmware and device/peripheral firmware updates under Linux and other platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Rocket" Accelerator Open-Source Linux Kernel Driver Posted For Rockchip NPU]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Rocket-Rockchip-NPU-Driver</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Rocket-Rockchip-NPU-Driver"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T14:35:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The past few months open-source developer Tomeu Vizoso has been developing an open-source accelerator driver for Rockchip's NPU. The experimental driver has shown the open-source code can compete with Rockchip's proprietary driver and Vizoso has been working to develop an upstream-minded driver for a kernel driver living within the "accel" subsystem and then leveraging Mesa's Teflon for the user-space component. Yesterday the "Rocket" accel kernel driver was posted for the Rockchip NPU...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Testing Ground Toolkit: Making It Less Difficult To Compile The X Server In 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Xorg-Testing-Ground-Toolkit</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Xorg-Testing-Ground-Toolkit"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T13:51:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the upstream X.Org Server development remains slow with most of the large vendors treating it in maintenance mode and not investing in new features, open-source developer Enrico Weigelt has been one of the few still working to improve the X.Org Server. As part of his work besides pushing new patches and testing of the latest X.Org Server Git state, today he announced the release of the X.Org Testing Ground Toolkit v0.0.1 as a means to help in facilitate testing of the latest X.Org Server Git by making it easier to build it...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu Talks Up A RISC-V Octa-Core Laptop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/DC-ROMA-RISC-V-Laptop-II</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/DC-ROMA-RISC-V-Laptop-II"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T11:02:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu maker Canonical put out a news release today around the DC-ROMA RISC-V Laptop II that is an octa-core RISC-V laptop shipping soon with Ubuntu Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coreboot To Be Shown Today With An Intel Meteor Lake Laptop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Coreboot-Dasharo-Meteor-Lake</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Coreboot-Dasharo-Meteor-Lake"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:46:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Going back to 2022 we've seen work by Intel engineers on adding Meteor Lake SoC support to Coreboot while to date there hasn't been much in the way of actual Intel Core Ultra "Meteor Lake" laptops with Coreboot as a replacement to the proprietary BIOS/firmware. But to be shown later today is one of the first laptop designs using these latest Intel mobile processors and running the Dasharo downstream of Coreboot...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Framework Laptop 16 CAD Design Files Open-Sourced]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Framework-16-CAD-Files</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Framework-16-CAD-Files"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:27:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In making the Framework 16 laptop even more appearing to open-source hardware enthusiasts and makers, Framework Computer has published the CAD design files as open-source...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft's Azure Linux 2.0 Update Ships Dozens Of Security Patches, Adds Azl-Compliance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Azure-Linux-2.0.20240609</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Azure-Linux-2.0.20240609"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:02:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft's in-house Linux distribution, Azure Linux (nee CBL-Mariner), is out with a new update. In the first new stable release for Azure Linux 2.0 since late April, the Azure Linux 2.0.20240609 update ships with dozens of security fixes to address a wide range of CVEs as well as bringing various bug fixes and other updates...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FEX 2406 Brings JIT Optimizations For Running x86_64 Binaries On AArch64]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/FEX-2406-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/FEX-2406-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T09:44:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FEX is one of the open-source projects working on user-mode x86/x86_64 binary emulation atop ARM64/AArch64 Linux. FEX 2406 is out today as the project's newest monthly feature release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-12]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-12.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-12.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 12, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Home-Cooked Software and Barefoot Developers
(comments)


When Water Flows Uphill [video]
(comments)


Show HN: Unforget, the note-taking app I always wanted: offline first, encrypted
(comments)


Self-Serve Dashboards
(comments)


Show HN: Revideo – Create Videos with Code
(comments)


ARC Prize – a $1M+ competition towards open AGI progress
(comments)


Flameshot – Open-source screenshot software
(comments)


Swift Static Linux SDK
(comments)


Silicon Valley's best kept secret: Founder liquidity
(comments)


Elixir 1.17 released: set-theoretic types in patterns, durations, OTP 27
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD Community Survey Confirms ZFS Is Their Most Valued Server Feature]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeBSD-Community-Survey-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeBSD-Community-Survey-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T21:11:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The FreeBSD Foundation has published the results of the FreeBSD Community Survey that reveal interesting insights about FreeBSD usage and its users...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve Rolls Out Proton 9.0-2 With Many Fixes For Running More Games On Steam Play]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Valve-Proton-9.0-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Valve-Proton-9.0-2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T19:24:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proton 9.0-2 is out this afternoon as the Valve/CodeWeavers downstream of Wine that powers Steam Play for running Windows games under Linux within the Steam client...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safety-Critical Rust Consortium Announced]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Safety-Critical-Rust-Consortium</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Safety-Critical-Rust-Consortium"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T16:34:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In aiming to make the Rust programming language more suitable for safety-critical software like within automobiles, aviation, and other industries, the Safety-Critical Rust Consortium was announced today...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD 14.1 vs. FreeBSD 14.0 Benchmarks On AMD Ryzen Threadripper]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/freebsd-141-benchmarks</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/freebsd-141-benchmarks"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T14:36:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Debuting last week was FreeBSD 14.1 with performance improvements and more. Given there being some performance optimizations and other upgrades like a more recent LLVM Clang compiler by default, I've begun running some benchmarks of this newest FreeBSD stable release. In today's article is a quick comparison of FreeBSD 14.1 vs. FreeBSD 14.0 performance using an AMD Ryzen Threadripper 7980X 64-core processor within the System76 Thelio Major workstation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Fast CPPC To Be Merged For Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Fast-CPPC-For-Linux-6.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Fast-CPPC-For-Linux-6.11"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T13:50:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The AMD Fast CPPC feature enablement for the "amd_pstate" driver has been submitted to the power management subsystem ahead of next month's Linux 6.11 merge window...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[openSUSE Leap 15.6 Release - Adds Cockpit, Linux 6.4 & Other Updates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/openSUSE-Leap-15.6-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/openSUSE-Leap-15.6-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T13:21:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSUSE Leap 15.6 is now officially available for this community Linux distribution release aligned with SUSE Linux Enterprise 15 Service Pack 6. With Leap 15.6 comes the inclusion of the Cockpit web administration software and many software updates...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Low Power Mode Daemon v0.0.4 Released To Optimize Hybrid CPUs On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-LPMD-Low-Power-0.0.4</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-LPMD-Low-Power-0.0.4"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:54:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Low Power Mode Daemon v0.0.4 has been released with "LPMD" being the open-source daemon for optimize active idle power for modern Core hybrid CPUs under Linux that sport a combination of the E and P cores...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LLVM Clang 19 Lands Support For C23's #embed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/LLVM-Clang-19-C23-Embed</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/LLVM-Clang-19-C23-Embed"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:27:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged today to LLVM Clang 19 Git is support for the #embed resource inclusion mechanism that is an approved C23 feature. This also makes Clang the first for supporting this pre-processor embed feature...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marek Lands 40 Patch Series To Further Enhance The Open-Source AMD Graphics Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Marek-Universal-Optimized-Comp</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Marek-Universal-Optimized-Comp"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:14:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well known open-source AMD OpenGL/Gallium3D driver developer Marek Olšák has landed a big patch series into Mesa 24.2 for a universal optimized compute image clear/blit shader and MSAA-resolving pixel shader...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's oneDNN 3.5 Begins Optimizing For Xe2, More Xeon 6 Tuning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-oneDNN-3.5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-oneDNN-3.5"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's oneDNN 3.5 has been released as this Deep Neural Network Library for the oneAPI specification and now part of the UXL Foundation. With oneDNN 3.5 comes more performance optimizations for existing and upcoming Intel hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds Throws Down The Hammer: Extensible Scheduler "sched_ext" In Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-Extensible-Scheduler</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-Extensible-Scheduler"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T00:40:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The extensible scheduler "sched_ext" code has proven quite versatile for opening up better Linux gaming performance, more quickly prototyping new scheduler changes, Ubuntu/Canonical has been evaluating it for pursuing a more micro-kernel like design, and many other interesting approaches with it. Yet it's remained out of tree but that is now changing with the upcoming Linux 6.11 cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-11.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-11.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 11, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


I built an ROV to solve missing person cases
(comments)


Apple unveils 'Passwords' manager app at WWDC 2024
(comments)


macOS Sequoia Preview
(comments)


Deterioration of local community a major driver of loss of play-based childhood
(comments)


Apple's On-Device and Server Foundation Models
(comments)


Private Cloud Compute: A new frontier for AI privacy in the cloud
(comments)


Noam Chomsky 'no longer able to talk' after 'medical event'
(comments)


POV-Ray – The Persistence of Vision Raytracer (2021)
(comments)


I like the RP2040
(comments)


Lynn Conway has died
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[systemd 256 Released With run0, systemd-vpick, importctl & Other New Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/systemd-256</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/systemd-256"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T23:20:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Systemd 256 is out today as the latest major feature update to this integral component to modern Linux distributions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SUSE Working To Upstream RP1 Southbridge Linux Driver For The Raspberry Pi 5]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-5-RP1-Linux-RFC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-5-RP1-Linux-RFC"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T20:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Raspberry Pi 5 features the "RP1" as the in-house silicon design for the southbridge to this single board computer. The RP1 driver maintained by Raspberry Pi is just found in their downstream kernel while a SUSE engineer is working to rework that driver so that it can be eventually mainlined in the upstream Linux kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Glibc Non-Temporal Stores Memset Optimization Extended To AMD CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Glibc-Non-Temp-Stores-AMD</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Glibc-Non-Temp-Stores-AMD"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T14:57:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged last month to the GNU C Library (glibc) Git code was a new tunable for non-temporal stores for memset. This optimization for glibc's memset performance was limited to Intel processors given at the time it was only tested/benchmarked on Intel CPUs but now it's proven to be useful too for AMD processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AlmaLinux Now Available For The Raspberry Pi 5]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AlmaLinux-Raspberry-Pi-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AlmaLinux-Raspberry-Pi-5"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T14:12:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coincidentally coming out on the day of Raspberry Pi's IPO is AlmaLinux providing official support for the Raspberry Pi 5...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat Developing "eu-stacktrace" For Profiling Without Frame Pointers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Red-Hat-eu-stacktrace</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Red-Hat-eu-stacktrace"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T13:45:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While last year we saw Fedora to no longer omit the frame pointer to help in debugging/profiling Fedora packages and Ubuntu 24.04 LTS also enabled frame pointers for better debugging/profiling, among other distributions, there is the known performance implications of no longer omitting the frame pointer. But now in aiming to make the best of both worlds, it turns out Red Hat has been developing eu-stracktrace as a new means of profiling without relying on frame pointers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD P-State Linux Patches Updated For Heterogeneous CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-P-State-Hetero-v3</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-P-State-Hetero-v3"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T10:44:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month AMD Linux engineers posted ap atch series for better handling heterogeneous core type CPUs. This is for enhancing the P-State CPU frequency scaling on CPUs featuring a mix of conventional cores and efficiency cores, e.g. Zen 4 and Zen 4C. A third iteration of these patches were posted today...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Open-Sources GWPSan As A New Sanitizer Framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Google-GWPSan</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Google-GWPSan"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T10:25:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google is known for their many contributions to open-source compilers and particular many different sanitizer efforts over the years. Their newest project they have made open-source in this area is GWPSan as a sampling-based sanitizer framework...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Serves Up A Tasty IPO On The London Stock Exchange]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-IPO</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-IPO"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T10:04:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi carried out a successful IPO today on the London Stock Exchange...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[oneAPI-Focused UXL Foundation Now Collaborating With The Khronos Group]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/UXL-Foundation-Khronos-Collab</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/UXL-Foundation-Khronos-Collab"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T00:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year it was announced that Intel's oneAPI software initiative evolved into the UXL Foundation for making compute accelerators more open as well as opening things up to more cross-vendor collaboration and adoption. Intel started the Unified Acceleration Foundation with the Linux Foundation, Google, Arm, Qualcomm, Samsung, and others. Announced today is that the UXL Foundation has begun collaborating with The Khronos Group...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-10.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-10.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 10, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


An Introduction to ARM64 Assembly on Apple Silicon Macs
(comments)


Ultrasonic investigations in shopping centres
(comments)


A Revolution in Biology?
(comments)


Designing a Lego orrery
(comments)


Libtree: Ldd as a tree saying why a library is found or not
(comments)


A ChatGPT mistake cost us $10k
(comments)


Show HN: Markdown HN profiles at {user}.at.hn
(comments)


Apple blocks PC emulator in iOS App Store and third-party app stores
(comments)


Apple Intelligence for iPhone, iPad, and Mac
(comments)


OpenAI and Apple Announce Partnership
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One-Line Patch For Intel Meteor Lake Yields Up To 72% Better Performance, +7% Geo Mean]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-meteorlake-epp-perf</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-meteorlake-epp-perf"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covered last week on Phoronix was a new patch from Intel that with tuning to the P-State CPU frequency scaling driver was showing big wins for Intel Core Ultra "Meteor Lake" performance and power efficiency. I was curious with the Intel claims posted for a couple benchmarks and thus over the weekend set out to run many Intel Meteor Lake benchmarks on this one-line kernel patch... The results are great for boosting the Linux performance of Intel Core ultra laptops with as much as 72% better performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TUXEDO Developing A Snapdragon X Elite Linux Laptop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/TUXEDO-Snapdragon-X-Elite</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/TUXEDO-Snapdragon-X-Elite"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T14:23:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bavarian Linux PC vendor TUXEDO Computers is working on bringing a Snapdragon X Elite powered laptop to market...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 127 With 32-bit x86 Linux Pretending To Be "x86_64" To Reduce Fingerprinting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mozilla-Firefox-127</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mozilla-Firefox-127"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T14:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mozilla Firefox 127.0 binaries are available for download today ahead of tomorrow's official announcement. Firefox 127 brings a few nice changes for this month's feature update...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Posts New Linux Patches For Per-Core CPU Energy Counters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Linux-PMU-Power-Per-Core</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Linux-PMU-Power-Per-Core"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T10:48:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After an attempt in early 2023 didn't pan out, today an AMD Linux engineer posted a new kernel patch series for enabling per-core RAPL energy counter support for AMD processors. With this patch series when using Linux's venerable perf utility it's now possible for reading the power use on a per CPU core basis using a new "power_per_core" PMU...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Quest For Faster getrandom() Performance Continues Two Years Later]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Random-vDSO-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Random-vDSO-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T10:15:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Going back just under two years was the propsal for adding getrandom() to the vDSO in the quest to achieve faster performance for obtaining random numbers in user-space. That effort while seemingly simple remains an ongoing and contentious matter...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Lot More AMD RDNA4/GFX12 Graphics Driver Code Has Landed In Mesa 24.2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Busy-RDNA4-Mesa-24.2-Week</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Busy-RDNA4-Mesa-24.2-Week"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T09:57:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of AMD GFX12 IP enablement landed in Mesa 24.2-devel over the past week for bringing up the RadeonSI Gallium3D driver and RADV Vulkan driver for the upcoming RDNA4 graphics...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-09]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-09.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-09.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 09, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


LSP-AI: open-source language server serving as back end for AI code assistance
(comments)


Detecting a PS2 Emulator: When 1*X does not equal X
(comments)


My favorite 1980's Canadian TV show: Bits and Bytes
(comments)


Gene therapy restores hearing to children with inherited deafness
(comments)


Draw an iceberg and see how it will float
(comments)


Viagra improves brain blood flow and could help to prevent dementia
(comments)


Piku: Allows git push deployments to your own servers
(comments)


Economic Termites: Monopolies not noticeable enough for most of us
(comments)


The Weird Nerd comes with trade-offs
(comments)


Keylogger discovered in image generator extension
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10-rc3 Released For A Boring But Good Week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc3-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc3-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-09T21:37:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds just announced the release of Linux 6.10-rc3 as a rather pleasant week for this stage of the kernel cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arch Linux Powered CachyOS Now Defaults To Btrfs Rather Than XFS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/CachyOS-Btrfs-Default</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/CachyOS-Btrfs-Default"/>
        <updated>2024-06-09T16:25:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arch Linux derivative CachyOS that is optimized for a nice desktop experience and shipping a nice set of performance optimizations/tuning by default is out with its June 2024 refresh...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD's Linux Kernel Compute Driver For ROCm Begins Preparing For RDNA4 GPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDKFD-GFX12-Support</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDKFD-GFX12-Support"/>
        <updated>2024-06-09T10:52:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to debuting their "Peano" LLVM compiler back-end for Ryzen AI NPUs on Friday, AMD also submitted a new batch of feature code for their AMDGPU kernel graphics driver and AMDKFD kernel compute driver of new feature code aiming for the upcoming Linux 6.11 merge window...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel In-Tree Linux Network Drivers Being Adapted To Support Firmware Updates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-IGB-IXGBE-Firmware-Update</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-IGB-IXGBE-Firmware-Update"/>
        <updated>2024-06-09T10:36:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's IGB and IXGBE network drivers within the mainline Linux kernel are being adapted to support firmware updates for the underlying driver. To date such functionality was limited to Intel's out-of-tree versions of these drivers for their higher-end network hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mold 2.32 Released With Increased LLVM LLD Compatibility, Faster Identical Code Folding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mold-2.32-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mold-2.32-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-09T10:07:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mold 2.32 is out as the newest feature release for this high speed code linker that rivals LLVM LLD and GNU Gold...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-08]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-08.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-08.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 08, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Own a weather station? We want your data
(comments)


Tom 7: Badness 0 (Three ways)
(comments)


σ-GPTs: A new approach to autoregressive models
(comments)


Ask HN: Machine learning engineers, what do you do at work?
(comments)


Feynman’s Razor
(comments)


Xv6, a simple Unix-like teaching operating system
(comments)


What Is PID 0?
(comments)


Apollo 8 astronaut William Anders ID'd in WA plane crash
(comments)


South Pole Water Infrastructure
(comments)


The Backrooms of the Internet Archive
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD's Newest Open-Source Surprise: "Peano" - An LLVM Compiler For Ryzen AI NPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Peano-LLVM-Ryzen-AI</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Peano-LLVM-Ryzen-AI"/>
        <updated>2024-06-08T11:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There was a very exciting Friday evening code drop out of AMD... They announced a new project called Peano that serves as an open-source LLVM compiler back-end for AMD/Xilinx AI engine processors with a particular focus on the Ryzen AI SOCs with existing Phoenix and Hawk Point hardware as well as the upcoming XDNA2 found with the forthcoming Ryzen AI 300 series...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME OS Continues Seeing New Features, New GNOME App for Viewing 3D Models]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-CAD-Exhibit-OS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-CAD-Exhibit-OS"/>
        <updated>2024-06-08T10:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME developers continue to be quite busy this summer from enhancing their desktop with more security and accessibility features to further crafting GNOME OS...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redox OS With COSMIC Apps Is Looking Quite Nice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Redox-OS-COSMIC-Look</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Redox-OS-COSMIC-Look"/>
        <updated>2024-06-08T10:26:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jeremy Soller who is an engineer at System76 and manages a side hustle of leading development on the open-source, Rust-written Redox OS has shared the latest look at this open-source operating system with the System76 COSMIC desktop applications...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OBS Studio 30.2 Beta Brings Native NVENC Encoder Support On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/OBS-Studio-30.2-Beta-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/OBS-Studio-30.2-Beta-1"/>
        <updated>2024-06-08T10:17:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Out for testing this weekend is the OBS Studio 30.2 beta software for those into live-streaming their desktop and other screen recording purposes. With the OBS Studio 30.2 release there are video encode improvements for Linux, support for multi-track video streaming, hybrid MP4 output, and other new features...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 6.1 Is Looking To Be A "Good One"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Good-One</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Good-One"/>
        <updated>2024-06-08T10:07:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The KDE Plasma 6.1 desktop is due for release in a little more than one week. Prominent KDE developer Nate Graham thinks this is going to be a "good one" with a lot of new features, better performance, and more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-07]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-07.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-07.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 07, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Show HN: 2d web paddle game
(comments)


The right not to be subjected to AI profiling based on publicly available data
(comments)


lsix: Like \"ls\", but for images
(comments)


Extracting concepts from GPT-4
(comments)


Ice – open source menu bar manager for macOS
(comments)


Cancel Adobe if you are a creative under NDA with your clients
(comments)


How Does GPT-4o Encode Images?
(comments)


Microsoft will switch off Recall by default after security backlash
(comments)


OpenSSH introduces options to penalize undesirable behavior
(comments)


ASCII Silhouettify
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Begins Upstreaming Fuchsia OS Support Into Mesa 3D]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fuchsia-OS-Simple-Mesa-Support</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fuchsia-OS-Simple-Mesa-Support"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T20:45:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With not hearing much about Fuchsia OS in a while and the Fuchsia OS team being hit hard by layoffs last year, coming as a surprise today is seeing Google beginning to upstream Fuchsia OS support into the Mesa 3D graphics driver stack...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.11 To Merge Support For Running AMD SEV-SNP KVM Guests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-611-AMD-SEV-SNP-KVM-Guest</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-611-AMD-SEV-SNP-KVM-Guest"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T17:35:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The patches have been years in the making around AMD SEV-SNP encrypted virtualization and various elements have been upstreamed in prior kernel versions while for the upcoming Linux 6.11 cycle are finally the Kernel-based Virtual Machine (KVM) bits for launching SEV-SNP protected guest virtual machines...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big Speed Boost For AES-GCM Performance On Intel & AMD CPUs Queued Ahead Of Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AES-GCM-Intel-AMD-Linux-6.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AES-GCM-Intel-AMD-Linux-6.11"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T16:39:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The patches recently covered on Phoronix for up to 162% faster AES-GCM encryption/decryption with modern Intel and AMD processors is now queued for introduction in the upcoming Linux 6.11 cycle!..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Lands Support For Vendor Flavored SPIR-V Within LLVM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/LLVM-AMDGCN-Flavored-SPIR-V</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/LLVM-AMDGCN-Flavored-SPIR-V"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T14:12:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SPIR-V used by the likes of OpenGL, OpenCL, and Vulkan is a common intermediate representation (IR) / intermediate language for consumption by device drivers. With code now merged into LLVM, AMD has introduced the notion of vendor "flavored" SPIR-V for containing extra information pertinent to the GPU device/driver being targeted...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Xe Driver Preps For SR-IOV Support & More Lunar Lake With Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-DRM-Intel-Xe-Next</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-DRM-Intel-Xe-Next"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T10:56:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Thursday the first set of Intel Xe driver feature updates were submitted to DRM-Next of material intended for merging with the Linux 6.11 kernel in July...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python 3.13 Beta 2 Released For Testing The Experimental JIT & Other New Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Python-3.13-Beta-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Python-3.13-Beta-2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T10:49:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The second beta is now available for testing of the upcoming Python 3.13 release that is bringing an experimental JIT, a new interactive interpreter, and other big features for this annual Python feature release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved Linux Driver Support Coming For LG Gram 2024 Laptop Models]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/LG-Gram-2024-Laptops-LInux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/LG-Gram-2024-Laptops-LInux"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T10:37:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged to the Linux kernel back in 2018 was an LG Gram laptop driver for supporting various hotkeys and extra functionality of these LG laptops. That driver is now being extended to support the latest LG Gram laptop models...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Most Popular Linux Hardware Reviews & Featured Articles Over 20 Years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Hardware-Reviews-20</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Hardware-Reviews-20"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T10:21:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With this week marking the 20th birthday of Phoronix, as part of the commemorative articles this week has been looking at the most popular Linux/open-source news over 20 years. In the piece today is looking back at the most popular Linux hardware reviews and other featured articles on Phoronix since 2004...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-06]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-06.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-06.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 06, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Mathematical Optimization for Cargo Ships
(comments)


Show HN: Foosbar – My autonomous foosball-playing robot
(comments)


Researchers to retract landmark Alzheimer's paper containing doctored images
(comments)


Most life on Earth is dormant, after pulling an 'emergency brake'
(comments)


Microsoft AI spying scandal: time to rethink privacy standards
(comments)


Saint Michael Sword: Are the cathedrals really on a straight line?
(comments)


I learned Vulkan and wrote a small game engine with it
(comments)


AeroSpace is an i3-like tiling window manager for macOS
(comments)


Super Heavy has splashed down in The Gulf of Mexico
(comments)


Roman Roads (2017)
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated Intel Meteor Lake Tuning For Linux Shows Huge Performance/Power Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-MTL-EPP-Tuning-64</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-MTL-EPP-Tuning-64"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T20:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's like magic with one line of code changed in the Linux kernel that Intel is reporting up to 19% performance improvement for Intel Core Ultra "Meteor Lake" and up to an 11% improvement in performance per Watt. Or in another EPP mode, the power consumption during video playback can be reduced by 52%!..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New AMD RDNA 3.5 GPU Target "GFX1152" Appears In Open-Source Linux Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-GFX1152-Appears</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-GFX1152-Appears"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T17:02:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When it comes to the RDNA 3.5 / RDNA 3+ integrated graphics found with upcoming AMD products, the graphics driver IP has been referred to as "GFX1150" and "GFX1151" of the AMD GFX 11.5 graphics IP. But now appearing today within the AMDGPU LLVM shader compiler is a new GFX1152 variant...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD EPYC 4364P & 4564P @ DDR5-4800 / DDR5-5200 vs. Intel Xeon E-2488]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/amd-epyc-4004-ddr5-xeon</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/amd-epyc-4004-ddr5-xeon"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T16:15:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the AMD EPYC 4004 series that was announced in May and we have delivered benchmarks of the entire EPYC 4004 stack from the 4-core SKU up through the 16-core model with 3D V-Cache, there are many advantages over Intel's Xeon E-2400 series competition. In addition to going up to 16 cores versus 8 with the Xeon E-2400 series, the more competitive pricing, the 3D V-Cache SKUs, and 28 PCIe lanes rather than 20, the AMD EPYC 4004 models also support DDR5-5200 memory where as the Intel Raptor Lake E-2400 models are bound to DDR5-4800. In this follow-up testing is a look at the AMD EPYC 4004 performance both at DDR5-4800 and DDR5-5200 speeds for showing the performance difference.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shopping For A Launch-Day AMD Ryzen AI 300 Series Laptop For Linux Testing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ryzen-AI-300-Laptop-Shopping</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ryzen-AI-300-Laptop-Shopping"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T14:40:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With this week's Computex announcement by AMD of the Ryzen AI 300 series laptop processors built atop Zen 5, one of the pleasant aspects has been several laptop models being announced already to be powered by either the Ryzen AI 9 365 or Ryzen AI 9 HX 370 flagship models. Some models are also already available for pre-order ahead of launch day. This is quite nice compared to in the past there was often at times quite a delay between the initial AMD Ryzen mobile announcements and being able to (pre)order any hardware. And thus I've already been looking around to coordinate near launch day Linux testing of the new AMD Zen 5 powered Ryzen AI 300 series hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Releases Azure Linux 3.0 Preview]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Microsoft-Azure-Linux-3.0-Pre</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Microsoft-Azure-Linux-3.0-Pre"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft has published its first tagged preview of the upcoming Azure Linux 3.0 operating system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated AMD GPU Firmware Makes Valve's Steam Deck More Robust Against Buggy Apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-More-Robust-Steam-Deck</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-More-Robust-Steam-Deck"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD has published a new set of AMDGPU firmware binaries for Linux users. In particular, this should benefit AMD APUs the most and these firmware improvements were focused on Valve's Steam Deck to make the device more robust against buggy applications...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Fixes AMD Zen 5 CPU Frequency Reporting With cpupower]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-cpupower-Zen-5-Freq</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-cpupower-Zen-5-Freq"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:39:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week's pull request of power management fixes for the Linux 6.10 kernel has an important change for the in-tree cpupower utility to fix P-State frequency reporting on upcoming Zen 5 (Family 1Ah) processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Most Popular Linux News Over The Past 20 Years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/20-Year-Popular-News</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/20-Year-Popular-News"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:20:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With yesterday marking the 20th birthday of Phoronix, I was curious what the most popular news articles were over these past two decades. There's a lot of compiler fodder, news from the early days of AMD Ryzen, Linus Torvalds commentary, and more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sovereign Tech Fund Providing €300k For GNU libmicrohttpd]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/STF-GNU-libmicrohttpd</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/STF-GNU-libmicrohttpd"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:13:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest funding for open-source from Germany's Sovereign Tech Fund is providing €300,000 over the course of the next year for improving GNU libmicrohttpd for building high performance HTTP web servers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Libinput 1.26 Rolls Out New Features, gsetwacom Introduced To Replace xsetwacom]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/libinput-1.26-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/libinput-1.26-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:01:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat's Peter Hutterer is out with two important updates to the Linux input stack: libinput 1.26 has released for this input handling library used both by X.Org and Wayland systems and then secondly he has announced the "gsetwacom" CLI program as a replacement to the "xsetwacom" program...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 24.1.1 Released With Many Graphics Driver Bug Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.1.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.1.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T00:22:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those typically waiting until the first point release of a new Mesa3D driver series before upgrading, today it's your chance to upgrade! Mesa 24.1.1 is now available with the first round of Mesa 24.1 fixes to the prominent OpenGL and Vulkan drivers. Coincidentally the bi-weekly release times nicely for the Phoronix 20th birthday today as a nice present with our love for the open-source Linux graphics stack...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-05]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-05.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-05.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 05, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Sphere Rendering: Flat Planets
(comments)


Some notes on influenceering
(comments)


An animated introduction to Fourier series
(comments)


You'll regret using natural keys
(comments)


Israel reportedly used fake social accounts to garner support from US lawmakers
(comments)


Simple tasks showing reasoning breakdown in state-of-the-art LLMs
(comments)


Boeing Starliner launches first crewed mission
(comments)


Vulkan1.3 on the M1 in one month
(comments)


Managing my motivation as a solo dev
(comments)


Employees who stay in companies longer than two years get paid 50% less (2014)
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blender 4.2 LTS Beta Brings Open Image Denoise On AMD GPUs, GPU Compositing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Blender-4.2-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Blender-4.2-Beta"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T18:24:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The beta process has begun for the Blender 4.2 open-source 3D modeling software. Making Blender 4.2 all the more significant is that it's a Long Term Support (LTS) release for this widely-used program by 3D artists across platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Honeykrisp" Is A New Vulkan Driver For Apple M1 On Linux - Derived From The NVK Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Honeykrisp-Apple-Vulkan-Driver</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Honeykrisp-Apple-Vulkan-Driver"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T16:09:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the Asahi AGX Gallium3D driver for OpenGL support with Apple Silicon on Linux has been maturing nicely and is quite capable these days, the Vulkan support hasn't been coming together as quick or for as long. But a new Apple Silicon Vulkan driver was recently started by Asahi Linux / Mesa developers and is looking positive for being able to become a compliant Vulkan 1.3 driver for the Apple M1 on Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Xeon 6766E/6780E Sierra Forest vs. Ampere Altra Performance & Power Efficiency]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6700e-ampere-altra</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6700e-ampere-altra"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T15:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the launch day review of the Intel Xeon 6766E and Xeon 6780E "Sierra Forest" processors the focus was on looking at the performance and power efficiency compared to prior Intel Xeon generations as well as the AMD EPYC competition. For those wondering how Intel's new Xeon 6 Sierra Forest processors compete against Amere Computing's "cloud native" Altra Max processors, here are those benchmarks looking at the performance and power efficiency.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA 555.52.04 Beta Linux Driver Brings Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/NVIDIA-555.52.04-Linux-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/NVIDIA-555.52.04-Linux-Beta"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T13:51:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few weeks ago NVIDIA introduced their much anticipated R555 beta driver with NVIDIA 555.42.02 for Linux bringing Wayland explicit sync support, the GPU System Processor (GSP) firmware being used by default, and a variety of Wayland improvements. Today the NVIDIA 555.52.04 beta driver is out that offers additional fixes for the R555 series...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Is Soliciting Ideas For Their Goals To Pursue Over The Next 2~3 Years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Goals-2024-Request</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Goals-2024-Request"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T13:25:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in 2022 the KDE project laid out new goals to improve accessibility, develop more environmentally sustainable software, and automate more processes for easing the development of KDE. These overarching KDE Goals are refined every 2~3 years and they are now soliciting ideas from the community for what they should focus on ahead...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.11 Device Mapper Will Optimize Flushing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-DM-Optimize-Flushing</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.11-DM-Optimize-Flushing"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T10:32:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest performance optimization work for the Linux kernel's Device Mapper (DM) comes thanks to Red Hat's Mikulas Patocka...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel NPU Library v1.2 Adds Int4 Support & Performance Optimizations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-NPU-Library-v1.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-NPU-Library-v1.2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T10:20:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel released a new version of its NPU Acceleration Library, the user-space Python library for leveraging the Neural Processing Unit (NPU) found within their Core Ultra "Meteor Lake" laptops and upcoming Lunar Lake and Arrow Lake hardware as well...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMDVLK 2024.Q2.2 Driver Brings Bug Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDVLK-2024.Q2.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDVLK-2024.Q2.2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T10:02:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building off last month's AMDVLK 2024.Q2.1 driver adding Phoenix 2 support, AMD today released AMDVLK 2024.Q2.2 as the newest update to their official open-source Vulkan Linux driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Today Marks 20 Years Since Starting Phoronix For Linux Hardware Reviews & News]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Phoronix-20th-Birthday</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Phoronix-20th-Birthday"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well, it's been a wild ride to say the least... Today marks twenty years since I started Phoronix.com devoted to reviewing Linux hardware and ultimately enriching the Linux hardware experience with more benchmarks, open-source/Linux hardware news, and more over the years...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD ROCm 6.1.2 Released With Fixes & Optimizations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-ROCm-6.1.2-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-ROCm-6.1.2-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T00:17:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ROCm 6.1.2 is out today as the newest update to AMD's open-source GPU compute stack for Linux systems and with growing support for Windows Subsystem for Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-04]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-04.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-04.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 04, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Hacking millions of modems and investigating who hacked my modem
(comments)


Show HN: 10 Years to Build a Free SQL Editor
(comments)


Show HN: I made a tiny camera with super long battery life
(comments)


If English was written like Chinese (1999)
(comments)


Diffusion on syntax trees for program synthesis
(comments)


Hacking millions of modems and investigating who hacked my modem
(comments)


I am sick of LeetCode-style interviews
(comments)


A breakthrough towards the Riemann hypothesis
(comments)


Why do electronic components have such odd values? (2021)
(comments)


Things the guys who stole my phone have texted me to try to get me to unlock it
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dell "PC Extras" Driver Slated For Linux 6.11 - Initially To Control Fan Modes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Dell-PC-Driver-For-Linux-6.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Dell-PC-Driver-For-Linux-6.11"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Queued into the x86 platform drivers' "for-next" branch ahead of the Linux 6.11 kernel cycle is the "Dell PC Extras" driver. Initially this new dell-pc driver is used for controlling fan modes via the Platform Profile setting on capable systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Open-Source Vulkan Driver Wires Up Mesh Shader Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-ANV-Mesh-Shader-Queries</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-ANV-Mesh-Shader-Queries"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T18:22:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building atop the Intel "ANV" Vulkan driver's mesh shader support that's been enabled by default since last year, the newest Mesa 24.2-devel code as of today now adds support for mesh shader queries...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora Moves Ahead In Replacing Redis With Valkey]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-Replacing-Redis-Valkey</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-Replacing-Redis-Valkey"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in April I noted that Fedora was considering replacing Redis with Valkey given the upstream Redis software licensing changes. At yesterday's Fedora Engineering and Steering Committee (FESCo) they have now signed off on replacing Redis with Valkey...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IBM Ready With POWER11 Support "-mcpu=power11" For GCC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/IBM-GCC-mcpu-power11-Ready</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/IBM-GCC-mcpu-power11-Ready"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T14:45:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IBM compiler engineers are ready to flip-on their POWER11 support within the GNU Compiler Collection (GCC) in wiring up the "-mcpu=power11" option...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated Printk Rework Patches - Necessary Step For Mainlining Linux Real-Time "RT"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Printk-Rework-v2-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Printk-Rework-v2-Linux"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T10:43:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[John Ogness of Linutronix today sent out the second iteration of his patches working on threaded printing support for printk() and related rework of that code that is a necessary step before the real-time (RT) kernel patches can be finally mainlined...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi AI Kit Launches For $70 For 13 TOPS AI Inference]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-AI-Kit</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Raspberry-Pi-AI-Kit"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T10:04:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi teamed up with Hailo to develop the Raspberry Pi AI Kit as a $70 add-on for the Raspberry Pi 5 that offers a 13 TOPS AI accelerator module...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD 14.1 Released With Performance Improvements, OpenZFS Upgrade & Better Sound]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeBSD-14.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeBSD-14.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T09:52:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD 14.1-RELEASE is now available as the newest stable release to this leading BSD operating system. There are a number of package updates, new features, and expanded hardware support to find with FreeBSD 14.1...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Xeon 6780E / Xeon 6766E 144-Core Performance Benchmarks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6780e-6766e</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6780e-6766e"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T03:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Intel's launch today of the Xeon 6700E series processors formerly codenamed Sierra Forest I am now able to share benchmarks of these new E-core server processors. Here is an initial look at the Intel Sierra Forest Linux performance using the Xeon 6766E and Xeon 6780E 144-core server processors in both single and dual socket configurations compared to prior Intel Xeon processors and the AMD EPYC competition.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Launches Xeon 6700E Sierra Forest CPUs - Initially Up To 144 Cores]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6700e-sierra-forest</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-xeon-6700e-sierra-forest"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T03:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel is using Computex 2024 for announcing the first Xeon 6 processors, which are the E-Core Sierra Forest models that initially are available in up to 144 cores per socket. Intel is also using Computex to shed more light on the Gaudi 3 AI accelerator and the upcoming P core Xeon 6 Granite Rapids processors and the later launch of the Xeon 6900E models with up to 288 cores per socket.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Reveals New Lunar Lake Details At Computex]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Lunar-Lake-Xe2-Details</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Lunar-Lake-Xe2-Details"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[24 hours ago AMD was in the limelight in announcing the Ryzen 9000 series, the Ryzen AI 300 series, teasing AMD 5th Gen EPYC, etc. Now the tables have turned to Intel with the embargo lifting concerning new details on the Gaudi 3 AI accelerator and upcoming Lunar Lake mobile processors and the launch of the Intel Xeon 6700E (Sierra Forest) E-core server processors. In this article is a look at some of the new disclosures around Lunar Lake...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-03]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-03.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-03.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 03, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


L(O*62).ONG: Make your URL longer
(comments)


Everything I know about the fast inverse square root algorithm
(comments)


Ask HN: What was your most humbling learning moment?
(comments)


An intuitive guide to Maxwell's equations (2020)
(comments)


Learn CSS Grid with a virtual garden game
(comments)


AMD Unveils Ryzen 9000 CPUs for Desktop, Zen 5
(comments)


Making USB devices – end to end guide to your first gadget
(comments)


I'm forking Ladybird and stepping down as SerenityOS BDFL
(comments)


How many photons are received per bit transmitted from Voyager 1?
(comments)


Ask HN: Who is hiring? (June 2024)
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Hiring To Improve Their Linux Driver/ROCm Installation Process Across Distributions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Unified-Linux-Jobs</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Unified-Linux-Jobs"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T21:05:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD is hiring engineers to work on build and packaging of their "AMD Unified Linux Driver" to enhance the experience of deploying their packaged graphics driver stack -- including ROCm -- across different Linux distributions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rust-Written Redox OS Continues Gravitating Toward The COSMIC Desktop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Redox-OS-May-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Redox-OS-May-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T16:53:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Rust-written Redox OS operating system issued their May monthly status report to highlight the various improvements made to this original open-source OS...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debian Seeing Work To Support systemd-boot]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Debian-Expert-systemd-boot</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Debian-Expert-systemd-boot"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T15:10:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Debian developer Luca Boccassi has begun working on systemd-boot support for using it as an alternative to the GRUB bootloader...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Mint Disabling Unverified Flatpaks By Default]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Mint-Unverified-Flatpaks</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Mint-Unverified-Flatpaks"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T12:43:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux Mint project is out with its monthly newsletter that highlights recent progress made on this Ubuntu (and Debian) derived, desktop-focused Linux distribution. In May they worked out enhancements to Linux Mint's software manager and also continued working on optimizing their package archive hosting...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Up To 162% Faster AES-GCM Encryption/Decryption For Intel & AMD CPUs On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AES-GCM-Faster-AVX-VAES</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AES-GCM-Faster-AVX-VAES"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T10:38:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the in-development Linux 6.10 kernel Eric Biggers of Google landed new AES-XTS implementations for much faster performance for Intel/AMD processors via new AES-NI + AVX, VAES + AVX2, VAES + AVX10/256, and VAES + AVX10/512 code paths. Biggers has since begun tackling even better AES-GCM encryption/decryption performance by leveraging a new code path to utilize AVX-512/AVX10 and/or VAES...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 15 Merges Support For Intel APX NF]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-15-APX-NF</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-15-APX-NF"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T10:22:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest feature work around Intel's Advanced Performance Extensions (APX) that is merged for the in-development GCC 15 compiler is supporting APX NF functionality for suppressing the update of status flags on arithmetic operations...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCV 4.10 Released With Many DNN Improvements, Wayland Backend For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/OpenCV-4.10-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/OpenCV-4.10-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T09:54:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCV 4.10 is out today as the newest version of the Open Computer Vision Library for this widely-used library with machine learning support, object detection, segmentation and recognition, motion video tracking, gesture recognition, and a variety of other features important for today's diverse workloads...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phoronix Turns 20 Years Old This Week - Celebrate With A Premium Special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Phoronix-20th-Birthday-Special</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Phoronix-20th-Birthday-Special"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Wednesday, 5 June, marks 20 years since I started Phoronix.com for covering the Linux hardware ecosystem! It's sure been a long and tough journey with more remarks I'll reserve for Wednesday, but given the two decade mark, there's a Phoronix Premium special for those wishing to mark the special occasion and help ensure the site's healthy continuance into the next decade...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Ryzen 9000 Series Announced - Zen 5 Showing Big Generational Uplift]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Ryzen-9000-Series-Zen-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Ryzen-9000-Series-Zen-5"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T03:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arguably most exciting out of AMD's slew of Computex 2024 announcements is finally making official the Ryzen 9000 "Granite Ridge" processors built atop the new Zen 5 cores...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Previews 5th Gen EPYC With Up To 192 Cores Per Socket]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-5th-Gen-EPYC-Turin-192-Core</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-5th-Gen-EPYC-Turin-192-Core"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T03:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to all of the AMD client-side news during Lisa Su's keynote at Computex 2024 (see AMD Ryzen 9000 Series and AMD's Ryzen AI 300 Series Mobile APUs), the AMD CEO also teased the upcoming 5th Gen EPYC processors. AMD 5th Gen EPYC "Turin" processors are still on the way for releasing in H2'2024...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD's Ryzen AI 300 Series Mobile APUs Should Be Interesting For Next-Gen Laptops]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Ryzen-AI-300-Series-Zen-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Ryzen-AI-300-Series-Zen-5"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T03:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to announcing the AMD Ryzen 9000 series desktop processors powered by Zen 5, Lisa Su at Computex 2024 also announced the AMD Ryzen AI 300 series as the next-generation mobile processors powered by Zen 5 CPU cores while sporting RDNA 3.5 (also referred to as RDNA 3+ and RDNA3 refresh) integrated graphics and an XDNA 2 NPU...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Roadmaps Instinct MI325X Accelerator For Q4, Instinct MI350 In 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Instinct-MI325X-MI350-MI400</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Instinct-MI325X-MI350-MI400"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Computex 2024, AMD confirmed the Instinct MI325X will be released in Q4'2024 as the successor to the MI300X accelerator. Next year will be the AMD Instinct MI350 series based on the new CFNA 4 architecture. AMD is committing to an annual Instinct accelerator roadmap moving forward as they further up their AI game...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Announces Radeon PRO W7900 Dual Slot For Workstations & Gen AI]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Radeon-PRO-W7900-Dual-Slot</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Radeon-PRO-W7900-Dual-Slot"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the AMD Ryzen 9000 series (Zen 5) details are arguably the most exciting aspect of Lisa Su's keynote at Computex 2024, over on the Radeon side is the announcement of the AMD Radeon PRO W7900 Dual Slot graphics card intended for compact workstations and Gen AI...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-02]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-02.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-02.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 02, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Repairing my mug with Kintsugi
(comments)


What we've learned from a year of building with LLMs
(comments)


In Colorado, an ambitious new highway policy is not building them
(comments)


What I think about Lua after shipping a project with 60k lines of code
(comments)


Einstein went to his office just so he could walk home with Gödel
(comments)


Lisp: Icing or Cake?
(comments)


Python notebooks for fundamentals of music processing
(comments)


How do our brains adapt to control an extra body part?
(comments)


Signal: Will leave the EU market rather than undermine our privacy guarantees
(comments)


Parable of the Sofa
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10-rc2 Released With An Initial Batch Of Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc2-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc2-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds just released Linux 6.0-rc2 with a busy week's worth of fixes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autodafe 1.0 Released For Freeing Projects Of Autotools]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Autodafe-1.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Autodafe-1.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Controversial free software developer Eric S Raymond has been spending a lot of time recently on the new Autodafe project as a means of free software projects from relying on Autotools. This "De-Autoconfiscation" has now led to the release of Autodafe 1.0 with the tool now being considered production-ready...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.11 To Bring Nouveau NVreg_RegistryDwords Support, Intel NPU Enhancements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/DRM-Misc-6.11-Nouveau-Intel-NPU</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/DRM-Misc-6.11-Nouveau-Intel-NPU"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now past the Linux 6.10 merge window, this week brought an initial batch of drm-misc-next changes submitted to the Direct Rendering Manager subsystem's DRM-Next for queuing until the Linux 6.11 merge window opens up in July. The changes this week include a notable addition for the open-source NVIDIA (Nouveau) driver and some improvements for the Intel iVPU driver for their Neural Processing Unit (NPU)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10-rc2 Will Fix Booting Intel Quark CPUs & Problems With Old AMD CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc2-x86-urgent</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc2-x86-urgent"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of today's Linux 6.10-rc2 kerne weekly test release a few "x86/urgent" patches were submitted for addressing some fallout on Intel and AMD processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ASUS Announces The ROG Ally X Upgraded Handheld]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/ASUS-ROG-Ally-X</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/ASUS-ROG-Ally-X"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T10:14:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ASUS used Computex 2024 for announcing the ROG Ally X, the latest version of their handheld gaming console. The ASUS ROG Ally X continues to be powered by the AMD Ryzen Z1 Extreme SoC but now having more storage, faster RAM, a larger battery, updated controls, and other refinements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Shoots Past The 2% Threshold For The Steam Survey, AMD CPU Use Breaks 75%]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Steam-2024-Above-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Steam-2024-Above-2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T00:37:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Steam on Linux debuted a decade ago it maintained around a 2% marketshare before receding and then beginning its long climb back up following the debut of Steam Play for running Windows games on Linux and then with the much anticipated Steam Deck handheld game console and the modern Arch-based SteamOS. Valve just published their May 2024 numbers for the Steam Survey and they indicate the Linux marketshare is finally back above 2%...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-06-01]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-01.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-06-01.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on June 01, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Debian KDE: Right Linux distribution for professional digital painting in 2024
(comments)


Carpenter's AirTags help uncover 'massive' case of stolen tools in Maryland
(comments)


This Message Does Not Exist
(comments)


How to copy a file from a 30-year-old laptop
(comments)


Recall: Stealing everything you've ever typed or viewed on your own Windows PC
(comments)


UI elements with a hand-drawn, sketchy look
(comments)


Tiny number of 'supersharers' spread the majority of fake news
(comments)


ROOT: analyzing petabytes of data scientifically
(comments)


Arthur Whitney releases an open-source subset of K with MIT license
(comments)


Napster sparked a file-sharing revolution 25 years ago
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VCN5 AV1 Encode & More AMD RDNA4 RADV Support Land In Mesa 24.2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-More-GFX12-RDNA4-Mesa-24.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-More-GFX12-RDNA4-Mesa-24.2"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T14:48:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been another busy week with the open-source AMD Linux graphics driver stack with continued preparations around enabling support for next-generation RDNA4 graphics (as well as continued RDNA3+ / RDNA 3.5 tuning)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Xe2 Brings Native 64-bit Integer Arithmetic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Xe2-Native-64-bit-Int</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Xe2-Native-64-bit-Int"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T10:50:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As some more exciting news for upcoming Xe2 graphics with Lunar Lake integrated graphics and Battlemage discrete GPUs, the latest open-source driver activity for Linux has confirmed Xe2 supporting native 64-bit integer arithmetic...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debian Has Yet To Establish Firm Stance On The Use Of AI]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Debian-AI-Undecided</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Debian-AI-Undecided"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T10:45:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the Gentoo Linux project recently established an AI policy to forbid contributions to the project made using any AI tools/assistance and NetBSD also came out with a similar policy against AI-generated code, the Debian project for now has no project-wide policy regarding AI...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA Open Kernel Driver News, AMD EPYC 4004 & Linux 6.10 Made For A Fun May]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/May-2024-Highlights</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/May-2024-Highlights"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T10:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[May 2024 is now in the books with 285 original news articles written by your's truly last month along with another 14 Linux hardware reviews / multi-page featured benchmark articles. It was an interesting month with some fun new hardware launches, the Linux 6.10 merge window taking place, and other open-source software progress...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Releases Updated Celeron & Pentium Silver CPU Microcode]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Celeron-Silver-Microcode</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Celeron-Silver-Microcode"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T10:13:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's not too common for Intel to publish new CPU microcode updates outside of their "Patch Tuesday" regiment but that happened yesterday with a Friday night release of new CPU microcode although this time is limited to the Celeron and Pentium Silver families...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME Shares Update On Sovereign Tech Fund & Other Development Funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-STF-Update</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-STF-Update"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T01:55:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Expressed last week was a "major issue" from the GNOME Foundation side with regard to the Sovereign Tech Fund partnership for funding a number of useful improvements to the GNOME software stack just as Germany's STF has been doing to a number of other prominent open-source projects. While there still aren't many clear public details on this "major issue", a Friday night update from the GNOME side seems to indicate all is well and they are also embarking on additional development funding initiatives...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkan 1.3.286 Released With One New Extension]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Vulkan-1.3.286-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Vulkan-1.3.286-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T00:38:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkan 1.3.286 was released today with a handful of corrections/clarifications as well as one new extension...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-31]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-31.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-31.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 31, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


The Pumpkin Eclipse
(comments)


Unexpected anti-patterns for engineering leaders
(comments)


Show HN: Every mountain, building and tree shadow mapped for any date and time
(comments)


Japan's push to make all research open access
(comments)


Engineering for Slow Internet
(comments)


Every mountain, building and tree shadow in the world simulated for any time
(comments)


A man ordered to hide his boat painted the boat on his fence
(comments)


Snowflake breach: Hacker confirms access through infostealer infection
(comments)


Standard Ebooks' 1,000th title: Ulysses
(comments)


IRS Direct File to open to all 50 states and D.C. for 2025 tax season
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 9.10 Released With Upgrade To VKD3D 1.12, Brings DPI Awareness Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-9.10-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-9.10-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T23:14:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 9.10 is out today as the newest bi-weekly development release for this open-source software to enjoy Windows games/applications on Linux and other operating systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Godot 4.3 Beta 1 Released With Native Wayland Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Godot-4.3-Beta-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Godot-4.3-Beta-1"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T14:06:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The open-source Godot game engine has worked its way up to the Godot 4.3 Beta 1 milestone with some exciting achievements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dav1d 1.4.2 Provides More AVX2 & AVX-512 Performance Optimizations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/dav1d-1.4.2-AV1-Decoder</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/dav1d-1.4.2-AV1-Decoder"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T13:57:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jean-Baptiste Kempf released Dav1d 1.4.2 as the newest version of this speedy CPU-based AV1 video decoder. With this new dav1d 1.4.2 update are yet more performance optimizations for modern systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Lands A Nice Memset Performance Optimization In Glibc]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Glibc-Memset-Perf</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Glibc-Memset-Perf"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T12:56:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel engineer Noah Goldstein has landed another nice performance optimization in the GNU C Library "glibc" for benefiting newer Intel processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Is Making It Much Easier To Deal With Quirky Touchscreens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Easier-Quirky-Touch</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Easier-Quirky-Touch"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T11:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Right now when dealing with quirky/buggy touchscreens a C file needs to be manually manipulated and the Linux kernel recompiled. With a new "i2c_touchscreen_props" kernel command line option on its way to the mainline kernel, the process of overriding touchscreen properties is dramatically easier for those dealing with Linux on touchscreen-enabled devices...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bcachefs Preparing For New Features In Linux 6.11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Bcachefs-Look-Toward-Linux-6.11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Bcachefs-Look-Toward-Linux-6.11"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T10:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bcachefs lead developer Kent Overstreet sent in a batch of file-system fixes on Thursday for the in-development Linux 6.10 kernel. In that pull request he teased features that are set to arrive with the Linux 6.11 kernel later in the summer...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More AMDGPU Linux Firmware Published For RDNA 3+]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-Firmware-More-RDNA-3.5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-Firmware-More-RDNA-3.5"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T10:28:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month we began seeing AMDGPU driver firmware files published for the rumored "RDNA3+" hardware as an RDNA3 refresh (also as "RDNA 3.5") for upcoming APUs. More firmware files have now landed public in linux-firmware.git for these forthcoming RDNA3 refresh products...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kdenlive 24.05 Brings Multi-Format Rendering, Automatic Subtitle Translations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Kdenlive-24.05-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Kdenlive-24.05-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T10:19:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If the recent release of Flowblade 2.16 video editor wasn't of interest to you due to being GTK-based software, the Qt/KDE-aligned Kdenlive video editor is out this week with its Kdenlive 24.05 feature release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-30]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-30.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-30.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 30, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Donating forks to the dining hall
(comments)


DuckDB Doesn't Need Data to Be a Database
(comments)


Gov. Polis Signs Bill Mandating That Consumers Have Options to Fix Electronics
(comments)


FrankenPHP: Modern PHP App Server
(comments)


How actors remember their lines
(comments)


After 6 years, I'm over GraphQL
(comments)


I got tired of hearing that YC fired Sam, so here's what actually happened
(comments)


I love my wife. My wife is dead (1946)
(comments)


Show HN: ChatGPT UI for rabbit holes
(comments)


Don't DRY Your Code Prematurely
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wayland 1.23 Released With OpenBSD Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wayland-1.23-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wayland-1.23-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T19:46:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Simon Ser today released Wayland 1.23 for this core Wayland code that brings some minor enhancements, bug fixes, and Wayland protocol clarifications...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Rolling Out New Windows Subsystem For Linux "WSL" Features For 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Microsoft-WSL2-2024-Features</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Microsoft-WSL2-2024-Features"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T18:43:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Given Microsoft's recent BUILD conference, Microsoft has announced a number of sizable updates to Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD EPYC 4124P Benchmarks: A Quad-Core $149 Server CPU]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/amd-epyc-4124p</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/amd-epyc-4124p"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T16:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week with the AMD EPYC 4004 review and benchmarks I tested nearly the entire product stack for these new AM5-based server processors with the EPYC 4244P (6 cores), EPYC 4344P (8 cores), EPYC 4364P (8 cores), EPYC 4464P (12 cores), EPYC 4484X (12 cores + 3D V-Cache), EPYC 4564P (16 cores), and EPYC 4584PX (16 cores + 3D V-Cache). The only EPYC 4004 class processor I wasn't able to finish testing in time was the entry-level EPYC 4124P as a 4-core processor with $149 retail price. I've now had the time to finish benchmarking that budget-focused Zen 4 server processor as well as seeing how it compares to the 4-core Skylake Xeons that were prolific for years.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora's New Web-Based Installer UI Delayed Yet Again... Now In 2025 With Fedora 42]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Anaconda-Web-UI-Fedora-42</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Anaconda-Web-UI-Fedora-42"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T15:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been more than two years now talking about the Anaconda installer for Fedora/RHEL shifting to a web-based UI. Going back to Fedora 37 have been previews and plans for getting this modern user interface up to parity but it's been a long road. With repeated delays, there's at least one more delay: the Anaconda web UI was just shifted from Fedora 41 to Fedora 42...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real-Time Kernel Now Available On Ubuntu 24.04 LTS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.04-LTS-Real-Time</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.04-LTS-Real-Time"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T14:37:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Similar to the real-time kernel for Ubuntu 22.04 LTS, Canonical announced today the availability of their new real-time "RT" kernel for Ubuntu 24.04 LTS. But like with the existing Ubuntu RT kernels, this real-time support is limited to Ubuntu Pro subscriptions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Servo Web Engine Continues Advancing But Seeing Just $1.6k In Monthly Donations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Servo-Engine-May-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Servo-Engine-May-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T14:26:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Rust-written Servo web engine as a reminder was started as a Mozilla project but then abandoned and now developed by multiple organizations as part of Linux Foundation Europe. The Servo project has put out a new status update that highlights the work accomplished in recent weeks...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yocto 5.0 LTS Released - Now Powered By Linux 6.6 LTS, Boeing Joins The Project]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Yocto-5.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Yocto-5.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T14:09:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yocto 5.0 LTS has been released as the newest version from the Yocto Project that is popular for organizations assembling their own embedded/IoT-minded custom Linux distributions. The Linux Foundation also announced today that Boeing has become a Platinum Member with Yocto...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD & Intel Team Up For UALink As Open Alternative To NVIDIA's NVLink]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ultra-Accelerator-Link-UALink</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ultra-Accelerator-Link-UALink"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's rare for an advanced media briefing to involve representatives from both AMD and Intel, but that happened yesterday. AMD and Intel along with Broadcom have formed the Ultra Accelerator Link "UALink" as a new open standard they are hoping to use to take on NVIDIA's proprietary NVLink interface...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Battlemage Platform Support Begins Landing In Mesa 24.2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Battlemage-Goes-Mesa-24.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Battlemage-Goes-Mesa-24.2"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T10:33:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Intel Battlemage discrete graphics support is beginning to come together for the open-source Linux graphics driver stack as the successor to DG2/Alchemist. In addition to all the Xe2 work for what's found with Lunar Lake, more Battlemage Linux kernel and user-space driver work has been appearing recently. The milestone crossed today is the initial Battlemage "BMG" platform support being merged for the Mesa 24.2 OpenGL/Vulkan drivers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Improving NMI Source Reporting On Linux With FRED]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Linux-NMI-Source-Report</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Linux-NMI-Source-Report"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T10:24:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of Intel's Flexible Return Event Delivery (FRED), Intel open-source software engineers are now working on improving Non-Maskable Interrupt (NMI) source reporting for the Linux kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Enabling PowerVR Rogue GX6250 Open-Source Support With The MediaTek MT8173]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/PowerVR-GX6250-MT8173</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/PowerVR-GX6250-MT8173"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T10:14:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building off the PowerVR kernel driver merged in Linux 6.8 and PowerVR Vulkan driver in Mesa 24.0 that are both focused on Imagination's newer PowerVR Rogue architecture, Google engineers are working on enabling open-source driver support for the PowerVR Rogue GX6250 as found within the MediaTek MT8173 SoC...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDGpu v0.5 Vulkan Wrapper Released, KDXr Begins Wrapping OpenXR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDGpu-0.5-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDGpu-0.5-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T09:57:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year the KDAB consulting firm typically associated with Qt work published KDGpu as a thin Vulkan wrapper to make it easier leveraging this graphics API. Out today is KDGpu v0.5 with many improvements to this Vulkan wrapper...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VKD3D 1.12 Released With Support For Directly Outputting SPIR-V & D3D Shader Assembly]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/VKD3D-1.12-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/VKD3D-1.12-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T00:23:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While VKD3D-Proton that is bundled with Valve's Steam Play (Proton) is the most common source for mapping Direct3D 12 over the Vulkan API for Windows games on Linux, Wine's VKD3D upstream continues to be developed. Out today is VKD3D 1.12 as the newest feature release for this open-source D3D12-on-Vulkan implementation...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-29]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-29.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-29.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 29, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Mobifree – An open-source mobile ecosystem
(comments)


Show HN: Openkoda – Open–source, private, Salesforce alternative
(comments)


Llama 3-V: Matching GPT4-V with a 100x smaller model and 500 dollars
(comments)


Ex-OpenAI board member reveals what led to Sam Altman's brief ousting
(comments)


AI headphones let wearer listen to a single person in a crowd by looking at them
(comments)


Codestral: Mistral's Code Model
(comments)


I sold TinyPilot, my first successful business
(comments)


Ottawa wants the power to create secret backdoors in networks for surveillance
(comments)


Vector indexing all of Wikipedia on a laptop
(comments)


Kino: Pro Video Camera
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[XZ 5.6.2 Released With The Frightening Backdoor Removed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/XZ-5.6.2-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/XZ-5.6.2-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T20:14:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was two months ago today that an urgent security alert was issued over XZ being hit by malicious code that turned out to be a backdoor within liblzma added by a bad actor that worked his way into XZ co-maintainership. Longtime XZ developer Lasse Collin is back at the helm and has been auditing the prior XZ commits and today released XZ 5.6.2 with the backdoor completely removed...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Cloud Traffic Is Suffocating Fedora's Mirrors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AWS-Cloud-Breaks-Fedora-Mirrors</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AWS-Cloud-Breaks-Fedora-Mirrors"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T19:49:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A massive uptick in traffic to Fedora's package mirrors is causing problems for the Linux distribution. Some five million additional systems have started putting additional strain on Fedora's mirror resources since March and appear to be coming from Amazon's cloud...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Framework Announces Intel Core Ultra Powered Laptop With 2.8k Display]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Framework-Core-Ultra-Laptop</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Framework-Core-Ultra-Laptop"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T17:54:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Framework is out today with some exciting announcements from lowering the price of the existing Framework 13 with AMD Ryzen 7040 series SoC to announcing a new Framework Laptop 13 powered by Intel Core Ultra (Meteor Lake) and having a new 2.8K display option for this modular/upgradeable laptop shipping this summer...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Features Include TPM Bus Encryption, More AMD Zen 5 & A Prison Letter Merge Request]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/linux-610-features</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/linux-610-features"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now that the Linux 6.10 merge window has wrapped up, here's a look at all of the exciting features/changes coming to this summer 2024 kernel. Linux 6.10 brings a lot as usual for the latest/upcoming Intel and AMD platforms, never-ending work on file-systems, a new memory sealing "mseal" system call, TPM bus encryption, and dozens of other exciting changes and new hardware support.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arm Announces The Cortex-X925 & Cortex-A725]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Arm-Cortex-X925-Cortex-A725</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Arm-Cortex-X925-Cortex-A725"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T16:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arm today announced the latest products in the Armv9 CPU portfolio: the Cortex-X925 as their "ultimate performance" processor and the Cortex-A725 as their processor option for sustained performance...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[QuestDB 8.0 Brings Up To 50% Performance Improvement, ZFS Data Compression]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/QuestDB-8.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/QuestDB-8.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T14:39:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[QuestDB 8.0 is out today as the newest feature update to this open-source time-series database. QuestDB continues to cater to high throughput ingestion and fast SQL queries so it can handle use-cases from financial data to IoT sensors. With today's QuestDB 8.0 release, it's even faster...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Launches "Opt Green" Initiative For Sustainable Software & Hardware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Opt-Green</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Opt-Green"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T12:58:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[KDE's Eco group announced today "Opt Green" as a new initiative for sustainable software...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical Developing "Flamenco" For Enhancing .NET Developer Experience On Ubuntu]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Flamenco-dot-NET-Ubuntu</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Flamenco-dot-NET-Ubuntu"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T11:06:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the newest open-source projects in-development by Ubuntu maker Canonical is a new C# written program called Flamenco...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve's AMD Shader Compiler "ACO" Makes More Preparations For Radeon RDNA4]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-ACO-Changes-GFX12</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-ACO-Changes-GFX12"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:41:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The AMD shader compiler "ACO" alternative to the AMDGPU LLVM back-end has seen another batch of changes merged in preparations for next-generation Radeon RDNA4 GPUs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Makes One Line Tweak To GCC To Fix A "Random Performance Penalty"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-GCC-Loop-Alignment</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-GCC-Loop-Alignment"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coming up on my radar today is a commit made to the GNU Compiler Collection (GCC) for adjusting the loop alignment with Intel's generic tuning path. In turn this should address "some random performance penalty in benchmarks" with coping better around cache lines...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Sub-NUMA Clustering Support Linux Patches Spun A 19th Time]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-SNC-With-RDT-Linux-v19</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-SNC-With-RDT-Linux-v19"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:22:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The past year there's been a big Linux kernel patch series in the work by Intel to improve Sub-NUMA Clustering "SNC" support so it behaves well with Intel Resource Director Technology (RDT) on modern Intel hardware. Hopefully that work will soon be ready for mainlining in the Linux kernel while this week brought the 19th revision to those patches...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flowblade 2.16 Open-Source Video Editor Released]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Flowblade-2.16-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Flowblade-2.16-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:15:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flowblade 2.16 is out today as the newest version of this open-source non-linear video editor...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SVT-AV1 2.1 Released With Yet More Performance Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/SVT-AV1-2.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/SVT-AV1-2.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T00:34:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SVT-AV1 that started out as an open-source AV1 video encoder at Intel and more recently an an Alliance of Open Media project quietly released SVT-AV1 v2.1 last week. With this new SVT-AV1 release are yet more performance optimizations and tuning...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-28]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-28.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-28.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 28, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


A 1.3B-light-year-across ring of galaxies has confounded astronomers
(comments)


Resume Tip: Hacking \"AI\" screening of resumes
(comments)


Priced out of home ownership
(comments)


Surveilling the masses with wi-fi-based positioning systems
(comments)


Tantivy – full-text search engine library inspired by Apache Lucene
(comments)


WP21
(comments)


Show HN: I made a free app to calibrate your turntable by simply playing a song
(comments)


Reproducing GPT-2 in llm.c
(comments)


TTE: Terminal Text Effects
(comments)


API Shouldn't Redirect HTTP to HTTPS
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Xe2 Ray-Tracing & More Intel Lunar Lake Enabling Land In Mesa 24.2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.2-More-Intel-Lunar-Lake</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.2-More-Intel-Lunar-Lake"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T20:34:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's open-source Linux graphics driver engineers continue to be quite busy preparing their Xe kernel driver and Mesa user-space ANV Vulkan / Iris Gallium3D driver for upcoming Lunar Lake processors. Merged today for Mesa 24.2-devel is more Lunar Lake platform enablement work plus early support for ray-tracing with the integrated Xe2 graphics. However, more work is still needed before this Lunar Lake / Xe2 support will be ready for end-users on the Linux desktop...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Starts Preparing Its Open-Source DirectX Shader Compiler For "HLSL 202x"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/MS-HLSL-202x-Prep-Compiler</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/MS-HLSL-202x-Prep-Compiler"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T18:33:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft's open-source DirectX Shader Compiler that is open-source and derived from the LLVM/Clang compiler infrastructure is out with a significant new release as it begins preparing for "HLSL 202x" as a big leap for the High-Level Shader Language...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome 127 Should Provide PipeWire Camera Capture Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Chrome-127-PipeWire-Capture</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Chrome-127-PipeWire-Capture"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T18:18:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Google Chrome/Chromium 127 web browser release should finally provide support for PipeWire camera capturing support!..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crucial Pro DDR5-6000 32GB Memory Kit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/crucial-pro-ddr5-6000</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/crucial-pro-ddr5-6000"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T18:05:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Crucial last week announced the launch of their newest Crucial DDR5 Pro Memory: Overclocking (OC) Edition in white heatspreader form. Crucial recently sent over a pair of these 2 x 16GB Crucial Pro DDR5-6000 UDIMM memory kits that we've been putting through the paces with Intel Core i9 14900K and AMD Ryzen 9 7950X systems. These new Crucial Pro DIMMs have been working out very well and align with the great quality we've long enjoyed from Crucial/Micron.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux cpupower Tool Fix Coming For AMD Zen 5 CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-cpupower-Fix-AMD-Zen-5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-cpupower-Fix-AMD-Zen-5"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T16:26:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sent out today as a fix for the Linux kernel's in-tree "cpupower" utility is properly handling P-State frequency reporting for upcoming AMD Zen 5 processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AlmaLinux 8.10 Released With Support Re-Enabled For Some Older Hardware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AlmaLinux-8.10-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AlmaLinux-8.10-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T14:06:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those continuing to rely on the Enterprise Linux 8 series, AlmaLinux 8.10 has made its stable debut this morning as the newest version of this community-oriented operating system derived from Red Hat Enterprise Linux 8.10...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TPM HMAC Encryption Being Pulled Back To x86_64 By Default For Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/TPM-HMAC-Encrypt-x86_64</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/TPM-HMAC-Encrypt-x86_64"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T12:54:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the new security features coming with Linux 6.10 is TPM bus encryption and integrity protection to fend off a wave of possible attacks against Trusted Platform Module recovery keys, TPM sniffing, etc. This functionality was merged for the Linux 6.10 merge window but is now being pulled back to x86_64-only by default where it's been sufficiently tested...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ASUS Linux Driver Adding Ability To Toggle CPU Cores, APU Memory Settings & dGPU TGP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/ASUS-Linux-Cores-APU-Mem-TGP</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/ASUS-Linux-Cores-APU-Mem-TGP"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T10:38:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ASUS WMI platform driver for Linux that is predominantly used by ASUS laptops for enabling more functionality under Linux has a new patch series available that is enabling yet more features for the latest ASUS hardware on Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[openSUSE Aeon RC2 Released With Btrfs Compression Default, ZRAM & Tik]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/openSUSE-Aeon-RC2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/openSUSE-Aeon-RC2"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T10:13:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly one year ago to the day the openSUSE project anounced MicroOS Desktop GNOME being renamed to openSUSE Aeon while openSUSE Desktop Plasma was taking the name openSUSE Kalpa...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 24.04 Now Available For The Milk-V Mars RISC-V Single Board Computer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.04-Milk-V-Mars</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.04-Milk-V-Mars"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T09:58:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical announced this morning an optimized Ubuntu 24.04 image for the Milk-V Mars, a "credit card sized" RISC-V single board computer...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-27]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-27.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-27.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 27, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


To the brain, reading computer code is not the same as reading language (2020)
(comments)


Mediocre Engineer's Guide to HTTPS
(comments)


What the damaged Svalbard cable looked like
(comments)


The one-year anniversary of my total glossectomy
(comments)


The t-test was invented at the Guinness brewery
(comments)


Big data is dead (2023)
(comments)


Instead of “auth”, we should say “permissions” and “login”
(comments)


Should I use JWTs for authentication tokens?
(comments)


The Internet Archive is under a DDoS attack
(comments)


Controlling the Taylor Swift Eras Tour wristbands with Flipper Zero
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD 14.1-RC1 Adds More Packages To The DVD Images - Including The Sway Compositor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeBSD-14.1-RC1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/FreeBSD-14.1-RC1-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-27T21:27:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD 14.1-RC1 is now available for testing as this incremental update to FreeBSD 14 prepares for its stable release in June...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Performance Limit Reasons For Linux To Report Why Your CPU Is Downclocking]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Perf-Limit-Reasons-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Perf-Limit-Reasons-Linux"/>
        <updated>2024-05-27T17:23:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Performance Limit Reasons (PLR) can indicate why your CPU is downclocking / limited to a lower performance limit for a given core or die. With some Windows utilities this information this Intel CPU feature has been available there while now Intel is bringing PLR support to Linux too...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Releases ISPC 1.24 With New AVX-VNNI & AVX512-VNNI Targets]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-ISPC-1.24-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-ISPC-1.24-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-27T14:37:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Intel Implicit SPMD Program Compiler (ISPC) is out with a new version today for this C programming language variant that features SPMD programming extensions. Intel ISPC aims to make it easy to take advantage of SIMD capabilities on their modern processors as well as GPUs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD's GPUOpen Vulkan Memory Allocator 3.1 Improves Raspberry Pi Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Vulkan-Memory-Allocator-3.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Vulkan-Memory-Allocator-3.1"/>
        <updated>2024-05-27T13:44:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD by way of their GPUOpen group have released version 3.1 of the open-source Vulkan Memory Allocator...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Patches Posted For Enabling A 22 x 35 mm RISC-V / ARM Board]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/LicheeRV-Nano-Linux-Patches</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/LicheeRV-Nano-Linux-Patches"/>
        <updated>2024-05-27T10:55:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux kernel patches were posted today for enabling Linux to boot on the LicheeRV Nano, a mini single board computer that comes in at a mere 22.86 x 35.56 mm. As interesting as the size with this SBC is the Sophgo SG2002 SoC that features a mix of RISC-V and ARM cores...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An End-User Has Made It Easier To Build ROCm & AMD GPU Machine Learning Software]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Making-ROCm-Build-Easier</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Making-ROCm-Build-Easier"/>
        <updated>2024-05-27T10:26:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An end-user and Phoronix reader has taken up creating his own AMD ROCm SDK build system to make it easier to setup a machine learning software stack from scratch on AMD Radeon GPUs under Linux. This open-source build system pulls in the AMD ROCm source code as well as AMD GPU-accelerated tools like PyTorch and ONNX and makes it easier to deploy and without having to rely on Docker or other solutions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-26]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-26.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-26.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 26, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


&udm=14 – easy access to an AI-free Google search
(comments)


So good, it works on barbed wire (2001)
(comments)


Helen Keller on her life before self-consciousness (1908)
(comments)


Diffusion Models
(comments)


Ask HN: What is your ChatGPT customization prompt?
(comments)


How Home Assistant is being used to protect from missile and drone attacks
(comments)


Braid: Synchronization for HTTP
(comments)


Hurl, the Exceptional Language
(comments)


Cloudflare took down our website
(comments)


Google Meet rolls out multi-device adaptive audio merging
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10-rc1 Kernel Released With Many New Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-rc1"/>
        <updated>2024-05-26T22:38:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux 6.10-rc1 kernel was just released to top off the Linux 6.10 merge window...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel NPU Driver Being Refactored For More Versatile CPU+NPU Handling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-NPU-iVPU-Refactoring</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-NPU-iVPU-Refactoring"/>
        <updated>2024-05-26T13:50:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's open-source NPU "iVPU" Linux kernel driver for supporting their Neural Processing Unit beginning with Core Ultra "Meteor Lake" processors is already seeing a code refactoring. The refactoring of this Intel accelerator driver is intended for allowing more versatile CPU and NPU combinations moving forward...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Supports NUMA Balancing For Multi-Size THPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-MM</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-MM"/>
        <updated>2024-05-26T10:59:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the memory management "MM" updates merged for the Linux 6.10 there is now NUMA balancing support for multi-size transparent hugepages (THPs). This is yielding some nice performance results and there is also other work in this new kernel around multi-size THPs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated Patches For AMD "Fast CPPC" To Yield Higher Performance At Same Power Level]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Fast-CPPC-v4-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-Fast-CPPC-v4-Linux"/>
        <updated>2024-05-26T10:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the patch series that sadly was not ready in time for the Linux 6.10 merge window and thus will need to wait a few months for at least the next kernel is enabling AMD Fast CPPC support for Zen 4 processors. Fast CPPC aims to allow the processor to deliver higher performance at the same power consumption...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nouveau DRM_Panic Being Worked On For Linux "Blue Screen Of Death" Type Situations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Nouveau-DRM-Panic-Patches</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Nouveau-DRM-Panic-Patches"/>
        <updated>2024-05-26T10:15:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged for Linux 6.10 is DRM_Panic as a kernel panic screen for situations akin to Windows' well known "Blue Screen of Death". This is a kernel-based panic screen as an  alternative to systemd's recent systemd-bsod. Patches have been posted by Red Hat for allowing the open-source NVIDIA "Nouveau" Direct Rendering Manager driver to work with DRM Panic...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modern NTFS Driver Sees Bug Fixes With Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-NTFS-Fixes</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-NTFS-Fixes"/>
        <updated>2024-05-26T10:01:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While not as exciting as XFS expanding its online repair support, Bcachefs prepping for online fsck, Btrfs seeing some performance work, or F2FS improving zoned storage support, the modern NTFS driver "NTFS3" saw a set of fixes land for the Linux 6.10 kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-25]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-25.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-25.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 25, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Show HN: We open sourced our entire text-to-SQL product
(comments)


Voxel Displacement Renderer – Modernizing the Retro 3D Aesthetic
(comments)


Sharing details on a recent incident impacting one of our customers
(comments)


Thermodynamic Natural Gradient Descent
(comments)


Samsung WB850F Firmware Reverse Engineering
(comments)


Writing a Unix clone in about a month
(comments)


Mp3tag – Universal Tag Editor
(comments)


Show HN: Spot – Simple, cross-platform, reactive desktop GUI toolkit for Go
(comments)


Abusing Go's Infrastructure
(comments)


Google scrambles to manually remove weird AI answers in search
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Improves AMD ROCm Compute Support For "Small" Ryzen APUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-AMDKFD-Small-APUs</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-AMDKFD-Small-APUs"/>
        <updated>2024-05-25T13:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sneaking in as a "fix" for the Linux 6.10 kernel is an enhancement to the AMDKFD kernel compute driver used by the ROCm compute stack for better supporting small Ryzen APUs like client and embedded SoCs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 On RISC-V Allows Configurable Boot Image Compression]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-RISC-V-Image-Comp</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-RISC-V-Image-Comp"/>
        <updated>2024-05-25T13:04:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few days ago with the main RISC-V architecture pull for Linux 6.10 was enabling Rust support within the kernel for this ISA as well as other additions. A secondary set of RISC-V changes have been merged as well ahead of the Linux 6.10 merge window closing this weekend...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Llamafile 0.8.5 Delivers Greater Performance: Tiny Models 2x Faster On Threadripper]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Llamafile-0.8.5-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Llamafile-0.8.5-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-25T10:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Mozilla Ocho group has published their newest version of Llamafile, the open-source project that makes it very easy to distribute and run large language models (LLMs) as a single file. Llamafile is an excellent solution for easily sharing and running LLMs and supporting both speedy CPU-based execution as well as GPU acceleration where available...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME Continues Working On New Installer, "Major Issue" With STF]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Memorial-Week-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Memorial-Week-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-05-25T10:33:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This Week In GNOME is out with their newest edition to outline all of the interesting developments as we approach the end of May...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel NPU Acceleration Library 1.1 Adds New Model Support & Optimizations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-NPU-Accel-Lib-1.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-NPU-Accel-Lib-1.1"/>
        <updated>2024-05-25T10:18:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel software engineers did a late Friday night release of the Intel NPU Acceleration Library v1.1, their Python library for tapping into the Intel Neural Processing Unit (NPU) found on the new Core Ultra (Meteor Lake) processors. This Python library makes it easier to interface with the Intel VPU/NPU kernel driver and in turn enjoying accelerated operations for AI...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Landed Many Last Minute Features Ahead Of The Plasma 6.1 Beta]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Plasma-6.1-Last-Minute-Features</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Plasma-6.1-Last-Minute-Features"/>
        <updated>2024-05-25T10:11:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was a busy week for KDE developers ahead of yesterday's Plasma 6.1 Beta release. KDE developer Nate Graham in his weekly development summary outlined all of the interesting changes to make it into the Plasma 6.1 desktop ahead of the feature freeze that went into effect with the beta release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memory Sealing "mseal" System Call Merged For Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Merges-mseal</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Merges-mseal"/>
        <updated>2024-05-25T00:15:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged this Friday evening into the Linux 6.10 kernel is the new mseal() system call for memory sealing...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-24]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-24.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-24.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 24, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Tom Waits vs. Frito-Lay, Inc (2003)
(comments)


BB(3, 4) > Ack(14)
(comments)


300k airplanes in five years
(comments)


Making EC2 boot time faster
(comments)


Matcha.css – Drop-in semantic styling library in pure CSS
(comments)


Cement recycling method could help solve one of the big climate challenges
(comments)


Perplexica: Open-source Perplexity alternative
(comments)


2D Rigid Body Collision Resolution
(comments)


ICQ will stop working from June 26
(comments)


Financial Statement Analysis with Large Language Models
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New AMD RDNA3 APUs Added To Open-Source Linux Driver Along With RDNA4 Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-More-RDNA3-Plus-RDNA4-Fixes</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMD-More-RDNA3-Plus-RDNA4-Fixes"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T20:18:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Famed open-source AMD Mesa driver developer Marek Olšák has landed 13 more patches in Mesa 24.2-devel to provide fixes for GFX12 (RDNA4) graphics IP while also adding more GFX11 (RDNA3) APUs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 6.1 Beta Released With Wayland Explicit Sync, Input Capture Portal & More]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Plasma-6.1-Beta"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T18:24:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The beta release of Plasma 6.1 is now available for testing over the US holiday weekend...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Core Ultra 7 165U "Meteor Lake" Linux Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-core-ultra-165u</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/intel-core-ultra-165u"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those considering an Intel Core Ultra 7 165U "Meteor Lake" powered laptop, here are some benchmarks of the 165U using a Lenovo ThinkPad T14 Gen 5 compared against the Acer Swift 14 with the Core Ultra 7 155H (Meteor Lake), the AMD Ryzen 7 7840U (Zen 4) within the Framework 13, and the AMD Ryzen 7 7840HS (Zen 4) within the Framework 16 under Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 6.1 Lands Dynamic Triple Buffering Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Lands-Triple-Buffering</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Lands-Triple-Buffering"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T17:34:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The four month old KWin merge request by Xaver Hugl to allow for triple buffering has been merged and just in time for the Plasma 6.1 code branching!..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PoCL 6.0-RC1 OpenCL Bringing OpenMP, Intel oneTBB Driver & Better Level Zero]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/POCL-6.0-RC1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/POCL-6.0-RC1"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T14:46:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[POCL as the "Portable Computing Language" OpenCL implementation that originally began as a CPU-based run-time and has expanded to support a variety of GPU and accelerator targets is out with its first release candidate of the upcoming PoCL 6.0...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Btrfs Sends In Fixes For Linux 6.10 & Restores "norecovery" Mount Option]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Btrfs-norecovery-Linux-6.10</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Btrfs-norecovery-Linux-6.10"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T14:35:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week saw the main Btrfs pull request for Linux 6.10 that delivered on some performance optimizations while today saw a secondary set of merge window changes for this CoW file-system that is now adding back the "norecovery" mount option...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DM-Crypt "High Priority" In Linux 6.10 Makes For Better Throughput & Latency]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-DM</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-DM"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T13:41:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Device Mapper changes were merged last week into the Linux 6.10 kernel, including a new "high priority" option for DM-Crypt...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PipeWire 1.2 Can Stream To Snapcast Servers For Multi-Room Audio]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/PipeWire-1.2-RC2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/PipeWire-1.2-RC2"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T11:11:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the recent PipeWire 1.2 release candidate, a second release candidate is out today that also includes the ability to stream to Snapcast servers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Hardware Monitoring Includes New Lenovo ThinkStation Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-HWMON</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-HWMON"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T10:51:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The hardware monitoring "HWMON" subsystem changes for the Linux 6.10 kernel include enabling monitoring of more all-in-one liquid coolers for CPUs, a new driver for exposing monitoring on Lenovo ThinkStation workstations, and other new monitoring capabilities...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Framework 13 & 16 Added To ChromeOS Platform Driver In Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Framework-CrOS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Framework-CrOS"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T10:43:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Framework 13 and Framework 16 AMD Ryzen powered laptops make use of an NPCX embedded controller that rely on the ChromeOS open-source embedded controller (EC) firmware. With the Linux 6.10 kernel the Chrome OS "cros_ec_lpc" driver is being extended to support these latest Framework upgradeable laptops...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Adds Support For The Machenike G5 Pro Controller]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Input</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Input"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T10:17:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the HID changes last week that brought Steam Deck IMU and ASUS ROG Ally support along with other Human Interface Device additions, on Thursday the input subsystem updates were submitted for this new kernel. The Machenike G5 Pro gaming controller is now supported along with other input additions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Is Disabling NFS v2 Client Support By Default]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-NFS-Client</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-NFS-Client"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T00:06:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the NFS server changes from a few days ago for Linux 6.10 that brought optimizations and prepping for the new "nfsdctl" utility, the Network File System client changes have been submitted and merged for this new kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-23]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-23.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-23.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 23, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Number 16 (spider)
(comments)


Windows 10 wallpaper was physically built and photographed (2015)
(comments)


Sal Khan is pioneering innovation in education again
(comments)


Show HN: Route your prompts to the best LLM
(comments)


US Justice Department to seek breakup of Live Nation-Ticketmaster
(comments)


OpenAI didn’t copy Scarlett Johansson’s voice for ChatGPT, records show
(comments)


WinDirStat – Windows Directory Statistics
(comments)


The Space Quest II Master Disk Blunder
(comments)


We're ending our Samsung collaboration
(comments)


Daylight Computer – New 60fps e-paper tablet
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME Publishes Draft Of Five-Year Strategic Plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-5-Year-Plan-Draft</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-5-Year-Plan-Draft"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T18:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GNOME Foundation has published a draft copy of their five-year strategic plan that calls for more around the community, DEI, services, a more streamlined and inclusive annual event, and strengthening the foundation...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coreboot 24.05 Released With 25 More Platforms - Including The Framework 13 AMD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Coreboot-24.05-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Coreboot-24.05-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T16:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coreboot 24.05 is available today as the newest stable release of this open-source system firmware solution. With Coreboot 24.05 there is support for 25 more motherboards/platforms and an assortment of other improvements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 24.04 + Linux 6.9 Intel & AMD Server Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/linux69-ubuntu-2404-servers</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/linux69-ubuntu-2404-servers"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While earlier this week was looking at the AMD EPYC 4004 vs. Intel Xeon E-2488 performance for entry-level server performance, in today's benchmarking showdown is a fresh look higher up the stack at the current generation server performance out of Intel Xeon Sapphire Rapids / Emerald Rapids and AMD EPYC Genoa(X) / Bergamo / Siena with a leading-edge open-source software stack of using Ubuntu 24.04 LTS while also jumping from Linux 6.8 to Linux 6.9 for the very latest x86_64 Linux server performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Delivers AMD & Intel P-State Driver Updates To Refine Power Management]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Power-Management</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Power-Management"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T16:16:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ACPI and power management / thermal subsystem changes were merged last week for the Linux 6.10 kernel. This cycle there are updates to both the Intel and AMD P-State CPU frequency scaling drivers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[64-bit ARM With Linux 6.10: Building FIT Images & Optional Disabling 32-bit User-Space]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-ARM64</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-ARM64"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T14:28:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged last week for the Linux 6.10 kernel were all of the 64-bit ARM (ARM64 / AArch64) architecture changes. There is ACPI FACS support, the ability to easily construct FIT images, and a new command-line option for disabling 32-bit application support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Staging Drops Broken & Unused Drivers To Remove 19k L.O.C.]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Staging</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Staging"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T10:58:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to the Linux 6.10 USB changes and char/misc with the new NTSYNC driver, Greg Kroah-Hartman on Wednesday also sent out the staging updates for Linux 6.10. There isn't much in the way of new code but some 19k lines of code removed thanks to removing an unused driver as well as a broken driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Removes Knights Mill & Knights Landing Xeon Phi Support In LLVM 19]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/LLVM-19-Drops-Xeon-Phi</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/LLVM-19-Drops-Xeon-Phi"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T10:44:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Similar to the GCC compiler dropping support for the Xeon Phi Knights Mill and Knights Landing accelerators a few days ago, Intel has also gone ahead and seen to the removal of Xeon Phi support for the LLVM/Clang 19 compiler...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newer AMD Radeon Graphics Cards Now Work On RISC-V With Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Non-MM-Patches</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Non-MM-Patches"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T10:28:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andrew Morton sent out more patches on Wednesday that have been pulled into the Linux 6.10 kernel. Notable from this latest round of "non-MM" updates is enabling more compiler warnings by default and getting newer AMD GPUs working on the RISC-V architecture...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME Shell & Mutter Broke Their Good Faith With Ubuntu]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-MRE-Over-Mutter-Shell</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-MRE-Over-Mutter-Shell"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T10:09:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME Shell and Mutter had been covered by Ubuntu's GNOME MicroReleaseException "MRE" policy that allows for new point releases to ship rather easily as stable updates to existing Ubuntu Linux releases. But breaking the camel's back is GNOME 46.1 shipping explicit sync support. Due to landing a "significant new feature" into a point release, the GNOME Shell and Mutter are no longer covered by this exception...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VirtIO Improvements Ready For Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-VirtIO</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-VirtIO"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T09:57:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All of the VirtIO updates are now ready for the Linux 6.10 merge window that is closing this weekend...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[systemd 256 Nears Release With run0, systemd-vpick, importctl & More]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/systemd-256-rc3-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/systemd-256-rc3-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T00:37:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It looks like systemd 256 will officially debut as stable in the near future with systemd 256-rc3 being released today and not tacking on any new features compared to the prior release candidates...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Initial Windows NT Sync Driver Merged Into Linux 6.10 But Not Yet Complete]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-char-misc</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-char-misc"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T00:07:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman today sent in the char/misc updates for Linux 6.10 alongside the other areas of the kernel he oversees. Among the char/misc changes is adding the NTSYNC driver that exposes the /dev/ntsync character device for use by the likes of Wine and Valve's Steam Play (Proton). But for Linux 6.10 the driver is effectively "broken" as most of the feature patches have yet to be included...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-22]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-22.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-22.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 22, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Show HN: I built a game to help you learn neural network architectures
(comments)


Show HN: Pls Fix – Hire big tech employees to appeal account suspensions
(comments)


Amber: Programming language compiled to Bash
(comments)


The curious case of the missing period
(comments)


Storing knowledge in a single long plain text file
(comments)


'Right to roam' movement fights to give the commons back to the public
(comments)


Pluckable Strings
(comments)


One-third of Amazon warehouse workers are on food stamps or Medicaid
(comments)


Try Clojure
(comments)


Leaked OpenAI documents reveal aggressive tactics toward former employees
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 24.1 Released With Explicit Sync Vulkan Drivers, More Mature NVK Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Mesa-24.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T19:27:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Engestrom has announced the release of Mesa 24.1 as this quarter's feature release to these open-source OpenGL and Vulkan drivers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RISC-V Now Supports Rust In The Linux Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-RISC-V</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-RISC-V"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T19:19:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest RISC-V port updates have been merged for the in-development Linux 6.10 kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Deck Platform Driver In No Apparent Rush For Upstreaming Into The Linux Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Steam-Deck-Platform-Driver-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Steam-Deck-Platform-Driver-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T17:46:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in February 2022 prior to the Valve Steam Deck being released, a Steam Deck Platform Driver was posted for the Linux kernel. Sadly, more than two years later, this driver still hasn't been upstreamed into the mainline Linux kernel and it looks like it could still be months before it happens...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10's Hardening Configuration Now Enables KCFI & Other Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Hardening</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Hardening"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T16:53:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduced last year with the Linux 6.7 kernel was a hardening configuration to allow for "make hardening.config" as an easy way of building a security-hardened Linux kernel with sane defaults. With Linux 6.10 there are some additional security minded features now enabled...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Shows People Are Still Using USB To Parallel Port Adapters In 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-USB</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-USB"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T16:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Kroah-Hartman sent out the USB/Thunderbolt changes this morning for the Linux 6.10 merge window that is wrapping up this weekend. Surprisingly, in 2024, a new USB to parallel printer port adapter variant is being introduced with Linux 6.10...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FUSE Adds VirtIO-FS Multi-Queue For ~5x Performance Win With Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-FUSE</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-FUSE"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T15:11:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The FUSE updates have been submitted for the Linux 6.10 kernel in supporting file-system implementations within user-space...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alpine Linux 3.20 Released With Initial 64-bit RISC-V Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Alpine-Linux-3.20</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Alpine-Linux-3.20"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T13:02:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alpine Linux 3.20 has been released as the newest feature release to this security-minded, lightweight Linux distribution that is popular for embedded and container use. Alpine Linux continues to set itself apart from others by making use of musl libc, Busybox, and other modifications in the name of security and small footprint...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Perf Tools Brings AMD Zen 5 Events & Intel Updates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Perf-Tools</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Perf-Tools"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T10:46:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sent out on Tuesday were all of the perf tool changes for the Linux 6.10 kernel. This includes perf event support for recent Intel CPUs as well as initial AMD Zen 5 processor support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 KVM Does More Prepping For Intel TDX]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-KVM</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-KVM"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T10:32:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The KVM changes for the Linux 6.10 kernel were merged a few days ago for this important piece to the open-source Linux virtualization stack...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse OpenJ9 v0.45 Released For Supporting OpenJDK 22]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Eclipse-OpenJ9-0.45</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Eclipse-OpenJ9-0.45"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T10:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse OpenJ9 v0.45 is now available as the newest version of this high performance JVM for Java applications...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Adds Support For The RISC-V Milk-V Mars & More SoC Additions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-More-SoCs</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-More-SoCs"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T10:19:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week the main SoC/platform updates were sent in for Linux 6.10 that included more ARM-based handheld game consoles and other new Arm devices from ASUS wireless routers to set-top boxes to enabling various SoCs. This week a secondary set of updates were submitted for the Linux 6.10 kernel merge window...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Box64 0.2.8 Released With Support For 16K Page Size - Allowing Games On Apple Silicon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Box64-0.2.8-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Box64-0.2.8-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T09:56:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Box64 is out as the newest version of this Linux user-space x86_64 emulator for running on ARM64 Linux devices. There is also an updated version of Box86 too for that x86 32-bit version on ARM...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-21]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-21.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-21.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 21, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


City in a Bottle – A 256 Byte Raycasting System
(comments)


pg_timeseries: Open-source time-series extension for PostgreSQL
(comments)


Enlightenmentware
(comments)


Chameleon: Meta’s New Multi-Modal LLM
(comments)


Shipbreaking
(comments)


NoTunes is a macOS application that will prevent Apple Music from launching
(comments)


Going Dark: The war on encryption is on the rise
(comments)


What UI density means and how to design for it
(comments)


CADmium: A local-first CAD program built for the browser
(comments)


Gordon Bell has died
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ASRock Rack Releases BIOS Update For EPYC 4004 Support With AM5 Ryzen Boards]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/ASRock-Rack-EPYC-4004-BIOS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/ASRock-Rack-EPYC-4004-BIOS"/>
        <updated>2024-05-21T17:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a follow-up to this morning's AMD EPYC 4004 review and benchmarks, Supermicro, ASRock Rack, Giga Computing, Tyan, and others have announced new motherboards/servers for these entry-level EPYC servers. In addition with the likes of ASRock Rack they have already published BIOS updates enabling existing AM5 Ryzen server boards to officially support the EPYC 4004 series processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA 555.42.02 Linux Beta Brings Wayland Explicit Sync, GSP Firmware Used By Default]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/NVIDIA-555.42.02-Linux-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/NVIDIA-555.42.02-Linux-Beta"/>
        <updated>2024-05-21T14:25:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's coming a week later than anticipated but the NVIDIA R555 Linux driver beta has been released! This is the NVIDIA proprietary Linux driver update that brings Wayland explicit sync support along with a host of other important improvements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD EPYC 4004 Benchmarks: Outperforming Intel Xeon E-2400 With Performance, Efficiency & Value]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/review/amd-epyc-4004</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/amd-epyc-4004"/>
        <updated>2024-05-21T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the past several years we have seen AMD Ryzen processors being used for low-cost servers, budget web hosting platforms, game servers, and more. Since the Ryzen 5000 series we have seen the likes of ASRock Rack and Supermicro putting out interesting budget-friendly Ryzen servers and that has ramped up even more with AMD Ryzen 7000 series server performance being stellar thanks to AVX-512 and other improvements making it more practical for such workloads. AMD has now solidified its positioning for entry-level servers with the introduction of the EPYC 4004 series processors. The EPYC 4004 series is derived from the Ryzen 7000 series offerings to facilitate cost conscious server options and putting the Intel Xeon E-2400 series in the crosshairs. In this review is a look at the EPYC 4004 series along with benchmarks of nearly the entire EPYC 4004 product stack compared to Intel's current top-end Xeon E-2400 series processor, the Intel Xeon E-2488 Raptor Lake.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LibreOffice 24.8 Alpha 1 Open-Source Office Suite Released]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/LibreOffice-24.8-Alpha-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/LibreOffice-24.8-Alpha-1"/>
        <updated>2024-05-21T12:26:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of the planned release in August, the first alpha release of the LibreOffice 24.8 open-source office suite is now available for testing...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Adds eDP/DisplayPort Support For The Snapdragon X Elite]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-eDP-DP-X-Elite</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-eDP-DP-X-Elite"/>
        <updated>2024-05-21T11:12:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Qualcomm and their partners at Linaro have been busy working on the Linux support for the Snapdragon X Elite as the high-end Arm SoC beginning to roll-out for laptops. The latest Snapdragon X Elite upstreaming is Embedded DisplayPort and DisplayPort support for the Snapdragon X Elite...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[F2FS With Linux 6.10 Delivers Better Performance On Zoned Storage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-F2FS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-F2FS"/>
        <updated>2024-05-21T10:58:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There's a lot of file-system activity going on for the Linux 6.10 merge window: Bcachefs safety improvements, better OCFS2 write performance, continued XFS online repair, and even a "mail-in merge request" from prison for ReiserFS. The Flash-Friendly File-System (F2FS) has also seen some new feature work this cycle and has now been merged...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hangover 9.9 Adds Support For Using The NTSYNC Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Hangover-9.9-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Hangover-9.9-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-21T10:51:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[André Zwing continues hacking on the Hangover project as a means of running Windows applications on AArch64 Linux by leveraging Wine and pairing it with emulators like QEMU, FEX, or Box64. Besides the initial AArch64/ARM64 focus, Hangover can be important for bring Windows game/application on Linux support eventually to other architectures like POWER and RISC-V...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 13.3 Compiler Released With Tons Of Bug Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-13.3-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-13.3-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-21T10:23:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While GCC 14 recently debuted as stable in the form of GCC 14.1, for those relying on the GCC 13 compiler that debuted last year there is now a new point release available with many bug fixes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Adds Support To Reset CXL Devices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Reset-CXL-Devices</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Reset-CXL-Devices"/>
        <updated>2024-05-21T10:12:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to the CXL updates for Linux 6.10 that were sent in last week, the PCI subsystem updates this week bring a notable addition for Compute Express Link (CXL) devices...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qt 6.7.1 Released With 400+ Fixes - Including Several Wayland Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Qt-6.7.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Qt-6.7.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-21T10:03:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Qt Company today released Qt 6.7.1 as the first point release for the cross-platform Qt 6.7.1 toolkit. Since releasing Qt 6.7 just under two months ago, they have fixed more than 400 bugs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[XFS Expanding Its Online Repair Capabilities In Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-XFS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-XFS"/>
        <updated>2024-05-21T00:40:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The XFS file-system improvements have been merged for the in-development Linux 6.10 kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-20]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-20.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-20.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 20, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Swarming Proxima Centauri: Picospacecraft Swarms over Interstellar Distances
(comments)


Make timelapses easily using FFmpeg
(comments)


Ask HN: Video streaming is expensive yet YouTube \"seems\" to do it for free. How?
(comments)


Meteor seen in Portugal
(comments)


The Lunacy of Artemis
(comments)


Migrating Uber's ledger data from DynamoDB to LedgerStore
(comments)


3M executives convinced a scientist forever chemicals in human blood were safe
(comments)


ICC prosecutor seeks arrest warrants against Sinwar and Netanyahu for war crimes
(comments)


Introducing Copilot+ PCs
(comments)


Statement from Scarlett Johansson on the OpenAI \"Sky\" voice
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Honors One Last ReiserFS Request Made By Hans Reiser]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/ReiserFS-README-Linux-6.10</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/ReiserFS-README-Linux-6.10"/>
        <updated>2024-05-20T20:55:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While ReiserFS is obsolete and will eventually be dropped from the upstream Linux kernel in Linux 6.10 is one last ReiserFS change that was requested by former lead developer Hans Reiser...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RFC Patches Posted For Rust-Written NVIDIA "Nova" GPU Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/RFC-Rust-Nova-NVIDIA-Driver</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/RFC-Rust-Nova-NVIDIA-Driver"/>
        <updated>2024-05-20T19:37:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat engineers have been developing Nova as a new, Rust-written open-source NVIDIA kernel graphics driver as the eventual successor to the Nouveau kernel driver and is designed around NVIDIA's GPU System Processor (GSP) thus making the driver relevant for RTX 20 / Turing GPUs and newer. Today they posted a request for comments (RFC) patch series of the Nova driver and Rust DRM abstractions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Announces Q3'2024 Arrival For Lunar Lake]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Lunar-Lake-Q3-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-Lunar-Lake-Q3-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-05-20T18:18:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel previously indicated that Lunar Lake processors would launch by the end of 2024 and leading to anticipation of a Q4 launch... Intel today announced that Lunar Lake will actually launch in Q3...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Many x86 Laptop Improvements In Linux 6.10 Plus Acer ARM Laptop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-x86-Platform-Drivers</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-x86-Platform-Drivers"/>
        <updated>2024-05-20T17:58:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The x86 platform driver updates have been merged for the ongoing Linux 6.10 merge window. The platform-drivers-x86 changes continue to primarily revolve around x86 Intel/AMD laptops but also some other desktop/platform drivers. Now in Linux 6.10 there is also a new "ARM64" sub-section of the platform drivers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora Miracle Spin Approved To Ship As Part Of Fedora Linux 41]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-Miracle-Spin-Approved</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fedora-Miracle-Spin-Approved"/>
        <updated>2024-05-20T14:33:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Fedora Engineering and Steering Committee (FESCo) has approved of the newest Fedora desktop ISO spin: Fedora Miracle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Farewell Intel Xeon Phi: Support Removed In The GCC 15 Compiler]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-15-Drops-Intel-Xeon-Phi</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-15-Drops-Intel-Xeon-Phi"/>
        <updated>2024-05-20T13:40:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week I wrote about Intel aiming to remove Xeon Phi support in GCC 15 with the products being end-of-life and deprecated in GCC 14. While some openly wondered whether the open-source community would allow it given the Xeon Phi accelerators were available to buy just a few years ago and at some very low prices going back years so some potentially finding use still out of them especially during this AI boom (and still readily available to buy used for around ~$50 USD), today the Intel Xeon Phi support was indeed removed...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMDGPU ISP Firmware Upstreamed In linux-firmware.git]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-ISP-Firmware</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/AMDGPU-ISP-Firmware"/>
        <updated>2024-05-20T12:36:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was just earlier this month that AMD Linux kernel graphics driver patches appeared for introducing a new ISP hardware block for Image Signal Processing with new AMD APUs. Already the AMDGPU ISP firmware has appeared in linux-firmware.git indicating that this "ISP" block may be coming in hardware quite soon if not already quietly found within some products...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OCFS2 File-System Seeing Improved Write Performance On Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Faster-OCFS2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Faster-OCFS2"/>
        <updated>2024-05-20T10:42:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's not often having anything to write about on the Oracle Cluster File-System v2 (OCFS2), but with Linux 6.10 it's seeing a rather significant performance optimization...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Will Print The Number Of Populated Memory Slots At Boot Time]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Prints-Memory-Slots</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Prints-Memory-Slots"/>
        <updated>2024-05-20T10:24:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a small information heads up, the Linux 6.10 kernel will print the number of populated memory slots at boot time to the kernel log as a little helper...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel CR 24.17.29377.6 Offers Latest OpenCL & oneAPI Level Zero Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-CR-24.17.29377.6</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Intel-CR-24.17.29377.6"/>
        <updated>2024-05-20T10:04:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Compute Runtime 24.17.29377.6 is now available as the latest routine update to this open-source GPU compute stack used by the company's integrated and discrete graphics products for providing OpenCL and oneAPI Level Zero compute capabilities...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fwupd 1.9.20 Released With Updated FPC Fingerprint Reader Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fwpupd-1.9.20-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Fwpupd-1.9.20-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-20T09:51:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Fwupd developers are working toward the Fwupd 2.0 release, out this morning is Fwupd 1.9.20 as the newest point release for this open-source solution for firmware updating on Linux that pairs with the Linux Vendor Firmware Service (LVFS)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-19]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-19.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-19.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 19, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


A trustworthy, free (libre), Linux capable, self-hosting 64bit RISC-V computer
(comments)


I organized a 20-acre game of Capture the Flag
(comments)


Floor796
(comments)


Calculus with Julia
(comments)


Riven
(comments)


Big Tech to EU: \"Drop Dead\"
(comments)


Classic Usenet posts on computer architecture, operating systems and languages
(comments)


Transforming a QLC SSD into an SLC SSD
(comments)


Coding My Handwriting
(comments)


Llama3 implemented from scratch
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bcachefs Brings Safety Improvements To Linux 6.10, Preps For Online Fsck]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Bcachefs</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Bcachefs"/>
        <updated>2024-05-19T18:15:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bcachefs lead developer Kent Overstreet today sent out his feature pull request of all the new file-system code that is ready in time for the Linux 6.10 merge window...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloudflare Praises Golang PGO For Significant CPU Savings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Cloudflare-Golang-PGO</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Cloudflare-Golang-PGO"/>
        <updated>2024-05-19T10:47:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Released over a year ago was Golang 1.20 with support for Profile Guided Optimizations (PGO) and has since been improved with Go 1.21 for 2~7% faster Go binaries thanks to this optimization approach also found with other compilers. The engineers at Cloudflare have put out a blog post this week praising Go's PGO support and the CPU savings they are seeing as a result...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EXT4 In Linux 6.10 Adds FS_IOC_GETFSSYSFSPATH Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-EXT4</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-EXT4"/>
        <updated>2024-05-19T10:36:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While EROFS is seeing Zstd support and Bcachefs is seeing performance optimizations with the in-development Linux 6.10 kernel, over on the mature EXT4 file-system side the changes are mostly small. There are some minor changes, more folio conversion work, and also adding support for the FS_IOC_GETFSSYSFSPATH ioctl that has been seeing some standardization and adoption by the common Linux file-systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Patch Posted For The Bigscreen Beyond VR Headset]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Bigscreen-Beyond-VR</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-Bigscreen-Beyond-VR"/>
        <updated>2024-05-19T10:14:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Linux patch has been posted for delivering a quirk so that the Bigscreen Beyond VR Headset can properly behave under Linux and in turn also jives with the likes of SteamVR...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Scheduler Changes Bring More Refinements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Scheduler</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Scheduler"/>
        <updated>2024-05-19T10:04:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alongside all of the other pull requests by Ingo Molnar submitted at the start of the week during the opening of the Linux 6.10 merge window were the scheduler updates. As usual, the kernel scheduler work continues to see various tweaks and refinements to enhance its behavior...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turbostat Gains New Features & New Hardware Support With Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Turbostat</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Turbostat"/>
        <updated>2024-05-19T09:48:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux's Turbostat utility that is developed by Intel for reporting idle/power state statistics, temperatures, and other useful data on modern Intel/AMD processors has seen its changes submitted for the in-development Linux 6.10 kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-18]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-18.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-18.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 18, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


Wuffs: Wrangling Untrusted File Formats Safely
(comments)


The Downfall of DeviantArt
(comments)


ADSL works over wet string (2017)
(comments)


Show HN: I built a website to create financial models for any stock online
(comments)


Thinking out loud about 2nd-gen email
(comments)


OpenAI departures: Why can’t former employees talk?
(comments)


Ex-OpenAI staff must sign lifetime no-criticism contract or forfeit all equity
(comments)


Gio UI – Cross-platform GUI for Go
(comments)


Cyber Security: A pre-war reality check
(comments)


If you’re seeing this, I’m in jail [video]
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SUSE's YaST Team Drops Cockpit With New Installer Code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/SUSE-Agama-Ditches-Cockpit</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/SUSE-Agama-Ditches-Cockpit"/>
        <updated>2024-05-18T19:50:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SUSE/openSUSE has been busy crafting a next-gen Linux installer that is a web-based installer and originally known as D-Installer but now going by the name Agama...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 NFSD Brings Optimizations & Preps For New nfsdctl Utility]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-NFSD</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-NFSD"/>
        <updated>2024-05-18T13:53:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux Network File System (NFS) server code (NFSD) is seeing a new Netlink protocol introduced in Linux 6.10 as part of laying the groundwork for the new "nfsdctl" utility...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Niri 0.1.6 Wayland Compositor Adds Interactive Window Resizing & Mouse View Scrolling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Niri-0.1.6-Wayland-Compositor</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Niri-0.1.6-Wayland-Compositor"/>
        <updated>2024-05-18T13:08:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Niri is a scrollable-tiling Wayland compositor inspired by PaperWM and heavy on the animations/effects. Out this morning is Niri 0.1.6 as the newest feature release for this Wayland compositor...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME OS Working On A New Installer & Other Enhancements To Make It More Practical]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-OS-New-Installer</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-OS-New-Installer"/>
        <updated>2024-05-18T10:56:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Germany's Sovereign Tech Fund continues providing the resources for various new GNOME desktop development initiatives. There are various efforts underway for new features and refinements with GNOME 47 in September and a renewed emphasis around GNOME OS...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 x86 Instruction Decoder Prepares For APX & Other New Intel Instructions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-x86-APX-Decode</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-x86-APX-Decode"/>
        <updated>2024-05-18T10:46:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The performance events updates were submitted today for the ongoing Linux 6.10 kernel merge window. This pull adds support for Advanced Performance Extensions (APX) and other new Intel CPU instructions to the x86 instruction decoder...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Preps For "When Things Go Seriously Wrong" On Bigger Servers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Larger-CPUs-MCE</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Larger-CPUs-MCE"/>
        <updated>2024-05-18T10:34:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While machine check exception (MCE) events tend to be uncommon, a change made by Intel engineers is accommodating the ability in the Linux kernel to store more machine check records for "when things go seriously wrong" on increasingly high core count servers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Apps Improving Experience When Running Outside Of Plasma]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Go-Non-Plasma-Experience</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/KDE-Go-Non-Plasma-Experience"/>
        <updated>2024-05-18T10:23:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[KDE development remains very busy ahead of next month's Plasma 6.1 desktop release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 9.9 Brings ARM Improvements, Drops Obsolete WineD3D Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-9.9-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Wine-9.9-Released"/>
        <updated>2024-05-18T00:37:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 9.9 is out as the newest bi-weekly development release for running Windows games/applications on Linux and other platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Hacker News for 2024-05-17]]></title>
        <id>https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-17.html</id>
        <link href="https://www.daemonology.net/hn-daily/2024-05-17.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 highest-rated articles on
Hacker News
on May 17, 2024 which have not appeared on any previous
Hacker News Daily
are:


D3 in Depth
(comments)


Computer scientists invent an efficient new way to count
(comments)


Egypt's pyramids may have been built on a long-lost branch of the Nile
(comments)


Slack AI Training with Customer Data
(comments)


A forged Apple employee badge
(comments)


Visualizing algorithms for rate limiting
(comments)


Exercises to Learn Rust
(comments)


Non-Euclidean Doom: what happens to a game when pi is not 3.14159 (2022) [video]
(comments)


Toon3D: Seeing cartoons from a new perspective
(comments)


Bend: a high-level language that runs on GPUs (via HVM2)
(comments)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Daily</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Adds Support For Posted Interrupts On Bare Metal Hardware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Posted-Interrupts</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-Posted-Interrupts"/>
        <updated>2024-05-17T16:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged as part of the IRQ changes for the in-development Linux 6.10 kernel is support for posted interrupts on bare metal hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 24.10 To See More Polishing, NVIDIA Wayland By Default & New Welcome Wizard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.10-Roadmap</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-24.10-Roadmap"/>
        <updated>2024-05-17T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oliver Smith who is serving as the Interim Engineering Director for the Ubuntu Desktop team at Canonical has shared some roadmap plans around Ubuntu 24.10. With this being the first post-LTS release following last month's Ubuntu 24.04 Long Term Support, they are more free to innovate this cycle and they have a lot of great plans for enhancing the Linux desktop experience...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's OpenVINO Now Available In openSUSE]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/openSUSE-Shipping-OpenVINO</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/openSUSE-Shipping-OpenVINO"/>
        <updated>2024-05-17T13:48:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSUSE is the first major Linux distribution to package up and offer Intel's OpenVINO open-source AI toolkit within its package repository...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Improves Performance For Opening Unencrypted Files]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-FSCRYPT</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-FSCRYPT"/>
        <updated>2024-05-17T12:37:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FSCRYPT is the file-system encryption framework within the Linux kernel for supporting optional encryption  on file-systems like EXT4, F2FS, and others. With Linux 6.10 an optimization is coming for enhancing the performance of opening files on file-systems supporting FSCRYPT-based encryption but when the files are unencrypted...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 6.10 Wires Up More Compute Express Link "CXL" Functionality]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-CXL</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-CXL"/>
        <updated>2024-05-17T10:49:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Compute Express Link (CXL) subsystem development continues to be led by Intel engineers and with the in-development Linux 6.10 kernel there are yet more features in tow...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Readies Xeon Phi Removal For GCC 15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-15-Patch-Drops-Xeon-Phi</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GCC-15-Patch-Drops-Xeon-Phi"/>
        <updated>2024-05-17T10:32:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the GCC 14 compiler release is the deprecation of the Xeon Phi targets. With Intel Knights Landing and Knights Mill being end-of-life at Intel, they are working to do away with the GNU Compiler Collection support. A patch has been posted to drop the Xeon Phi ISAs with GCC 15...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EROFS Adds Zstd & Btrfs Gets Minor Performance Work In Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-EROFS-Btrfs</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Linux-6.10-EROFS-Btrfs"/>
        <updated>2024-05-17T10:21:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The EROFS and Btrfs file-systems saw their feature patches merged as part of the ongoing Linux 6.10 merge window...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sysctl Sentinel Bloat Removal Wrapping Up In Linux 6.10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Sysctl-Finish-Line-Linux-6.10</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Sysctl-Finish-Line-Linux-6.10"/>
        <updated>2024-05-17T10:12:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The year-long effort to removal the sysctl sentinel for clearing bloat from the kernel and allowing faster build times should be crossing the finish line in Linux 6.10...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME 47 Aims For Release On 18 September]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-47-Release-Schedule</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-47-Release-Schedule"/>
        <updated>2024-05-17T00:43:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GNOME project has now solidified their release schedule for the current GNOME 47 development cycle: GNOME 47.0 should be out on 18 September...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Larabel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>